<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Air-Quality on HeaterTips</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/category/air-quality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Air-Quality on HeaterTips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.146.7</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 13:39:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/category/air-quality/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dyson F4 Error Code: How To Fix It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fix-dyson-f4-error-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 13:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fix-dyson-f4-error-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Encountering the F4 error on your Dyson appliance can be a cause for concern, but it’s often a problem you can solve yourself. This guide will provide you with a clear understanding of what the F4 error means for different Dyson models and the steps you can take to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;If your Dyson shows an F4 error, first try power cycling and checking for any obvious blockages or misalignments.&lt;/strong&gt; If the problem continues, it could indicate a motor or sensor issue, in which case you should contact Dyson support, especially if your device is still under the 2-year warranty. If not, consider replacing it with a newer model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Drip Tray Overflow Error: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fix-dyson-drip-tray-overflow-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 14:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fix-dyson-drip-tray-overflow-error/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptom:&lt;/strong&gt; Dyson Humidify+Cool shows a “Drip Tray Overflow” error after activating humidification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/are-dyson-humidify-cool-fans-worth-it/&#34;&gt;Dyson Pure Humidify+Cool&lt;/a&gt; is a combined humidifier, air purifier, and fan. When it works, it’s great. But the Humidify+Cool units encounter errors much more frequently than other Dyson fans, since they work with water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “Drip Tray Overflow” error is a common issue in Dyson Humidify+Cool fans that affects the device’s humidifying functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re having a look at what the error means, where it comes from, and how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Humidify&#43;Cool Not Humidifying: How To Fix It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fix-dyson-humidify-cool-not-humidifying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 08:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fix-dyson-humidify-cool-not-humidifying/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;re focusing on a problem that many owners of the Dyson Pure Humidify+Cool have encountered: the unit not humidifying properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a frustrating issue, especially considering the investment you make in a Dyson product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide is designed to help you diagnose and fix the problem quickly and efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most common causes for the humidification not working is a clogged pump column, but there can be other reasons for its reduced functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Humidify&#43;Cool Fans: Are They Worth It?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/are-dyson-humidify-cool-fans-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/are-dyson-humidify-cool-fans-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dyson Humidify+Cool models cost a hefty price. The recent PH04 is around $900. Older models such as the PH03 still sell for $700 - $800.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what’s so special about a Dyson humidifier? Can it do more than just add humidity to your room? And is getting one worth it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to have a critical look at Dyson Humidify+Cool models, checking out how well they really perform and if they do justify their price tag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Deep Clean Cycle Not Working: How To Fix It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fix-dyson-deep-clean-cycle-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 11:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fix-dyson-deep-clean-cycle-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The deep clean cycle on Dyson humidifiers is known to have several problems. For some, it won’t start, other times, it keeps stopping, and sometimes the timer is stuck and not counting down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any of these problems make a full deep clean cycle impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check out several different solutions for your Dyson humidifier’s deep clean cycle not working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-deep-clean-cycle-and-why-do-you-need-it&#34;&gt;What is the Deep Clean Cycle and why do you need it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep cleaning is the process of removing limescale by dissolving it with citric acid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Wrong Air Quality / Temperature: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fix-dyson-wrong-air-quality-temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 11:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fix-dyson-wrong-air-quality-temperature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your Dyson fan suddenly shows wrong air quality reports and / or a wrong temperature?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes, the air quality report shows a 999 value and the temperature shows 0°C (or °K).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or the air quality report and temperature are stuck at a certain value, or they don’t show values at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This usually indicates a problem with the air quality and temperature sensor. Usually, the problem is easy to fix and requires just a few minutes of your time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Fan Warning Triangle (5 Fixes)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dyson-fan-warning-triangle-error-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dyson-fan-warning-triangle-error-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When your Dyson fan shows a warning triangle with an exclamation mark, something is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the warning triangle, your Dyson fan does not give you any further information about the issue, and no instructions on what to do now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll have a quick look at the warning triangle error, what causes it, and what you should do about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Daniel, I’m an electrical engineer. I’ve worked in a large repair department of an electronics company before. Let’s have a look at what’s going on together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Reset the “F” Code On a Dyson Air Purifier</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-reset-the-f-code-on-a-dyson-air-purifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 08:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-reset-the-f-code-on-a-dyson-air-purifier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every few months, your Dyson air purifier will show an F code with three blinking lights next to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “F” code stands for “Filter” and signals you to replace your air purifier’s filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dyson recommends to do this every 6-12 months. Based on the time passed since you last replaced the filter (or since you bought the air purifier), and the filter’s airflow resistance, Dyson can determine when a filter replacement is due.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson F3 Error Code: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dyson-f3-error-code-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 07:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dyson-f3-error-code-fix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Owning a Dyson Pure+Cool or a Humidify+Cool fan has its fair share of perks, from enjoying a cool breeze to breathing cleaner air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when the F3 error code comes up, your Dyson Fan suddenly stops despite all seeming well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been scratching your head over this, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone: Nobody really knows what causes the F3 error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I’ll tell you how to fix the F3 error code, or at least,  how to reset it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Purifier Keeps Shutting Off (7 Reasons &amp; Fixes)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fix-air-purifier-keeps-shutting-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 08:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fix-air-purifier-keeps-shutting-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Air purifiers are great for keeping the air in your living space fresh and clean. All the more annoying it is when your air purifier keeps shutting off on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll have a look at 7 common reasons and how to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the troubleshooting is not difficult and for most fixes, you don’t need any electronics knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this is a layman’s guide to fixing an air purifier that keeps shutting off!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blueair Blue 211&#43; Review: Is It Worth It?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blueair-blue-211-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 08:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blueair-blue-211-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Blueair Blue 211+ is the largest air purifier in Blueair’s Blue series. But does its size benefit you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or are smaller models such as the 311 or 411 just as good?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, how does the Blueair Blue keep up with its competition?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blueair fiercely competes with Levoit and Coway, two of the most popular air purifier brands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, my goal is to answer all these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer, and on this blog, my top priority is finding out which heating, cooling, and air quality devices &lt;em&gt;really work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Best Air Purifiers for Small Rooms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-air-purifiers-for-small-rooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 09:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-air-purifiers-for-small-rooms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What are the best air purifiers for small rooms? In this post, we’re going to check out air purifiers, for small rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And one interesting question we’re going to answer is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you even need a small air purifier for a small room?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is absolutely counterintuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, as an electrical engineer, it is my mission to spread the truth about small-room air purifiers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let’s start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;small-room--small-air-purifier&#34;&gt;Small Room = Small Air Purifier?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a misconception about air purifiers that seems hard to grasp for most people. But it’s actually quite simple:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Air Purifiers Need Water?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/do-air-purifiers-need-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 11:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/do-air-purifiers-need-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do air purifiers need water? And do you have to replace water regularly? Do you need to put in any maintenance work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quick post is going to answer all of that. Luckily, it’s very simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;No, most air purifiers never need water. Air purifiers pass air through a dry HEPA filter, which needs replacement every 6-12 months. Air purifiers with built-in humidifiers, however, need water replacements occasionally. But in this case, the water is not needed for air purification.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuwave OxyPure Review: Exceptional Filtration, Poor Monitoring</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nuwave-oxypure-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 06:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nuwave-oxypure-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Nuwave OxyPure is one of the best-selling large air purifiers online. It’s time I put my hands on it and review it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I look for an in-depth Nuwave OxyPure review, I am surprised there is so little actual insight available. I mean there is plenty of information. But everybody just tries to sell you this air purifier, without consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let me tell you: The Nuwave OxyPure is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the best choice for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Big&#43;Quiet Review: High Price, High Performance?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dyson-big-quiet-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 08:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dyson-big-quiet-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dyson recently launched the Big+Quiet air purifier. I found out yesterday, after writing about &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/are-dyson-air-purifiers-worth-the-money/&#34;&gt;whether Dyson air purifiers are worth the money&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally, as an HVAC blogger and electrical engineer, I get to know all new products on the market quickly. But the Big+Quiet entered the stage, as its name suggests, quietly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess the biggest reason is the price. &lt;strong&gt;At $1,000, the Dyson Big+Quiet is a luxury product.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you google the &amp;ldquo;Dyson Big+Quiet&amp;rdquo;, all you get is a wall of sales copy-type blog posts with no investigation beyond surface-level data and no questioning of marketing statements at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Dyson Air Purifiers Worth the Money?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/are-dyson-air-purifiers-worth-the-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 09:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/are-dyson-air-purifiers-worth-the-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Dyson air purifiers worth the money? Recently, Dyson launched its new product line, the Dyson Purifier Big+Quiet, which costs just around $1,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a huge price for an air purifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what’s so special about this thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that Dyson has been selling air purifiers for ages, as features built into the Pure Cool and Hot+Cool models, are Dyson air purifiers worth the money?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer. One of my favorite free time activities is to uncover marketing myths and publish them on this website. One of my most popular articles is about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/are-dyson-heaters-energy-efficient-a-critical-review/&#34;&gt;alleged better energy efficiency of Dyson heaters&lt;/a&gt;, which turned out to be a huge marketing lie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coway Air Purifier Indicator Lights Meanings (Colors &amp; Blinking)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/coway-air-purifier-indicator-lights-meanings-colors-blinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 11:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/coway-air-purifier-indicator-lights-meanings-colors-blinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of your Coway air purifier’s indicator lights changed colors or started blinking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick, but complete guide on Coway indicator lights and their meanings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-air-quality-indicator-light&#34;&gt;1. Air Quality Indicator Light&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coway air purifiers have a built-in pollution sensor. Based on the sensor’s readings, the air purifier changes the air quality indicator light color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the model, the air quality indicator light changes as follows (according to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/D1SWYNC4nwS.pdf&#34;&gt;official Coway Airmega 300 / 400 user manual&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Air Purifiers Safe for Pets? (Dogs, Cats, Birds, etc.)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/are-air-purifiers-safe-for-pets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 08:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/are-air-purifiers-safe-for-pets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are air purifiers safe for pets? 4 months ago, my girlfriend got a puppy. Naturally, I have to take care of her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as an HVAC blogger, I have all kinds of devices at home, including an air purifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how did things turn out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did the dog survive the air purifier? (&amp;hellip; joking)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I am going to guide you through using air purifiers with pets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this, you’ll know exactly:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use an Extension Cord with an Air Purifier?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-you-use-an-extension-cord-with-an-air-purifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 09:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-you-use-an-extension-cord-with-an-air-purifier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use an extension cord for an air purifier? In this article, we’re going to explore the art of using extension cords with air purifiers and how to stay safe at all times!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extension cords can pose a risk when not used appropriately. While air purifiers generally consume much less power than similar devices (such as portable air conditioners), safety precautions are still essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most extension cords can handle the little power an air purifier draws. But a very bad quality extension cord that can&amp;rsquo;t handle the required power can pose a risk of melting or even catching fire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix a Coway Air Purifier not working (Repair Guide)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-a-coway-air-purifier-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 07:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-a-coway-air-purifier-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Experiencing problems with your Coway air purifier? Whether it&amp;rsquo;s an indicator light, fan issue, or connectivity problem, we&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s your comprehensive guide to troubleshooting the most common issues with Coway air purifiers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coway air purifiers are &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/are-coway-airmega-air-purifiers-worth-it/&#34;&gt;incredibly overpriced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, a Coway air purifier not working is annoying and can also cut a huge hole in your wallet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably don’t want to spend another $200 - $500 (or even up to $1,000 depending on the model) for a new Coway air purifier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Coway Airmega Air Purifiers worth it? (Critical Review)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/are-coway-airmega-air-purifiers-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/are-coway-airmega-air-purifiers-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Coway Airmega air purifiers worth it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know one thing about me, it’s most likely that I absolutely can’t stand overpriced garbage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And one of the worst things for me is seeing family and friends fall for marketing hoaxes … So, I hope I can at least save &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, dear reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Daniel, I am an electrical and aerospace engineer. And no HVAC company is safe from my bare honesty!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why your Air Purifier Smells (Musty, Wet Dog, Fish, etc.)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/why-your-air-purifier-smells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 10:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/why-your-air-purifier-smells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why does my air purifier smell musty, like plastic, sweet, or even like a wet dog?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That seems like a bad plot in a poor comic. I bought an air purifier to get the &lt;em&gt;exact&lt;/em&gt; opposite result!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just don’t buy an air purifier to make things smell &lt;em&gt;worse.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like you don’t eat food to get more hungry. And you don’t buy a car to drive you farther away from your destination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why your Air Purifier is not Removing Odors (&#43; Fixes)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/air-purifier-not-removing-odors-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 13:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/air-purifier-not-removing-odors-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your air purifier does not remove odors and you don’t know why? In this article, we’re going to check all the possible reasons and how to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having clean and fresh air is important for your well-being. And air purifiers are supposed to remove odors. Or are they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;( There will be a surprising answer to this question - not all air purifiers can remove odors )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you stick out until the end of this article, you’ll know exactly why your air purifier does not remove bad smells.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix an Air Purifier not Collecting Dust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-an-air-purifier-not-collecting-dust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 12:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-an-air-purifier-not-collecting-dust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your air purifier is not collecting dust, even though you already run it for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-air-purifier-all-day/&#34;&gt;long time&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check all the possible causes of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And before we take the deep dive: Not all air purifiers have to collect dust. Dust is, in the end, just the particles that are visible to the eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air purifiers filter much smaller particles than that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, after some time, you should see &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; on the filters. If that’s not the case, today is the day this is going to change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Purifier making Noise (8 Noises &#43; Fixes)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/air-purifier-making-noise-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 12:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/air-purifier-making-noise-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your air purifier is making some noise and you wonder whether that noise is normal or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, you’re in the right place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check the different noises air purifiers can produce and what you can do about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some noises, for example, quiet humming are normal. However, loud buzzing, screeching, or even banging noises can even indicate that something dangerous is going on inside your air purifier and it needs repair.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix an Air Purifier not turning on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-an-air-purifier-not-turning-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 12:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-an-air-purifier-not-turning-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s my complete guide on how to troubleshoot and fix an air purifier not turning on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air purifiers are very simple devices. There’s not much that can break if it does not turn on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, they are relatively simple to repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, my goal is to list &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; possible reason why your air purifier might not turn along with how to fix it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this article, you’ll know &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; how to fix your air purifier. And even if you can’t fix it, stick out until the end of this article. I still have a couple of ideas to get you a working air purifier quickly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run an Air Purifier and a Humidifier at the same time?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-air-purifier-and-humidifier-at-the-same-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 09:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-air-purifier-and-humidifier-at-the-same-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run an air purifier and a humidifier at the same time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a quick Google search. Here are the first results that pop up (in a nutshell).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google search results for the query “Can you run an air purifier and a humidifier at the same time?”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes (no explanation given &lt;em&gt;at all)&lt;/em&gt;( &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.filtrete.com/3M/en_US/filtrete/home-tips/full-story/~/running-an-air-purifier-and-humidifier-at-the-same-time/?storyid=59002fd2-fe9f-48a2-8c65-5be479d49355&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Of course, now buy our filters ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usairpurifiers.com/blog/can-you-use-air-purifiers-and-humidifiers-together/&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes… we are an industry leader in superior filter systems - contact us and buy from us! ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://ushomefilter.com/what-if-i-use-air-purifiers-and-humidifiers-together/&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t help but read these answers with a clown voice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run an Air Purifier with a Window open?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-air-purifier-with-window-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-air-purifier-with-window-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run an air purifier with a window open? In this article, we’re going to check whether it makes sense to vent your room while you run your air purifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, the answer is quite obvious: of course, you can run your air purifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as soon as you open your window, particles like pollen and bacteria enter your room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that a reason to stop your air purifier? Should you wait until the window is closed to run it again?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run an Air Purifier 24/7?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-air-purifier-all-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 11:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-air-purifier-all-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run an air purifier 24/7 (all day, every day)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is all about this question. But we don’t stop there. After reading this, you’ll not only know exactly &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; you can run your air purifier all day, but also whether it even &lt;em&gt;makes sense.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is not just to tell you what to do. A lot of search results are totally useless. For example, when I search for “Can you run an air purifier all day?”, the first result tells me “Yes”, but does not explain &lt;em&gt;why.&lt;/em&gt; (I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; a why!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Purifier Running Cost: The Ultimate Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/air-purifier-running-cost-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 11:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/air-purifier-running-cost-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How much does an Air Purifier cost to run? I love my air purifier and I&amp;rsquo;d really like to run it 24/7. But how much would that cost?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this guide, I am going to answer how much running an air purifier for different durations costs (8 hours, 24 hours, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading the article, you&amp;rsquo;ll know exactly, &lt;em&gt;how much&lt;/em&gt; your air purifier costs to run, &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it costs so much (or so little), and how you can &lt;em&gt;reduce the power consumption even further&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Air Purifier: My Top Pick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-air-purifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 20:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-air-purifier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like to stick to products that simply work. Personally, I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; marketing tricks and lies. And if you read my other articles on this website, I always prefer simplicity and sturdiness over shiny objects that can’t hold their promises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this time, let’s have a look at my favorite air purifier and why I decided to get this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The best air purifier is the Levoit Core 300. It is simple, collects a lot of dust and is easy to maintain. After using it for a month and seeing the thickness of dust it collects, it is evident why this air purifier is so popular.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
