<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bill on HeaterTips</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/bill/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bill on HeaterTips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.146.7</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 20:44:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tag/bill/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Electricity Usage of Oil-Filled Heaters: The Ultimate Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/electricity-usage-of-oil-filled-heaters-the-ultimate-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 20:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/electricity-usage-of-oil-filled-heaters-the-ultimate-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This guide is all about the electricity usage of oil heaters. You are probably about to get a new space heater and wondering whether getting an oil heater is the right choice for you. Oftentimes, you have several concerns when you’re about to get a brand new heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much electricity do oil heaters use?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it expensive to run an oil heater continuously?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are oil heaters more efficient than other types of space heaters?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can you reduce the electricity usage of your oil heater?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to tackle all these questions (and even more)! And don’t worry. You don’t need to be an electrician to be able to follow along. I’ve made this guide as easy and beginner-friendly as possible. All you have to do is to read through it and cherry-pick the information you need.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Cheapest Ways to Heat a Room &amp; House</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-21-cheapest-ways-to-heat-a-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 13:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-21-cheapest-ways-to-heat-a-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What are the cheapest ways to heat your room or even your entire house? In this article, we&amp;rsquo;re going to look at exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Daniel, an electrical engineer from Germany, and here&amp;rsquo;s a list of all the cheapest practical ways to heat your home!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the methods listed teach you cheap ways to heat single rooms. Also, you&amp;rsquo;ll find cheap ways to heat your entire house. Some of the heating-methods listed don&amp;rsquo;t even need central heating or electricity!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
