<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Space-Heater on HeaterTips</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/space-heater/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Space-Heater on HeaterTips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.146.7</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 10:18:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tag/space-heater/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Space Heater vs Electric Blanket: 21 Pros and Cons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/space-heater-vs-electric-blanket-21-pros-and-cons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 10:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/space-heater-vs-electric-blanket-21-pros-and-cons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Space heater vs electric blanket. Both are completely different products and yet they have something in common: They are meant to keep you warm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are not sure which one you should get, this article is for you. We’re going to compare space heaters and electric blankets and find out which one is the better choice for you. This is a very individual choice, so we’ll cover everything you need to know, to make the best decision. Heating with an electric blanket or with a space heater is very different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run a Space Heater off a Generator?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-a-space-heater-off-a-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 08:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-a-space-heater-off-a-generator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You want to run a space heater off a generator? Here’s everything you need to know about powering space heaters with generators and what you need to consider to stay safe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we’ll cover whether it makes sense to use generators to power space heaters and I’ll show you some handy alternatives (that might work even better for your purposes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first, let’s take a look at the generators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Question: Can you run a space heater off a generator?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can I use an Extension Cord with a Space Heater?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-i-use-an-extension-cord-with-a-space-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 08:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-i-use-an-extension-cord-with-a-space-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🆕 Updated April 17, 2025&lt;/strong&gt; - All recommended extension cords and power strips are up-to-date and safe for use with space heaters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to cover exactly whether you can use an extension cord with your space heater and what you have to be cautious of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Question: Can I use an extension cord with a space heater?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer: &lt;strong&gt;Usually, you should not use an extension cord with your space heater. Most extension cords can not handle the high currents space heaters draw. Especially small, low-quality extension cords can easily catch fire. However, if you absolutely need an extension cord, then you should get a heavy-duty cord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
