<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>🔥 Stay Warm, Cool, and Safe – Your Complete Home Heating &amp; Cooling Resource on HeaterTips</title>
    <link>https://heatertips.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 🔥 Stay Warm, Cool, and Safe – Your Complete Home Heating &amp; Cooling Resource on HeaterTips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 19:30:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://heatertips.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are Dyson Heaters Energy-Efficient? (Running Cost of Hot &#43; Cool)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-heaters-energy-efficient-a-critical-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 19:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-heaters-energy-efficient-a-critical-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the average Dyson Hot and Cool heater fan running cost? And how energy-efficient are Dyson heaters when compared to regular space heaters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dyson heaters are up to 30% more energy efficient than regular space heaters. At least that’s what Dyson claims. Today, I’m going to check whether Dyson heaters are as energy-efficient as they promise to be and whether getting one is worth your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m an electrical engineer and together with you, I want to cut through the jungle of myths and claims. In this article, you’ll learn everything about how efficient Dyson heaters really are and whether Dyson is overselling their product, or whether it’s worth buying (I surprised myself with my findings).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can I use an Extension Cord with a Space Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-i-use-an-extension-cord-with-a-space-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 10:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-i-use-an-extension-cord-with-a-space-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to cover exactly whether you can use an extension cord with your space heater and what you have to be cautious of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Question: Can I use an extension cord with a space heater?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer: &lt;strong&gt;You should avoid using an extension cord with your space heater. But if you have to, use a heavy-duty extension cord. Also, if possible, operate your space heater at a low to moderate heat setting in order.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Use a Diesel Heater Indoors: The Complete Guide</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-use-a-diesel-heater-indoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 13:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-use-a-diesel-heater-indoors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can use a diesel heater indoors, in your house, in a garage, shed, or workshop. All you need is a reliable, weatherproof diesel heater setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diesel heaters can make great emergency heaters. With just a car battery and some diesel, you can heat your home in case of an electricity outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, for tiny houses or cabins, diesel heaters can even be reliable long-term heaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this guide, we’re having a look at how to properly set up a diesel heater for indoor heating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Heaters Over 1,500 Watts (Electric, Gas)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heaters-over-1500-watts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 09:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heaters-over-1500-watts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Space heaters are usually limited to 1,500 Watts. Especially in the US. That’s because US home circuits are laid out to supply 120 Volts. Combined with a 15 Ampere fuse, that corresponds to a maximum power consumption of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;120 Volts × 15 Amps = 1,800 Watts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the average US household circuit can support 1,800 Watts. But since you want to run multiple devices simultaneously, and not just a single heater, space heaters cap at 1,500 Watts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet Daniel</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 14:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am Daniel, an electrical engineer. For heatertips.com I research cost-effective heating and air conditioning methods, debunk myths, and explain what really works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging about home heating and air conditioning on this website since 2019 now. There have been many emotional ups and downs. Sustaining a website in the age of AI is certainly a challenge. But since writing became a daily habit for me, I view heatertips as a passion project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How many Amps does a Diesel Heater use?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-many-amps-does-a-diesel-heater-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-many-amps-does-a-diesel-heater-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did an experiment, measuring the amperage of my diesel heater. This post is about the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you look for diesel heater amperages online, you don’t get any good answers. One website I found said that “diesel heater draws 1 amp per hour”. As an electrical engineer, hearing this hurts my brain. Severely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s as if I say that my car uses 100 horsepower per hour. It’s just a nonsensical use of the unit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Best Fanless Heaters</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-fanless-heaters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 09:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-fanless-heaters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fanless heaters have several advantages when compared to regular electric space heaters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No wear-down:&lt;/strong&gt; Since they have no built-in fan, they don’t wear down over time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No maintenance:&lt;/strong&gt; Since they contain no moving parts, they are maintenance-free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No cleaning:&lt;/strong&gt; Since there’s no constant stream of air passing through the heater, it does not accumulate dust, and, therefore, does not need cleaning or built-in air filters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silence:&lt;/strong&gt; Fanless heaters are 100% silent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on these findings, we can already tell that maintenance-wise and technology-wise, fanless heaters are superior to most other electric space heaters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diesel Heater E08 Error Code: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/fix-diesel-heater-e08-error-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 10:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/fix-diesel-heater-e08-error-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your (chinese) diesel heater shows an E08 error code? No problem. The E08 error code is usually simple to fix requires no tools and no disassembly, and takes under 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re having a look at the most common reasons and fixes for the E08 error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you follow this article closely, you will be able to resolve the error code within the next few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll keep it simple &amp;amp; easy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diesel vs Electric RV Heaters: Which to Pick?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/diesel-vs-electric-rv-heaters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 09:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/diesel-vs-electric-rv-heaters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re getting your RV ready for trips, picking the right heater is a big deal. It&amp;rsquo;s all about staying warm and cozy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of van travelers wonder whether to go with a diesel heater or an electric one. Diesel heaters are great for pumping out a lot of heat, but setting them up and keeping them running takes some work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electric heaters are easier to use and quieter, but they might not give you as much warmth and need a steady electric supply. Which one is better really depends on where and how you plan to use your van.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diesel Heater Fuel Gelling: 4 Fixes</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/fix-diesel-heater-fuel-gelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 10:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/fix-diesel-heater-fuel-gelling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it’s getting cold, the diesel in diesel heaters tends to gel up, which, in turn prevents your diesel heater from working properly. Ideally, the diesel in your heater should always be a liquid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll have a look at 4 simple ways to prevent diesel gelling in your diesel heater when it’s cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-fix-diesel-heater-fuel-gelling&#34;&gt;How to Fix Diesel Heater Fuel Gelling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To properly winterize your diesel heater, you can protect your diesel on 3 different levels:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diesel Heater E10 Error Code (3 Causes and Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/fix-diesel-heater-e10-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 21:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/fix-diesel-heater-e10-error/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diesel heaters are quite complex. Faults can be anywhere in the fuel pump, the blower, the glow plug, or the electric supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when your diesel heater shows an E10 error code without any context, you usually have no idea where to start looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article serves as a reference for the E10 error on diesel heaters. We’ll have a look at what the E10 code means, different reasons for the issue, and how to fix all of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diesel Heater Not Getting Hot (12 Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/diesel-heater-not-getting-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 09:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/diesel-heater-not-getting-hot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The single major disadvantage of diesel heaters is, in my opinion, that they contain too many different parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your diesel heater is not getting hot / not blowing hot air, the issue can be practically anywhere. It can be the fuel pump, electronic controls, the car battery, the atomizer, the combustion chamber, anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes them relatively hard to troubleshoot. However, it’s not as hard as you think. When diesel heaters stop working, it’s usually just a bunch of common problems you need to check.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diesel vs Propane Heater: Which To Pick? (5 Differences)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/diesel-vs-propane-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 06:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/diesel-vs-propane-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have a look at the vast amount of different diesel and propane heaters you can buy. It’s insane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you’re someone who has never used either of them, you’re probably wondering what’s even different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, as their names suggest, diesel heaters use diesel, and propane heaters use propane. That’s obvious. But the technical implications following the fuel choice are significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to have a look at the differences between diesel and propane heaters and which of both, in my opinion, is the better heater.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Best Child-Safe Heaters</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-child-safe-heaters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-child-safe-heaters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some space heaters are made specifically for families with children. However, most of these “child-safe space heaters” are actually regular space heaters that are designed to &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; child-safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But inherently, there’s nothing that makes them safer than space heaters for adults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really dislike the marketing scheme here. Just designing a dangerous device to &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; safe doesn’t make it safe. Especially not for children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll have a look at space heaters that are very safe for children, regardless of whether they are designed to look like baby / child products, or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson F4 Error Code: How To Fix It</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/fix-dyson-f4-error-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 13:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/fix-dyson-f4-error-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Encountering the F4 error on your Dyson appliance can be a cause for concern, but it’s often a problem you can solve yourself. This guide will provide you with a clear understanding of what the F4 error means for different Dyson models and the steps you can take to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;If your Dyson shows an F4 error, first try power cycling and checking for any obvious blockages or misalignments.&lt;/strong&gt; If the problem continues, it could indicate a motor or sensor issue, in which case you should contact Dyson support, especially if your device is still under the 2-year warranty. If not, consider replacing it with a newer model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Heater or Hot Water Bottle? (9 Differences)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-or-hot-water-bottle-9-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 15:28:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-or-hot-water-bottle-9-differences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been writing articles for this website for over 4 years now, spending hours and hours explaining space heaters and how to use them effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the while resting both feet against a hot water bottle lying on the floor, under my desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And one thought just popped up in my mind: Am I a hypocrite?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent so much time &amp;amp; effort writing about heaters and telling people which products to buy. All this, of course, earns me some money as well, when people buy from my recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Car Camping Heaters for Winter</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-car-camping-heaters-for-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 09:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-car-camping-heaters-for-winter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent countless nights in my car. This article is all about the best car camping heaters, found in years of trial and error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I learned is: You can make any night comfortable &amp;amp; warm with the right preparation, even without much special gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or … to be honest … &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; any night. Some nights are just doomed to be freezing cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for those freezing cold nights, all you think about is “why didn’t I bring a heater?”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Heat a Van in Winter</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-a-van-in-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 09:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-a-van-in-winter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all. First off, I want to say, I am absolutely no van expert since I don’t possess one myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I spent several nights in &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; cold environments, sleeping in an unheated car, sleeping outside on a freezing parking lot in mid-winter in the alps, and I even spent nights off-grid above 15,000 feet in the Himalayas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, even though I don’t drive a van around myself, I experienced quite a few nights in the freezing cold. And since I’ve been writing about heaters on this website for over 4 years now, it’s time to devote an article to the van community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Drip Tray Overflow Error: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/fix-dyson-drip-tray-overflow-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 14:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/fix-dyson-drip-tray-overflow-error/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptom:&lt;/strong&gt; Dyson Humidify+Cool shows a “Drip Tray Overflow” error after activating humidification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-humidify-cool-fans-worth-it/&#34;&gt;Dyson Pure Humidify+Cool&lt;/a&gt; is a combined humidifier, air purifier, and fan. When it works, it’s great. But the Humidify+Cool units encounter errors much more frequently than other Dyson fans, since they work with water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “Drip Tray Overflow” error is a common issue in Dyson Humidify+Cool fans that affects the device’s humidifying functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re having a look at what the error means, where it comes from, and how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Humidify&#43;Cool Not Humidifying: How To Fix It</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/fix-dyson-humidify-cool-not-humidifying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 08:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/fix-dyson-humidify-cool-not-humidifying/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;re focusing on a problem that many owners of the Dyson Pure Humidify+Cool have encountered: the unit not humidifying properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a frustrating issue, especially considering the investment you make in a Dyson product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide is designed to help you diagnose and fix the problem quickly and efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most common causes for the humidification not working is a clogged pump column, but there can be other reasons for its reduced functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Humidify&#43;Cool Fans: Are They Worth It?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-humidify-cool-fans-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-humidify-cool-fans-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dyson Humidify+Cool models cost a hefty price. The recent PH04 is around $900. Older models such as the PH03 still sell for $700 - $800.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what’s so special about a Dyson humidifier? Can it do more than just add humidity to your room? And is getting one worth it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to have a critical look at Dyson Humidify+Cool models, checking out how well they really perform and if they do justify their price tag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Best Basement Heaters (Gas &amp; Electric)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-basement-heaters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 10:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-basement-heaters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Heading into the colder months, we all know the struggle of keeping a basement warm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basements, notorious for being the coldest rooms in the house, demand efficient and effective heating solutions to transform them into comfortable living or working spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you require a permanent, powerful solution or a portable, occasional boost of warmth; whether you need a permanent, energy-efficient heater, or a heater with low upfront cost and high heat output, we&amp;rsquo;ve dissected the features, pros, and cons of the 4 best gas and electric basement heaters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Best Wood Workshop Heaters (Gas &amp; Electric)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-wood-workshop-heaters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 14:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-wood-workshop-heaters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A freezing cold wood workshop is uncomfortable to work in. But what’s the best heater for wood workshops?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wood workshops are quite special places not all heaters are suited for. Frequently, the air is dusty (from sawing and sanding), there’s a lot of flammable wood around, and oftentimes, wood workshops are not insulated too well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, an ideal wood workshop heater can handle dust exposure, is fire-safe, and outputs enough heat to keep your workshop at whatever temperature you desire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Best Tiny House Heaters (Gas, Electric, Wood)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-tiny-house-heaters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 09:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-tiny-house-heaters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first cold season in a tiny house is exciting. To make it through the winter, you will need a heat source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are dozens of options for tiny house heating. From expensive custom-made stoves to cheap electric space heaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will boil down tiny house heaters to a selection of a few core heaters that are affordable / reliable / simple to install - without being sidetracked to overly complex or even risky heating solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Deep Clean Cycle Not Working: How To Fix It</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/fix-dyson-deep-clean-cycle-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 11:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/fix-dyson-deep-clean-cycle-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The deep clean cycle on Dyson humidifiers is known to have several problems. For some, it won’t start, other times, it keeps stopping, and sometimes the timer is stuck and not counting down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any of these problems make a full deep clean cycle impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check out several different solutions for your Dyson humidifier’s deep clean cycle not working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-deep-clean-cycle-and-why-do-you-need-it&#34;&gt;What is the Deep Clean Cycle and why do you need it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep cleaning is the process of removing limescale by dissolving it with citric acid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric Kettle Keeps Boiling / Doesn’t Shut Off: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/fix-electric-kettle-keeps-boiling-doesnt-shut-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 12:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/fix-electric-kettle-keeps-boiling-doesnt-shut-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your electric kettle keeps boiling and doesn’t shut off? This is both frustrating and dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But don’t worry - you’ve landed in the right place. In this comprehensive guide, we’ll have a look at &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; your kettle keeps boiling (there are just 4 possible reasons) and how to fix each of the causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While writing this article, I discovered that kettles are actually incredibly easy to fix. At most, you’re going to need a screwdriver and a replacement switch (which costs just a few dollars).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat Storm Heater Not Working: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/fix-heat-storm-heater-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 07:13:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/fix-heat-storm-heater-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your heat storm heater is not working? It doesn’t turn on? Or it turns on, but the fan doesn’t blow? Or it turns on, but shuts off on its own after some time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I’ll show you simple fixes for these scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am Daniel, an electrical engineer who did electronic repairs professionally in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, heat storm heaters are comparably simple devices. They don’t have that many components that can break.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Wrong Air Quality / Temperature: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/fix-dyson-wrong-air-quality-temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 11:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/fix-dyson-wrong-air-quality-temperature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your Dyson fan suddenly shows wrong air quality reports and / or a wrong temperature?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes, the air quality report shows a 999 value and the temperature shows 0°C (or °K).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or the air quality report and temperature are stuck at a certain value, or they don’t show values at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This usually indicates a problem with the air quality and temperature sensor. Usually, the problem is easy to fix and requires just a few minutes of your time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Fan Warning Triangle (5 Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/dyson-fan-warning-triangle-error-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/dyson-fan-warning-triangle-error-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When your Dyson fan shows a warning triangle with an exclamation mark, something is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the warning triangle, your Dyson fan does not give you any further information about the issue, and no instructions on what to do now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll have a quick look at the warning triangle error, what causes it, and what you should do about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Daniel, I’m an electrical engineer. I’ve worked in a large repair department of an electronics company before. Let’s have a look at what’s going on together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson F2 Error Code: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/fix-dyson-f2-error-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 08:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/fix-dyson-f2-error-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The F2 error code on Dyson fans is simple to fix once you know what causes it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, Dyson doesn’t seem to know what causes the error. I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the reason for your Dyson fan showing the F2 error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptom:&lt;/strong&gt; Dyson fan senses a power drop, displays F2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cause:&lt;/strong&gt; Friction in the fan motor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; Disassemble and clean the fan, ensure the fan motor is snapped into position, tighten any screws&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The F2 error is comparably rare because it is related to internal friction inside the device. This usually happens when a Dyson fan is not carefully assembled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Reset the “F” Code On a Dyson Air Purifier</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-reset-the-f-code-on-a-dyson-air-purifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 08:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-reset-the-f-code-on-a-dyson-air-purifier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every few months, your Dyson air purifier will show an F code with three blinking lights next to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “F” code stands for “Filter” and signals you to replace your air purifier’s filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dyson recommends to do this every 6-12 months. Based on the time passed since you last replaced the filter (or since you bought the air purifier), and the filter’s airflow resistance, Dyson can determine when a filter replacement is due.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric Heater E1 Error: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-electric-heater-e1-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 10:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-electric-heater-e1-error/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your electric heater displays an E1 error code and you don’t know what to do? Worst of all, it stopped heating altogether and you can’t get it to run anymore?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry. The E1 error is usually simple to fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer, and in the past, I repaired electronics professionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s have a look at the issue together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-your-electric-heater-shows-an-e1-error-code&#34;&gt;Why your Electric Heater shows an “E1” Error Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-e1-mean&#34;&gt;What does “E1” Mean?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E1, standing for &amp;ldquo;Error 1&amp;rdquo;, often indicates an issue with the thermal cutoff switch or the thermostat in many electric heaters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lasko Heater Keeps Shutting Off (3 Causes and Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/lasko-heater-keeps-shutting-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 09:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/lasko-heater-keeps-shutting-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lasko ceramic heaters are very reliable. All the more surprising it is when your Lasko heater suddenly shuts off on its own. And after turning it back on, it doesn’t take long until it shuts off again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is happening here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the issue is, in most cases, very simple to fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-lasko-ceramic-heaters-shut-off-on-their-own&#34;&gt;Why Lasko Ceramic Heaters Shut Off On Their Own&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last ceramic heaters shut off on their own when they overheat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson F3 Error Code: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/dyson-f3-error-code-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 07:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/dyson-f3-error-code-fix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Owning a Dyson Pure+Cool or a Humidify+Cool fan has its fair share of perks, from enjoying a cool breeze to breathing cleaner air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when the F3 error code comes up, your Dyson Fan suddenly stops despite all seeming well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been scratching your head over this, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone: Nobody really knows what causes the F3 error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I’ll tell you how to fix the F3 error code, or at least,  how to reset it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Heater Ceramic Burner Tile Replacement (in 6 Steps)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/mr-heater-ceramic-burner-tile-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 10:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/mr-heater-ceramic-burner-tile-replacement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the chilly months, a reliable portable heater like Mr. Heater can be a true lifesaver, radiating warmth and making indoor spaces comfortable and cozy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, like all appliances, Mr. Heater units have components that may wear over time, and one such crucial component is the ceramic burner tile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The burner tile is prone to cracking due to the constant heating and cooling cycles it undergoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cracked burner tile can lead to inefficient heating and even pose safety risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Purifier Keeps Shutting Off (7 Reasons &amp; Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/fix-air-purifier-keeps-shutting-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 08:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/fix-air-purifier-keeps-shutting-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Air purifiers are great for keeping the air in your living space fresh and clean. All the more annoying it is when your air purifier keeps shutting off on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll have a look at 7 common reasons and how to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the troubleshooting is not difficult and for most fixes, you don’t need any electronics knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this is a layman’s guide to fixing an air purifier that keeps shutting off!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson H2 Error Code: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/dyson-h2-error-code-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 09:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/dyson-h2-error-code-fix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Encountering the H2 error code on your Dyson Hot+Cool fan can be a cause for concern, but don’t worry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This code indicates an overheating issue, often fixable with some straightforward troubleshooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s delve into the most common cause of this error and the steps to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-the-dyson-h2-error-code&#34;&gt;Understanding the Dyson H2 Error Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The H2 error code indicates overheating, usually stemming from dust and dirt accumulation around the heating elements.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When to Replace Your Air Conditioner: 3 Rules Of Thumb</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/when-to-replace-air-conditioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 08:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/when-to-replace-air-conditioner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is it time to replace my air conditioner?&amp;rdquo; This is a question that plagues many homeowners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air conditioners, unlike some other household items, don&amp;rsquo;t just stop working overnight. Instead, they degrade slowly, leaving you in a grey area about when exactly to invest in a new unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help the decision-making, rules like &amp;lsquo;replace it after 10 years&amp;rsquo; exist. But are they genuine?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found that most rules on the internet are constructed by the HVAC industry to sell you a new air conditioner way too early.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s the Best Space Heater Brand?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/whats-the-best-space-heater-brand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 11:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/whats-the-best-space-heater-brand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are hundreds of different space heater brands, ranging from Honeywell and Vornado to Dyson, DeLonghi, Dr. Infrared, and Mr Heater to many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to get your first space heater, all these choices can be confusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal with this article is to find out what the best space heater brand is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am Daniel, an electrical engineer and I’ve been writing about space heaters on heatertips.com for many years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric Fireplace Not Working: Tried &amp; Tested Fixes</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/electric-fireplace-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 07:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/electric-fireplace-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your electric fireplace is not working? In this article, we’ll try to get your heater working again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve been writing several in-depth articles on &lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/space-heater-not-blowing-hot-air/&#34;&gt;heater repairs&lt;/a&gt;. And the issues in electric heaters are always the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, it’s either a power supply issue, a thermostat issue, or a blown part in the electronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electric fireplaces are a bit special. They are a lot bulkier than regular heaters. And they come with some additional features, such as the moving lights, which also can stop working.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Electric Fireplaces Energy Efficient?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-electric-fireplaces-energy-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 12:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-electric-fireplaces-energy-efficient/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are electric fireplaces energy efficient? The first statement I see when I google for electric fireplace efficiency is that electric fireplaces have 100% efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds quite good, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not quite…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These statements about efficiencies are &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; misleading unless you know the physics of electric fireplaces precisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I am going to show you why the 100% efficiency of electric fireplaces is &lt;em&gt;meaningless&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after tearing these marketing statements down, we’ll find out how truly efficient they are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Infrared Heaters Heat the Air?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-infrared-heaters-heat-the-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 08:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-infrared-heaters-heat-the-air/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do infrared heaters heat the air? Or do they magically radiate heat through the air?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Infrared heaters don’t heat the air” is the single most common infrared heater myth. Since I started writing for this website, I’ve read it &lt;em&gt;everywhere.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just for fun and giggles, I googled “Do infrared heaters heat the air?” and the (current) number one result says that “infrared heaters don’t add [heat] to the air”&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is plain wrong!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix an Infrared Heater Not Working</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-an-infrared-heater-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 07:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-an-infrared-heater-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your infrared heater suddenly stopped working and you have no idea how to troubleshoot it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then this article is for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer and I’ve worked in an electronics manufacturing plant before! So, I know electronics both theoretically and practically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even if you don’t have a clue, I’ll try to help you as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;em&gt;complete&lt;/em&gt; troubleshooting guide. This means I’ll ask you specific questions about your infrared heater not working. And based on your answers, I’ll direct you to the cause of the issue and how to fix it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Best Shed Heaters (Gas &amp; Electric)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-shed-heaters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 07:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-shed-heaters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What’s the best heater for a shed? Of course, there is not a single right answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to have a look at 4 different space heaters that will work in your shed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll also explain in which situation each of the recommended heaters is best for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the end, we’ll have a quick look at some simple steps to improve your shed’s insulation. Insulation and heating go hand in hand, even in a shed!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Best Space Heaters for Garages</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-space-heaters-for-garages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 09:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-space-heaters-for-garages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What’s the best space heater for a garage? Which heater is best for your garage depends largely on your garage’s size, the power source you want to use (electric or fuel-based heating), and your willingness to install things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re having a look at the best garage space heaters. And I &lt;em&gt;guarantee&lt;/em&gt; you, you’ll know exactly which model is right for you after reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll have a look at the best heaters for different garage sizes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blueair Blue 211&#43; Review: Is It Worth It?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/blueair-blue-211-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 08:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/blueair-blue-211-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Blueair Blue 211+ is the largest air purifier in Blueair’s Blue series. But does its size benefit you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or are smaller models such as the 311 or 411 just as good?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, how does the Blueair Blue keep up with its competition?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blueair fiercely competes with Levoit and Coway, two of the most popular air purifier brands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, my goal is to answer all these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer, and on this blog, my top priority is finding out which heating, cooling, and air quality devices &lt;em&gt;really work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Best Air Purifiers for Small Rooms</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-air-purifiers-for-small-rooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 09:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-air-purifiers-for-small-rooms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What are the best air purifiers for small rooms? In this post, we’re going to check out air purifiers, for small rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And one interesting question we’re going to answer is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you even need a small air purifier for a small room?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is absolutely counterintuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, as an electrical engineer, it is my mission to spread the truth about small-room air purifiers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let’s start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;small-room--small-air-purifier&#34;&gt;Small Room = Small Air Purifier?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a misconception about air purifiers that seems hard to grasp for most people. But it’s actually quite simple:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bluegrass Living Propane Heater Review: Strong &amp; Reliable</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/bluegrass-living-propane-heater-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 07:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/bluegrass-living-propane-heater-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yay! I discovered a new product: The Bluegrass Living propane heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know where this model has been all the time, but the Bluegrass Living propane heater looks neat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending dozens of hours reviewing both ventless portable heaters and vented propane heaters, my results were clear: &lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/are-mr-heater-buddy-heaters-any-good/&#34;&gt;Mr Heater Buddy heaters&lt;/a&gt; are next to unbeatable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But possibly, &lt;strong&gt;Bluegrass Living models can compete&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let’s do a fully unbiased review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer and I write about heating and cooling methods on this website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Most Powerful Space Heaters</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/most-powerful-space-heaters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 07:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/most-powerful-space-heaters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to have a look at the most powerful space heaters. &lt;em&gt;In depth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re going to check:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which space heaters provide the most heat? (checking heaters with and without installation separately)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much electric power do they consume?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s the proper way to install and use them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And to round it all up: How to generate the most heat using only space heaters, but &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; installation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, a disclaimer: Since we’re really trying to find the absolute strongest space heaters on the market, most of the recommended products on this page are way too strong for regular living spaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Air Purifiers Need Water?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-air-purifiers-need-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 11:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-air-purifiers-need-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do air purifiers need water? And do you have to replace water regularly? Do you need to put in any maintenance work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quick post is going to answer all of that. Luckily, it’s very simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;No, most air purifiers never need water. Air purifiers pass air through a dry HEPA filter, which needs replacement every 6-12 months. Air purifiers with built-in humidifiers, however, need water replacements occasionally. But in this case, the water is not needed for air purification.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuwave OxyPure Review: Exceptional Filtration, Poor Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/nuwave-oxypure-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 06:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/nuwave-oxypure-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Nuwave OxyPure is one of the best-selling large air purifiers online. It’s time I put my hands on it and review it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I look for an in-depth Nuwave OxyPure review, I am surprised there is so little actual insight available. I mean there is plenty of information. But everybody just tries to sell you this air purifier, without consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let me tell you: The Nuwave OxyPure is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the best choice for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Big&#43;Quiet Review: High Price, High Performance?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/dyson-big-quiet-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 08:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/dyson-big-quiet-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dyson recently launched the Big+Quiet air purifier. I found out yesterday, after writing about &lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-air-purifiers-worth-the-money/&#34;&gt;whether Dyson air purifiers are worth the money&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally, as an HVAC blogger and electrical engineer, I get to know all new products on the market quickly. But the Big+Quiet entered the stage, as its name suggests, quietly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess the biggest reason is the price. &lt;strong&gt;At $1,000, the Dyson Big+Quiet is a luxury product.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you google the &amp;ldquo;Dyson Big+Quiet&amp;rdquo;, all you get is a wall of sales copy-type blog posts with no investigation beyond surface-level data and no questioning of marketing statements at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Dyson Air Purifiers Worth the Money?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-air-purifiers-worth-the-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 09:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-air-purifiers-worth-the-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Dyson air purifiers worth the money? Recently, Dyson launched its new product line, the Dyson Purifier Big+Quiet, which costs just around $1,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a huge price for an air purifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what’s so special about this thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that Dyson has been selling air purifiers for ages, as features built into the Pure Cool and Hot+Cool models, are Dyson air purifiers worth the money?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer. One of my favorite free time activities is to uncover marketing myths and publish them on this website. One of my most popular articles is about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-heaters-energy-efficient-a-critical-review/&#34;&gt;alleged better energy efficiency of Dyson heaters&lt;/a&gt;, which turned out to be a huge marketing lie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Vornado Heaters energy efficient?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-vornado-heaters-energy-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 08:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-vornado-heaters-energy-efficient/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vornado claims their heaters are energy efficient. They even have an entire &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vornado.com/savings&#34;&gt;savings&lt;/a&gt; page dedicated to how much you can save if you use a Vornado heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check Vornado heater energy efficiency and how much you can &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; save with a Vornado heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am Daniel, an electrical engineer. And I’ve been debunking heating myths on this website for 4 years. So, let’s take a deep dive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Vornado Fans Worth It? (Vortex Power or Marketing Hoax?)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-vornado-fans-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 09:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-vornado-fans-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Vornado fans worth it? In this article, we’re going to check how well Vornado fans &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; perform and whether they are worth the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am Daniel! I am an electrical engineer and I investigate electric devices &lt;em&gt;in-depth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t care about the Vornado brand and I am not affiliated with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, everything you read in this review is 100% independent information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, Vornado fans are worth it. They blow a focused stream of air, optimized for cooling people. Their build quality is superior to most other fans. A Vornado fan can easily last you 10-20 years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Space Heaters explode?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-space-heaters-explode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 12:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-space-heaters-explode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can space heaters explode? Space heaters can catch a fire if you use them incorrectly. But will they explode?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s important because an explosion could stun you and limit your ability to take action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am Daniel, an electrical engineer, and in this article, we’re going to check whether space heaters can explode and the fascinating engineering behind explosion-proof space heaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, space heaters don’t explode. In fact, it’s impossible for a space heater to explode. Let’s have a look.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are any Space Heaters made in the USA?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-any-space-heaters-made-in-the-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 10:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-any-space-heaters-made-in-the-usa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been looking for a space heater made in the USA for ages. I decided to put an end to it. In this article, we’re going to find out which space heaters are engineered, designed, or manufactured in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the rabbit hole is deep. While many space heater companies started manufacturing in the US, their manufacturing plants often left the country due to globalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;There are no space heaters that are 100% made in the USA, but some are engineered, designed, or assembled in the country. Brands like Vornado, Mr. Heater, and Lasko are American. My favorite American space heater is the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B002QZ11J6?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=heatertips-20&amp;amp;linkId=2123c0365f4cf1e6fc5710d8c9eb79ae&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Infrared DR-968&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Space Heaters for the Office</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-space-heaters-for-the-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 08:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-space-heaters-for-the-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Heating in the office can be unnecessarily complex, especially when using space heaters. Most workplaces either prohibit or limit the use of space heaters. And if space heaters are allowed, they have to fit certain size criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these rules can get very annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it&amp;rsquo;s practically impossible to heat an office to a temperature that suits everybody, space heaters can be a practical solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi! My name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer by profession and I write about space heaters every day!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Space Heaters for Rooms with High Ceilings</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-space-heaters-for-rooms-with-high-ceilings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 07:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-space-heaters-for-rooms-with-high-ceilings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Heating a room with high ceilings with only space heaters can be challenging. Not only does a lot of heat rise to the ceiling and is effectively wasted, but additionally, most space heaters are not very strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to explore how to properly heat rooms with high ceilings with just space heaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two fundamental approaches: Either get a very strong heater or get a heater that effectively distributes heat into your room and away from the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Space Heaters Burn Oxygen?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-space-heaters-burn-oxygen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 08:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-space-heaters-burn-oxygen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do space heaters burn oxygen? The cold season is approaching and there are plenty of space heater myths and misconceptions that make you stop and hesitate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If space heaters really burn oxygen, maybe you should find another way to heat. Should you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s stop the speculation and get right to the core of the matter. Here’s the answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electric space heaters never burn oxygen, since the source of the heat is not a chemical reaction. Only fuel-burning heaters such as propane heaters or kerosene heaters do burn oxygen. However, due to tiny oxygen inflow streams from outdoors through gaps and creeks, and the built-in oxygen depletion sensor many fuel-burning heaters are absolutely safe to use indoors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use a Dyson Hot &#43; Cool without the Remote</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-use-dyson-hot-cool-without-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 13:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-use-dyson-hot-cool-without-remote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you end up trying to turn your Dyson heater on, or change temperature settings, but apparently the remote doesn’t react? Or did you lose your Dyson remote control?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, you’re in the right place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer, and I’ve been writing about Dyson products for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a quick guide on how to control a Dyson Hot + Cool without the remote.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Space Heater Smell (Plastic, Burning)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-space-heater-smell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 10:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-space-heater-smell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After turning on a new space heater or a space heater that was long unused, it is very common to notice strange smells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some space heaters smell like something’s burning. Others give off plastic smells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check where your space heater smell comes from, whether it is dangerous, and, of course, how to eliminate the smell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer, who worked in the heat sensing industry. I love solving simple, day-to-day electronic problems. Not the abstract stuff you study at university.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix a Space Heater Cord getting Hot</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-space-heater-cord-getting-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-space-heater-cord-getting-hot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your space heater’s power cord is getting hot and you have no idea whether you should worry about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this guide, we are going to check your space heater’s cord together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer, and I have two space heaters at hand of which I am going to check cord temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One cord is getting hot, the other stays cool. But that&amp;rsquo;s normal. A space heater power cord getting hot is not necessarily dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Heater making Noise (6 Sound Samples &amp; Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-making-noise-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-making-noise-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve already talked quite a bunch about space heaters and other devices making noise on this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I am not really satisfied. After all, I can describe all the sounds space heaters make, but you still can’t be sure whether the sound your space heater is making is safe or needs repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I want to take a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each sound, I will embed a real-life noise sample you can play and listen to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ceramic vs Infrared Heater: Which is more energy efficient?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/ceramic-vs-infrared-heater-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 10:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/ceramic-vs-infrared-heater-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ceramic heater or infrared heater? Which one is more energy efficient and produces the most heat for the least cost?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to heating up your space, especially in those colder months, making an informed decision about which heater to use can save you both energy and money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With many options available, two popular choices often come up: ceramic and infrared heaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But which one is more energy efficient? Is there even a difference efficiency-wise?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Tower Fans better than Pedestal Fans? (Answer: NO)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-tower-fans-better-than-pedestal-fans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 10:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-tower-fans-better-than-pedestal-fans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are tower fans better than pedestal fans? Just recently, I noticed tower fans are trending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what are the differences between tower fans and pedestal fans? Are they better in any way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what makes them so popular?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to take a dive into understanding tower fans and their purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, what’s the gap a tower fan fills that makes people want to buy them?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coway Air Purifier Indicator Lights Meanings (Colors &amp; Blinking)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/coway-air-purifier-indicator-lights-meanings-colors-blinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 11:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/coway-air-purifier-indicator-lights-meanings-colors-blinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of your Coway air purifier’s indicator lights changed colors or started blinking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick, but complete guide on Coway indicator lights and their meanings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-air-quality-indicator-light&#34;&gt;1. Air Quality Indicator Light&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coway air purifiers have a built-in pollution sensor. Based on the sensor’s readings, the air purifier changes the air quality indicator light color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the model, the air quality indicator light changes as follows (according to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/D1SWYNC4nwS.pdf&#34;&gt;official Coway Airmega 300 / 400 user manual&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Fan not Cooling (5 Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/dyson-fan-not-cooling-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 09:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/dyson-fan-not-cooling-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Dyson fan not cooling (anymore) can be very frustrating. After all, Dyson fans are not cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to have a quick look at the 5 most common issues with a Dyson fan not cooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;A Dyson fan is usually not cooling because of blocked airways (air filter, air inlet holes). Also, check the set target temperature, and ensure your Dyson cooling fan does not run in backward airflow mode.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Air Purifiers Safe for Pets? (Dogs, Cats, Birds, etc.)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-air-purifiers-safe-for-pets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 08:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-air-purifiers-safe-for-pets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are air purifiers safe for pets? 4 months ago, my girlfriend got a puppy. Naturally, I have to take care of her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as an HVAC blogger, I have all kinds of devices at home, including an air purifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how did things turn out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did the dog survive the air purifier? (&amp;hellip; joking)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I am going to guide you through using air purifiers with pets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this, you’ll know exactly:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How long does a 420lb Propane Tank last?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-long-does-a-420lb-propane-tank-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 12:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-long-does-a-420lb-propane-tank-last/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The longevity of a 420lb propane tank varies significantly based on the heater you&amp;rsquo;re using it with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a smaller heating system, it might last you almost an entire season, but if you’re powering a strong industrial-scale heater, a 420lb propane tank can run out of gas in just a matter of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;A 420lb propane tank can last from roughly 60 hours up to an impressive 2,419 hours, depending on the heater&amp;rsquo;s BTU rating. With a standard household 9,000 BTU heater, it lasts for 805 hours (33 days) of uninterrupted heating. On the other hand, with an industrial-grade torpedo heater (120,000 BTU), it would last just about 60 hours.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use an Extension Cord with an Air Purifier?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-an-extension-cord-with-an-air-purifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 09:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-an-extension-cord-with-an-air-purifier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use an extension cord for an air purifier? In this article, we’re going to explore the art of using extension cords with air purifiers and how to stay safe at all times!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extension cords can pose a risk when not used appropriately. While air purifiers generally consume much less power than similar devices (such as portable air conditioners), safety precautions are still essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most extension cords can handle the little power an air purifier draws. But a very bad quality extension cord that can&amp;rsquo;t handle the required power can pose a risk of melting or even catching fire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix a Coway Air Purifier not working (Repair Guide)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-coway-air-purifier-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 07:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-coway-air-purifier-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Experiencing problems with your Coway air purifier? Whether it&amp;rsquo;s an indicator light, fan issue, or connectivity problem, we&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s your comprehensive guide to troubleshooting the most common issues with Coway air purifiers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coway air purifiers are &lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/are-coway-airmega-air-purifiers-worth-it/&#34;&gt;incredibly overpriced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, a Coway air purifier not working is annoying and can also cut a huge hole in your wallet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably don’t want to spend another $200 - $500 (or even up to $1,000 depending on the model) for a new Coway air purifier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Coway Airmega Air Purifiers worth it? (Critical Review)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-coway-airmega-air-purifiers-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-coway-airmega-air-purifiers-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Coway Airmega air purifiers worth it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know one thing about me, it’s most likely that I absolutely can’t stand overpriced garbage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And one of the worst things for me is seeing family and friends fall for marketing hoaxes … So, I hope I can at least save &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, dear reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Daniel, I am an electrical and aerospace engineer. And no HVAC company is safe from my bare honesty!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why your Air Purifier Smells (Musty, Wet Dog, Fish, etc.)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/why-your-air-purifier-smells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 10:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/why-your-air-purifier-smells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why does my air purifier smell musty, like plastic, sweet, or even like a wet dog?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That seems like a bad plot in a poor comic. I bought an air purifier to get the &lt;em&gt;exact&lt;/em&gt; opposite result!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just don’t buy an air purifier to make things smell &lt;em&gt;worse.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like you don’t eat food to get more hungry. And you don’t buy a car to drive you farther away from your destination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why your Air Purifier is not Removing Odors (&#43; Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/air-purifier-not-removing-odors-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 13:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/air-purifier-not-removing-odors-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your air purifier does not remove odors and you don’t know why? In this article, we’re going to check all the possible reasons and how to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having clean and fresh air is important for your well-being. And air purifiers are supposed to remove odors. Or are they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;( There will be a surprising answer to this question - not all air purifiers can remove odors )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you stick out until the end of this article, you’ll know exactly why your air purifier does not remove bad smells.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix an Air Purifier not Collecting Dust</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-an-air-purifier-not-collecting-dust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 12:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-an-air-purifier-not-collecting-dust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your air purifier is not collecting dust, even though you already run it for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-air-purifier-all-day/&#34;&gt;long time&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check all the possible causes of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And before we take the deep dive: Not all air purifiers have to collect dust. Dust is, in the end, just the particles that are visible to the eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air purifiers filter much smaller particles than that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, after some time, you should see &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; on the filters. If that’s not the case, today is the day this is going to change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Purifier making Noise (8 Noises &#43; Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/air-purifier-making-noise-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 12:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/air-purifier-making-noise-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your air purifier is making some noise and you wonder whether that noise is normal or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, you’re in the right place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check the different noises air purifiers can produce and what you can do about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some noises, for example, quiet humming are normal. However, loud buzzing, screeching, or even banging noises can even indicate that something dangerous is going on inside your air purifier and it needs repair.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix an Air Purifier not turning on</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-an-air-purifier-not-turning-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 12:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-an-air-purifier-not-turning-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s my complete guide on how to troubleshoot and fix an air purifier not turning on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air purifiers are very simple devices. There’s not much that can break if it does not turn on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, they are relatively simple to repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, my goal is to list &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; possible reason why your air purifier might not turn along with how to fix it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this article, you’ll know &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; how to fix your air purifier. And even if you can’t fix it, stick out until the end of this article. I still have a couple of ideas to get you a working air purifier quickly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run an Air Purifier and a Humidifier at the same time?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-air-purifier-and-humidifier-at-the-same-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 09:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-air-purifier-and-humidifier-at-the-same-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run an air purifier and a humidifier at the same time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a quick Google search. Here are the first results that pop up (in a nutshell).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google search results for the query “Can you run an air purifier and a humidifier at the same time?”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes (no explanation given &lt;em&gt;at all)&lt;/em&gt;( &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.filtrete.com/3M/en_US/filtrete/home-tips/full-story/~/running-an-air-purifier-and-humidifier-at-the-same-time/?storyid=59002fd2-fe9f-48a2-8c65-5be479d49355&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Of course, now buy our filters ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usairpurifiers.com/blog/can-you-use-air-purifiers-and-humidifiers-together/&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes… we are an industry leader in superior filter systems - contact us and buy from us! ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://ushomefilter.com/what-if-i-use-air-purifiers-and-humidifiers-together/&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t help but read these answers with a clown voice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run an Air Purifier with a Window open?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-air-purifier-with-window-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-air-purifier-with-window-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run an air purifier with a window open? In this article, we’re going to check whether it makes sense to vent your room while you run your air purifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, the answer is quite obvious: of course, you can run your air purifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as soon as you open your window, particles like pollen and bacteria enter your room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that a reason to stop your air purifier? Should you wait until the window is closed to run it again?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run an Air Purifier 24/7?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-air-purifier-all-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 11:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-air-purifier-all-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run an air purifier 24/7 (all day, every day)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is all about this question. But we don’t stop there. After reading this, you’ll not only know exactly &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; you can run your air purifier all day, but also whether it even &lt;em&gt;makes sense.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is not just to tell you what to do. A lot of search results are totally useless. For example, when I search for “Can you run an air purifier all day?”, the first result tells me “Yes”, but does not explain &lt;em&gt;why.&lt;/em&gt; (I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; a why!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Purifier Running Cost: The Ultimate Guide</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/air-purifier-running-cost-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 11:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/air-purifier-running-cost-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How much does an Air Purifier cost to run? I love my air purifier and I&amp;rsquo;d really like to run it 24/7. But how much would that cost?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this guide, I am going to answer how much running an air purifier for different durations costs (8 hours, 24 hours, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading the article, you&amp;rsquo;ll know exactly, &lt;em&gt;how much&lt;/em&gt; your air purifier costs to run, &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it costs so much (or so little), and how you can &lt;em&gt;reduce the power consumption even further&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Air Purifier: My Top Pick</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-air-purifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 20:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-air-purifier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like to stick to products that simply work. Personally, I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; marketing tricks and lies. And if you read my other articles on this website, I always prefer simplicity and sturdiness over shiny objects that can’t hold their promises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this time, let’s have a look at my favorite air purifier and why I decided to get this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The best air purifier is the Levoit Core 300. It is simple, collects a lot of dust and is easy to maintain. After using it for a month and seeing the thickness of dust it collects, it is evident why this air purifier is so popular.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Swamp Cooler: My Top Pick</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-swamp-cooler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 15:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-swamp-cooler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve seen me talk a lot about the Hessaire MC37M. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s on the list of top swamp coolers for garages or in our swamp cooler vs air conditioner comparison, the MC37M stands out. But why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The best swamp cooler is the Hessaire MC37M. It is robust, has more than enough power to cool even large spaces, and lasts a lifetime. For smaller rooms, you can get the MC18M model.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Swamp Coolers need open windows?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-swamp-coolers-need-open-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 09:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-swamp-coolers-need-open-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered if you need to leave your windows open for your swamp cooler to work effectively? The answer is no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;No, swamp coolers do not need open windows to operate effectively. For optimal performance and energy efficiency, it&amp;rsquo;s better to keep windows closed and control the indoor humidity through regular venting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, your cooler performs best with your windows closed and occasional venting. This contrasts with several misconceptions about swamp coolers: that the increased humidity must be constantly vented out, that longer running times lead to higher humidity, and that open windows help airflow. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll bust these myths and give you a clear guide to using your swamp cooler more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does putting ice in a Swamp Cooler make sense?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/does-ice-in-a-swamp-cooler-make-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 14:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/does-ice-in-a-swamp-cooler-make-sense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Does putting ice in a swamp cooler make sense? Hardly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It definitely skyrockets your swamp cooler running costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Putting ice in a swamp cooler doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense. The addition of ice doesn&amp;rsquo;t significantly enhance cooling, it increases energy consumption and cost, and ice melts rapidly in the cooler&amp;rsquo;s environment. Moreover, the design of many swamp coolers prevents the inclusion of ice in the tank.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-a-swamp-cooler-work-does-it-need-ice&#34;&gt;How does a swamp cooler work? Does it need ice?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A swamp cooler cools down air by evaporating water. Water evaporation sucks heat energy away from the air.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run a Swamp Cooler without water?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-a-swamp-cooler-without-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 08:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-a-swamp-cooler-without-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you need to refill a swamp cooler or can you run it without water? In this article, we’re checking how a swamp cooler uses water to cool and what happens once it runs dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to popular belief you can run a swamp cooler without water! And in extreme situations, you can even refill a swamp cooler without access to water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s find out how!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can run a swamp cooler without water. Once the water runs out, it becomes a simple fan. So, you still have a (reduced) cooling effect. In an emergency, where you don’t have access to water, you can collect morning dew by placing the water pads outdoors overnight. The humidity is enough to cool you in the afternoon heat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Cooler vs Air Conditioner (Cost comparison)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/swamp-cooler-vs-air-conditioner-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/swamp-cooler-vs-air-conditioner-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Swamp cooler vs air conditioner. What’s the better choice for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I am comparing swamp coolers and air conditioners&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus here is to provide you with an objective comparison. For every comparison, I am providing numbers and indisputable facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading through all the sections, you will know whether a swamp cooler or an air conditioner suits you better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Swamp coolers are way cheaper to run and do not require any installation. Air conditioners, however, work anywhere and anytime. Swamp coolers work best in dry and hot climates.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix Swamp Cooler Smell</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-swamp-cooler-smell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 18:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-swamp-cooler-smell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to fix swamp cooler smell. Swamp coolers are the ultimate breeding ground for bacteria and bad odors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the dust that comes in from the outside collects on the air filters and the wet water pads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few days in the summer heat, the smell is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swamp coolers stink naturally. Especially, when they’re used a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let’s have a look at how you can get rid of the smell by cleaning your swamp cooler.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where do Swamp Coolers work? (US States List)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/where-do-swamp-coolers-work-us-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 10:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/where-do-swamp-coolers-work-us-states/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether a swamp cooler works depends on the climate in your area. In this article, we’re having a quick glance at all US states and whether swamp coolers work there or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Swamp coolers work in&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;every US state during the afternoon, because that is the driest time of the day. Using a swamp cooler all day and throughout the year only makes sense in Arizona, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, New Mexico, Utah, and Wyoming.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can a Swamp Cooler run all day?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-a-swamp-cooler-run-all-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 15:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-a-swamp-cooler-run-all-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run a swamp cooler all day? How humid will your living space be? And is there a risk of the electronics blowing up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can run a swamp cooler all day. Swamp coolers do not add humidity to your room indefinitely, because they run at room temperature (and don’t boil the water like a kettle). Also, they run on very little electric power, so they don’t overheat. To maximize running time, lubricate the fan every year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can a Swamp Cooler catch on fire?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-a-swamp-cooler-catch-on-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 08:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-a-swamp-cooler-catch-on-fire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can a swamp cooler catch on fire? What happens when they run out of water?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;A swamp cooler will not catch fire, even when the water runs out. Swamp coolers run on low wattages, which makes overheating highly unlikely. Swap coolers are the safest cooling devices (together with fans).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-swamp-coolers-overheat-when-they-run-out-of-water&#34;&gt;Do swamp coolers overheat when they run out of water?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A swamp cooler is a fan that blows air through wet sponge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Best Swamp Coolers for Bedrooms</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-swamp-coolers-for-bedrooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 13:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-swamp-coolers-for-bedrooms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; few swamp coolers that are actually good. In this article, we’re looking at the 3 best swamp coolers to use in a bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The best bedroom swamp coolers are the Hessaire MC37M and MC18M models. Their water tanks last for a full night if you run them on half-power. Alternatively, you can connect them to a tap for continuous refills.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After checking my 3 different recommendations, we will also have a look at whether it makes sense to run a swamp cooler in your bedroom and see if there are better alternatives for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Best Swamp Coolers for Garages</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-swamp-coolers-for-garages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 11:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-swamp-coolers-for-garages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Garages get very hot in the summer. Let’s have a look at the best swamp coolers specifically for garages!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I looked for garage swamp coolers online, I was actually a bit surprised by the lack of information about garage swamp coolers. I mean, when you look for garage swamp coolers, you want a sturdy, durable, and maintainable device, that will last you for many summers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You usually don’t care about looks. You don’t want plastic screws. You want a swamp cooler that can take a hit, and which you can easily move around the garage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix a Dyna-Glo Heater not lighting</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-dyna-glo-heater-not-lighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 13:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-dyna-glo-heater-not-lighting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only a few parts can cause a Dyna-Glo heater not lighting. Typically, they are the parts that ignite and measure the pilot light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, a Dyna-Glo heater not lighting is usually easy to fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at all the possible problems and how you can fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-fix-a-dyna-glo-heater-not-lighting&#34;&gt;How to fix a Dyna-Glo heater not lighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Dyna-Glo heater is not lighting. So, to find out the cause of your issue, we have to trace the path of ignition, starting with the tank, followed by the propane hose, the igniter, the pilot light, and the thermocouple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix a Vornado Heater not working</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-vornado-heater-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 10:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-vornado-heater-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your Vornado Heater is not working and you don’t know why? In this article, we’re going to check everything you can do to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the official Vornado website is not helpful at all. All you get is a “troubleshooting” document that tells you to turn the heater off and on. Not helpful at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another tip you get in the document is to not use your heater with a Ground Fault Circuit Interrupter (GFCI) safety wall outlet… which is, in my opinion, pointless advice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Vented Propane Heater without Electricity</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-vented-propane-heater-without-electricity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 11:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-vented-propane-heater-without-electricity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You are looking for a vented propane heater that does not use electricity? Unfortunately, they don’t exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I am going to explain to you why you can’t find a vented propane heater that does not use electricity (for off-grid heating) anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, we’re going to check what you can do about it. Freezing is not an option!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Vented propane heaters always need electricity to power their built-in fan which blows waste gases through the vent. Propane heaters that don’t require electricity to run are always ventless. The best ventless propane heater without electricity is a Mr. Heater Buddy heater or a wall-mounted Dyna Glo propane heater.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How long does a 20lb Propane Tank last?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-long-does-a-20lb-propane-tank-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 11:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-long-does-a-20lb-propane-tank-last/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How long a 20lb propane tank lasts depends on the heater you use with it. Depending on how much you use your propane tank, the tank can empty in one day, or in a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check all the different possible durations. You just have to look up your heater’s heating power (in BTU per hour).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;A 20lb propane tank lasts for 38 hours of heating on a regular 9,000 BTU portable propane heater. On larger heaters (30,000 to 60,000 BTU) it lasts between 6 and 12 hours.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix a Honeywell Space Heater not working</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-honeywell-space-heater-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 09:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-honeywell-space-heater-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your Honeywell space heater is not working? In this article, we’re troubleshooting and fixing your Honeywell space heater using just a few targeted questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article covers all of the most-used Honeywell space heaters, including the Honeywell tower space heaters (Slim and HeatGenius) and the smaller Honeywell heaters (the 360-degree and UberHeat).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry if you have a different Honeywell heater. Most Honeywell heaters work just the same internally. So, you can follow this guide regardless!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Best Vented Gas Heaters</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-vented-gas-heaters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 10:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-vented-gas-heaters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being a heating blogger and an electrical engineer, the internet never ceases to disappoint me. When I looked for the best vented gas heaters online, I found only bogus results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost every article recommended heaters that looked like vented gas heaters but were actually ventless. Heck, even Walmart fails to differentiate between ventless and vented gas heaters when you use their search option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check out the best &lt;em&gt;&amp;amp; truly vented&lt;/em&gt; gas heaters. Spoiler: There are tons of choices, but only a few are good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Space Heaters Not Hot to Touch</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-space-heaters-not-hot-to-touch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 11:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-space-heaters-not-hot-to-touch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What are the best space heaters that are not hot to touch? When you have children or pets around, space heaters that are hot to the touch are not an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, you’re going to learn about space heaters with the lowest possible surface temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The Dyson Hot + Cool is the best space heater that’s not hot to the touch. The combination of an embedded heating element and a built-in fan that blows heat out of the heater’s body prevents surface overheating. A more cost-effective alternative is a DeLonghi oil-filled radiator, which maximizes its surface area using&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;thermal slots&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;, and, therefore, minimizes the chance of burning your fingers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaporative Cooler not turning on (7 Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/evaporative-cooler-not-turning-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 12:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/evaporative-cooler-not-turning-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your evaporative cooler is not turning on? In this article, you’re getting a complete list of things you should inspect before you declare your evaporative cooler dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re going to check the most common issues and their fixes. And along the way, you’re going to learn a bunch about the inner workings of your cooler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;An evaporative cooler won’t turn on if it does not receive electric power. This could be due to a broken wall outlet, power cord, or blown fuse. But broken parts such as blown electronics, water damage, or an empty water tank can also stop your evaporative cooler from turning on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Cooler not Blowing Cold Air (8 Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/swamp-cooler-not-blowing-cold-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 11:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/swamp-cooler-not-blowing-cold-air/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your swamp cooler is not blowing cold air? In this article, I guide you through fixing your swamp cooler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do that, we’re going to check the different possible reasons why your swamp cooler is not blowing cold air. For each cause, I list a way to test for this cause and one or more methods to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;A swamp cooler is not blowing cold air when the fan does not blow air or when the water pads are not soaked. Possible causes include a broken fan, clogged air filters, a broken water pump, or clogged water lines. Usually, cleaning the clogged parts, replacing air filters, and checking the connection points of the water lines solves the issue.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Cooler making Noise (7 Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/swamp-cooler-making-noise-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 12:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/swamp-cooler-making-noise-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your swamp cooler is making noise? In this article, we’re going to cover the most common noise types, including humming, screeching, buzzing, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each noise, you’re going to learn where it comes from and how you can fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Swamp coolers often make humming, gurgling and crackling noises. These are expected. You can reduce these normal noises with anti-vibration pads. Screeching, buzzing, scratching and banging noises are signs of unlubricated parts, loose parts, or faulty electronics. You can fix these noises with silicone lubricant, by tightening the parts in place, or by replacing the noisy parts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Window AC making Noise (9 Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/window-ac-making-noise-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 10:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/window-ac-making-noise-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your window AC is making noise? In this article, we’ll cover all the different noise types in window ACs. For each noise, we check whether it is dangerous, the cause for the noise, and, of course, how to fix it (if necessary).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Window AC noises are usually&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not dangerous.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;But scratching, whistling or banging noises indicate larger failures in your window AC which you have to address. The most common cause for window AC noises is broken parts in the compressor or fan, such as broken bearings or broken brackets which allow the fan or compressor to jump around in your window AC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blue Flame vs Infrared Heater: Which is better?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/blue-flame-vs-infrared-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 12:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/blue-flame-vs-infrared-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are blue flame or infrared heaters better? The answer is: Blue flame and infrared heaters are &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; the same. Together, we’re going to myth bust blue flame and infrared heater differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after reading this article, you know exactly which heater to pick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Technically, infrared heaters are better than blue flame heaters since they radiate some of the heat into the room. Blue flame heaters emit hot air which rises upward. So, infrared heaters have a slightly better heat distribution. However, practically, blue flame and infrared heaters both produce radiant and convection heat. So, the main difference is looks. Heating output, gas usage, and efficiency are equal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the safest Propane Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/whats-the-safest-propane-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 10:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/whats-the-safest-propane-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the safest propane heater? When it comes to propane heater safety, &lt;em&gt;everybody&lt;/em&gt; is claiming different things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I am going to uncover propane heater safety myths and tell you only the facts that &lt;em&gt;everybody&lt;/em&gt; agrees on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an experiment, I bought a propane heater, and actually tried to burn things. And I measured propane heater temperatures using a laser thermometer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the measurements, you can tell what is and what isn’t a safe propane heater.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Mr. Heaters safe in a tent? (Fact checked)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-mr-heaters-safe-in-a-tent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 09:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-mr-heaters-safe-in-a-tent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Mr. Heaters safe to use in a tent? Many use Mr. Heater Buddys (and other models) as their primary outdoor heat source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are great in cabins, RVs, and in workshops. But can you use a Mr. Heater in your tent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will check whether Mr. Heaters can ignite or melt tent walls and whether they emit carbon monoxide. And of course, we will check whether it’s possible to run a Mr. Heater for a full night in a tent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Mr. Heaters any good? (Critical Review)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-mr-heater-buddy-heaters-any-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 12:18:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-mr-heater-buddy-heaters-any-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Mr. Heater Buddy heaters any good? &lt;em&gt;Everybody&lt;/em&gt; recommends Mr. Heaters all the time. So, I bought one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together we will have a look at how good they &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to be &lt;em&gt;extra critical&lt;/em&gt; in this article and pay attention to all the fine-grained details that other websites leave out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s uncover the truth about Mr. Heater!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Mr. Heater Buddy heaters are not good for everyone. They get over &amp;gt;1,000°F. Their protection grid can’t prevent fire. And on a 1-pound propane bottle, a Mr. Heater lasts only for 5.4h on the lowest setting. So, they don’t last a full night unless you bring a larger propane tank.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;However, these issues are present in all propane heaters with the same heat output.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Heater Smoking (4 Fixes)&amp;nbsp;</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-smoking-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 08:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-smoking-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your space heater is smoking? Immediately unplug it from the wall outlet! Then, grab a tea (or whatever you like) and make yourself comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this article, you will know &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; what to do about your smoking space heater. We will check whether you should get a new one, and if not, how to fix the most likely causes of your space heater smoking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Space heaters usually smoke from the heating elements, the internal power electronics, the power cord, or the case. Smoking heating elements usually indicate dust. Clean them with rubbing alcohol. If smoke comes out the inside, then check the electronics for blown parts and replace them. Similarly, check your power cord for issues and replace it if necessary.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use a Gas Stove as a Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-gas-stove-as-a-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 11:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-gas-stove-as-a-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use a gas stove as a heater? Especially in emergencies, when there is no electricity and even central heating turns off, you need a backup heat source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a gas stove at home, then using it could be an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; you need to know about emergency heating using your gas stove. And you’re going to learn about better (and more cost-efficient) alternatives to gas stoves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Propane Heaters need electricity?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-propane-heaters-need-electricity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 08:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-propane-heaters-need-electricity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do propane heaters need electricity? There are two kinds of propane heaters. Those that need electricity, and those that don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, you will learn which propane heaters you can use without electricity, completely off-grid!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you will learn about the types of propane heaters that use electricity and &lt;em&gt;why.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;No, portable propane heaters never need electricity and work fully off-grid. However, central heating propane furnaces need electricity to run their built-in electronic thermostat, timers, and fans. Also, some RV propane heaters rely on the 12V car battery to run. Because only portable propane heaters work without electricity, you should always have one at home as an emergency heat source. Alternatively, you can power your propane furnace off a generator.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you put a Space Heater on a table?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-put-a-space-heater-on-a-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 09:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-put-a-space-heater-on-a-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you put a space heater on a table? When I googled this phrase initially, I found answers diverging all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People answered “yes” and “no” everywhere without actually proving their point somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to place my three space heaters (oil-filled radiator, infrared heater, and propane heater) on top of a living room table and see if anything happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I am going to prove that you can place your space heater on tables as well using simple physics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is Infrared hotter than visible light?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/why-is-infrared-hotter-than-visible-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 14:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/why-is-infrared-hotter-than-visible-light/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why is infrared radiation hotter than visible light? Why do we use infrared heaters and not &lt;em&gt;visible&lt;/em&gt; light heaters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, you will find out why infrared radiation is so common in heating and what makes infrared the only reasonable heat source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Infrared radiation is not hotter than visible light. Most radiators (in a physical sense), however, emit the majority of their heat as infrared radiation. This makes infrared heat the most common form of heat in your everyday life. A single-wavelength visible light laser or LED shows that you do perceive visible light as heat as well.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much do Infrared Heaters cost to run?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-much-do-infrared-heaters-cost-to-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 09:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-much-do-infrared-heaters-cost-to-run/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How much does an infrared heater cost to run? In this article, we’re going to check the average infrared heater’s running cost, by running time, location, electricity rate, and usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After checking the cost, we will have a look at how to reduce the cost to run your infrared heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also check whether a thermostat will &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; help reduce infrared heater running cost and I will recommend you the infrared heater I think is best!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood Stove not getting hot (12 Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/wood-stove-not-getting-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 11:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/wood-stove-not-getting-hot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your wood stove is not getting hot? In this article, we’re going to check the most common reasons and ways to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this article, you will know exactly how to get your wood stove as hot as you need it to be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will know exactly what to do and &lt;em&gt;why.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;A wood stove usually does not get hot because of an insufficient oxygen supply. You can fix this by opening the air intake valves and cleaning the burning chamber, the vents, and the wood grate. Also, make sure that you use seasoned firewood. Also, verify that your chimney’s diameter fits your wood stove size. You can maximize chimney airflow with a chimney liner.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Propane Heater making Noise (7 Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/propane-heater-making-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 12:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/propane-heater-making-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your propane heater is making noises and you don’t know how to fix it, or if the noise is normal? In this article, we’re going to check all of the common propane heater noises!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this article, you’ll know exactly where your heater’s noise comes from and whether you can do anything about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each noise listed, you’ll find a way to test for and fix the respective noise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Fan not Rotating (7 Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/dyson-fan-not-rotating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 18:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/dyson-fan-not-rotating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating to find out that your Dyson fan is no longer rotating. Obviously, how would you circulate the air in your room without this feature?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Dyson fan may have stopped oscillating for several reasons. And usually, the issue is relatively easy to fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I will share with you the most common reasons why your Dyson fan isn&amp;rsquo;t oscillating, along with troubleshooting and fixing instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Dyson heaters usually don’t rotate if there’s still tape on your Dyson fan&amp;rsquo;s base body split section. Additionally, if the fan doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit right in its base and dust accumulates in the oscillation system (oscillation motor), the system won&amp;rsquo;t work and thus won&amp;rsquo;t oscillate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Propane Heater keeps shutting off (7 Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/propane-heater-keeps-shutting-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 10:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/propane-heater-keeps-shutting-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your propane heater turns on but keeps shutting off? After reading this article, you will know what to do to fix your propane heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve listed the most common causes for your propane heater not staying lit along with an explanation, and a way to test for and fix each cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Propane heaters usually keep shutting off and don’t stay lit because of a dirty pilot light or thermocouple. A thorough cleaning of your pilot light with rubbing alcohol and a Q-tip should fix it. Also, ensure your gas line has no kinks and you don’t move it while heating. If this doesn’t work, a triggered safety mechanism such as tip-over protection or overheat protection could be the cause.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Ventless Heaters cause Carbon Monoxide Poisoning?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-ventless-heaters-cause-carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 11:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-ventless-heaters-cause-carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you get CO poisoning from a ventless heater?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can &lt;em&gt;theoretically&lt;/em&gt; get carbon monoxide poisoning from a ventless heater. However, it is very unlikely as long as you vent your room every few hours. Ventless space heaters are among the most common source of carbon monoxide poisoning in homes. Modern ventless heaters are designed not to produce CO when functioning properly, but many factors, including poor ventilation and dirt, can make the heater less than safe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix a Mr. Heater Buddy not lighting</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-mr-heater-buddy-not-lighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 14:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-mr-heater-buddy-not-lighting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your Mr. Heater Buddy is not lighting? Fixing a Mr. Heater that does not turn on is usually simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, you’re going to learn how to get your Mr. Heater running again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You can fix your Mr. Heater Buddy not lighting by cleaning the pilot light opening with a Q-tip and rubbing alcohol. Also, firmly smack your Mr. Heater 5-10 times. If gas comes out of the pilot light opening, but your heater does not spark, use a lighter to ignite the gas. Replace the igniter in the long run.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Propane Heaters safe indoors?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-propane-heaters-safe-indoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 10:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-propane-heaters-safe-indoors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are propane heaters safe for indoor use? In this article, we’re going to answer this question by checking the temperature a propane heater produces. Then we can conclude, whether propane heaters cause a fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we will follow up with a look at the combustion of propane gas and whether it creates any toxic waste materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After checking all of these “scary” aspects of propane heaters, you’re going to learn how to use a propane heater safely. And I am going to recommend you my favorite indoor-safe propane heater!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use a Surge Protector with a Space Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-surge-protector-with-a-space-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 15:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-surge-protector-with-a-space-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Surge protectors are the best safety devices to handle voltage spikes and power surges and keep your devices safe. But can you use a surge protector with your space heater?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we can&amp;rsquo;t answer this with a yes or no, because there are certain things you need to consider before using a surge protector with a space heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you if you should use a surge protector with your heater. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m going to do some calculations that will make it easy for you to choose the suitable surge protector for your space heater.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Propane vs Electric Space Heater: Which is better?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/propane-vs-electric-space-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 12:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/propane-vs-electric-space-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Should you get a propane heater or an electric heater? Which one is better for you? In this article, I am going to introduce you to all the relevant differences between propane and electric heaters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this article, you will know exactly in which case you should prefer propane heaters over electric heaters and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s actually quite simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Propane heaters are better than electric space heaters for rooms without a heat source or access to electricity. They are cheaper to run and can produce more heat. Meanwhile, electric space heaters don’t need refills and are usually safer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Best Ventless Propane Heaters</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-ventless-propane-heaters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-ventless-propane-heaters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing the right heater for your home or office is a daunting process. There are so many different types and sizes of heaters, it can be challenging to decide which one is right for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best ventless propane heaters on the market are those manufactured by Rinnai and Dyna-Glo, which are known for their high quality, efficient heating capabilities, and safety features.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll go over the five best ventless propane heaters on the market. We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the features and benefits of each one, so you can make an educated decision and find the right heater for your needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Infrared Heaters safe indoors?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-infrared-heaters-safe-indoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 11:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-infrared-heaters-safe-indoors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are infrared heaters safe to use indoors? Can they be a fire hazard? In this article, I am going to tell you exactly how hot infrared heaters get, which materials they can ignite and whether they can start a fire on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I will tell you how to safely run an infrared heater. And we will check whether you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need an infrared heater (because there is a safer space heater type).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How long does a Propane Tank last on a Patio Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-long-does-a-propane-tank-last-on-a-patio-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 15:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-long-does-a-propane-tank-last-on-a-patio-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How long does a propane tank last on a patio heater? The answer to this question depends on several factors, such as propane tank size, the heating capacity of the patio heater, propane burning efficiency, and the quantity of propane in the tank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to help you better understand, I will look at all the factors and calculate how long your propane tank would last on your patio heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;An average patio heater (45,000 BTU/h) lasts 7 hours with a 20lb propane tank, 10 hours with a 30lb propane tank, and 13 hours with a 40lb propane tank. A propane tank’s running duration depends on its size, the heat capacity of the heater, and the burning efficiency of your patio heater. Patio heaters between 10,000 BTU/h and 50,000 BTU/h with a 20lb propane tank would last 30 hours to 6 hours.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix a Dyson Heater not turning on</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-dyson-heater-not-turning-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 12:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-dyson-heater-not-turning-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your Dyson heater is not turning on? In this article, I am going to guide you through different possible causes. For each cause, you’re going to learn how to test and fix it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are looking for a solution on Dyson’s official website, all you’re getting is this text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Issue not resolved, please speak to our Customer Support Team”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dyson - &lt;em&gt;expressing love for their customers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I bet you don’t want to spend your day waiting for some uninterested call center employee at Dyson to pick up the phone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How long can you run a Dyson Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-long-can-you-run-a-dyson-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 10:29:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-long-can-you-run-a-dyson-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How long can a Dyson heater run without interruption? Is it safe to run a Dyson heater overnight?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to inspect &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; we need to find out how long a Dyson heater can truly safely operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re going to check&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the design of a Dyson heater and where the heat accumulates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how hot Dyson heaters get&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how much power Dyson heaters draw and whether that can overload circuits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whether Dyson heaters can melt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the end, we’re going to conclude with what you can do to prepare your Dyson for long heating sessions!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix a Dyson Heater not Blowing Hot Air</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-dyson-heater-not-blowing-hot-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 12:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-a-dyson-heater-not-blowing-hot-air/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your Dyson heater is not blowing hot air? The usual cause for this is blocked airways, issues with the thermostat, or a broken part in the electronic circuitry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, you will find each of the most common causes as well as instructions on how to inspect and test and fix the respective cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Your Dyson heater usually does not blow hot air if the airways are blocked with dust, dirt, and moisture. You can fix this by dry-brushing the internal parts using a toothbrush. Also, clean all of the air inlet holes in the case of the heater. Set your thermostat properly. And inspect the electronic circuitry if it still does not work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Infrared Heaters need to be vented?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-infrared-heaters-need-to-be-vented/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 10:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-infrared-heaters-need-to-be-vented/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do infrared heaters need venting? In this article, we’re going to have a quick check!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;No, you never need to vent an electric infrared heater. Electric infrared heaters don’t burn fuel or gas. Therefore, they emit no waste gases or water vapor. Only fuel or gas-based heaters need venting. However, you can run a portable propane infrared heater without venting for a few hours. You will only have to vent your room occasionally. Other gas or fuel-based heaters need a fixed vent installation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to make an Infrared Heater more efficient?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-make-an-infrared-heater-more-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 09:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-make-an-infrared-heater-more-efficient/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Increasing the efficiency of an infrared heater is easy, and you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a technician to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I will give you some tips for increasing infrared heater efficiency and reducing energy costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer:  &lt;strong&gt;You can increase your infrared heater&amp;rsquo;s perceived efficiency by adequately insulating your room (windows, cracks, and gaps below the door). Also, place your infrared heater facing into the room, or facing directly toward people. The technical efficiency of infrared heaters is always 100% since all electric energy ends as heat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run an Infrared Heater overnight?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-an-infrared-heater-overnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 08:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-an-infrared-heater-overnight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run an infrared heater all night? In this article, we’re going to measure the temperature of my infrared heater’s heating elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we can check whether this temperature is night-safe (i.e. will it burn or melt anything?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I am going to recommend you a night-safe infrared heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can run a quality infrared heater overnight given it is made of fireproof material and has built-in overheat protection. The radius of up to 2 feet in front of a space heater has to be free of any objects, as within this radius high temperatures up to 750°F can occur. Place your infrared heater at a safe distance from your bed without any objects blocking the heat radiation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to insulate a Window AC (for Efficiency)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-insulate-a-window-ac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 10:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-insulate-a-window-ac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How can you insulate a window air conditioner? Usually, the window kit that comes with a window AC does not fit perfectly and leaves room for heat to enter your room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let’s have a look at some improvements you can make to improve your window AC’s insulation (and, therefore, its &lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/how-to-make-a-window-ac-more-efficient/&#34;&gt;cost-efficiency&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You can add insulation around a window AC by gluing styrofoam panels around the sides. To close all air gaps, use spray foam or foam tape. If available, close your outdoor shutters to reduce the amount of heat entering your room.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to make a Window AC more efficient (9 Methods)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-make-a-window-ac-more-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 21:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-make-a-window-ac-more-efficient/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Window ACs are power-hungry! Even though they are one of the most-efficient AC types, their running cost adds up over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain 3 essential things you should do to make your window AC more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer: &lt;strong&gt;You can make your window AC more efficient by insulating windows and gaps below your door. Also, clean the evaporator coil and air filter. To avoid efficiency-decreasing dirt accumulation, clean your window AC’s internals yearly. Additionally, use high-quality extension cords (instead of cheap ones) and run your AC on a moderate cooling setting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Candles cause Carbon Monoxide Poisoning?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-candles-cause-carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 20:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-candles-cause-carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, candles can cause carbon monoxide poisoning, but it’s highly unlikely. Candles produce very little carbon monoxide. That’s not enough to cause poisoning unless you light many candles in a small, unventilated space, which would increase carbon monoxide emissions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that doesn’t mean lighting candles is 100% safe. Since carbon monoxide is undetectable by all five senses, it can be difficult to establish when the CO from candles is nearing dangerous levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use an Oil-filled Radiator in an RV?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-an-oil-filled-radiator-in-an-rv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 10:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-an-oil-filled-radiator-in-an-rv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use an oil-filled radiator in an RV? Sure! But you have to make sure you use a proper power source!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can use an oil-filled radiator in an RV. You can run any oil-filled radiator off shore power, off a generator, or off the batteries using an inverter. However, electric heating is not always the most cost-effective form of heating when you are off-grid.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check all you need to know about oil-filled radiators. And in the end, we’ll see whether there are better heating options for your RV!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use an Oil-filled Radiator in a Bathroom?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-an-oil-filled-radiator-in-a-bathroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 16:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-an-oil-filled-radiator-in-a-bathroom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use an oil-filled radiator in a bathroom? Or will it take damage from the humidity, or even be a safety threat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check whether and how to use oil-filled radiators in bathrooms, along with the necessary safety precautions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can use an oil-filled radiator in a bathroom. The large metal heating body is completely safe, even when water is splashed on it. Only the front panel of an oil-filled radiator contains sensitive electronics. So, avoid exposing it to water. An electric shock from an oil-filled radiator by accident is almost impossible unless you really try. Also, oil-filled radiators need no ventilation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix a Window Air Conditioner not Cooling</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-window-air-conditioner-not-cooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 13:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-window-air-conditioner-not-cooling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your window air conditioner is not cooling? In this article, I am listing all of the possible reasons!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll tell you &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; how to test each cause and how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list is sorted by issue frequency. So, the most common reasons are listed first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;To fix a window air conditioner not cooling, ensure that all airways are free. Clean the evaporator coil. Ensure that the power supply is OK and that there is no issue with the power cord. Also, properly insulate the window setup of your window AC. If nothing helps, get a new window AC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is my Oil-filled Radiator not getting hot? (6 Fixes)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/oil-filled-radiator-not-getting-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 09:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/oil-filled-radiator-not-getting-hot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your oil-filled radiator doesn’t get hot? I&amp;rsquo;m going to share some of the potential causes of why your oil-filled radiator is not getting hot so that you can check and fix those problems and get your heater running again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer: &lt;strong&gt;Oil-filled radiators stop heating because of a broken thermostat. Also, the thermostat can cut off the heating if the room is already warm. Furthermore, oil-filled radiators will not start and get hot if the power supply and extension cord are faulty.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you burn Coal in a Wood Stove?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-burn-coal-in-a-wood-stove/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 13:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-burn-coal-in-a-wood-stove/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coal has been used to heat homes and workplaces for centuries, but is it possible to burn coal in a wood stove?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;It is not recommended to burn coal in a wood stove. While it is possible, it is not efficient and can cause damage to your stove. A coal stove needs a grate at the bottom in order to allow air from below the fire to burn efficiently. Without this grate, wood stoves won&amp;rsquo;t be able to burn coal properly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Improve Oil-filled Radiator Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-improve-oil-filled-radiator-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 10:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-improve-oil-filled-radiator-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How can you improve the heating and cost-efficiency of an oil-filled radiator?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three different efficiencies that we want to optimize for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical efficiency - How much electricity is converted to heat?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perceived efficiency - How much heat does actually reach you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost efficiency - How much heat do you get for your money’s worth?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we are going to cover all three different kinds of efficiencies. For each efficiency type, I am going to give you straight-to-the-point advice on how to optimize your oil-filled radiator!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is my Propane Heater using so much gas?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/why-is-propane-heater-using-so-much-gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 10:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/why-is-propane-heater-using-so-much-gas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If your propane heater uses too much gas, it&amp;rsquo;s time to check for possible reasons and fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;m going to reveal some of the major causes that are messing with your propane heater and causing it to consume more gas than usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also going to highlight some precautions you should take if you want your propane heater to consume less gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer: &lt;strong&gt;Your Propane heater consumes more gas than usual if there is a leakage in the gas tank, hose, or heater itself. Also, a lack of insulation, or using undersized heaters in large rooms can increase gas consumption.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How long does a 100lb propane tank last?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-long-does-a-100lb-propane-tank-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 13:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-long-does-a-100lb-propane-tank-last/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How long a 100lb propane tank lasts depends entirely on the propane heater that you connect to it. While a small heater can run for many weeks, a very strong industrial-grade heater will only last one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;A 100lb propane tank lasts anywhere between 13 hours to 576 hours depending on the heating power. On an average household 9,000 BTU heater, it will last for 192 hours of heating. On a (very) strong industrial-grade torpedo heater it will last 13 hours only.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can You Run a Wood Stove Pipe through a Window?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-wood-stove-pipe-through-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 11:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-wood-stove-pipe-through-window/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run a wood stove pipe through a window?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wood stove pipe connects the chimney to the stove, and it&amp;rsquo;s meant to exhaust fumes out of your home. But what if your house or RV doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a chimney?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can run a wood stove pipe through a window by using a pre-made window plate kit or making one yourself using double-walled metal pipes and a metal sheet to cover the window space. Ensure the pipe is angled upwards and lifted above the roof to increase efficiency.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run two Portable ACs at once?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-two-portable-air-conditioners-at-once/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 17:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-two-portable-air-conditioners-at-once/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Running two portable air conditioners simultaneously on the same circuit is not a good practice, as it will increase energy consumption or may trip your circuit breaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still, if you want to run two portable ACs simultaneously, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you whether you can do it or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you an alternative to portable ACs that will consume less energy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer: &lt;strong&gt;You can run two portable air conditioners at the same time on the same circuit if they do not draw current more than the ampere rating of the circuit (15A - 20A). A 15A circuit and 110V - 120V outlet voltage (US) will not support two portable air conditioners. On the other hand, you can easily run two portable air conditioners when the outlet voltage is 220V - 230V (Europe and UK) and the circuit ampere rating is 15A - 20A.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where to Place an Infrared Heater? (3 Example Placements)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/where-to-place-an-infrared-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 11:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/where-to-place-an-infrared-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What’s the best place to put your space heater? In the corners? Or in the middle of the room?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check different space heater placements and how they affect your heater’s efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You should place your space heater facing toward the center of the room or the area where people are. The closer you place your heater to people, the higher the perceived heat, but the worse is the area coverage of the infrared radiation. The infrared heater’s radiation should not be blocked by any objects in between. You can safely place your infrared heater on the floor or on the carpet as long as no pets are around.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use a Space Heater for a Sauna?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-space-heater-for-a-sauna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 14:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-space-heater-for-a-sauna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use a space heater as a heat source for your sauna? Yes! In this article, I am going to tell you exactly what you have to do and what you should consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can use space heaters to heat a sauna. However, you either have to use two electric space heaters without built-in thermostats simultaneously or one propane gas heater for heating. Adding insulation to your sauna helps increase to raise the possible maximum temperature.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Heat Pumps dry the air?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-heat-pumps-dry-the-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 15:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-heat-pumps-dry-the-air/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do heat pumps dry the air? In this article, we’re going to check if a heat pump will dehumidify your room’s air (Spoiler: They don’t, but the air feels dryer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, we’re going to check how you can keep your room’s humidity at a comfortable level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;No, heat pumps do not dry the air. Instead, they reduce the air&amp;rsquo;s relative humidity, making it feel dryer. This phenomenon is typical to all heaters and not specific to heat pumps. The reduced relative humidity is what you perceive as dry air. In case you prefer humid air, you will need a humidifier.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Quietest Portable Air Conditioners (47dB - 52dB)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/quietest-portable-air-conditioners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 14:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/quietest-portable-air-conditioners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the 5 quietest portable air conditioners between 47dB and 52dB. You’ll find all cooling capacities between 8,000 BTU and 14,000 BTU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each quiet portable air conditioner, I’ll also list the room size each model is good for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The quietest portable air conditioner is a 47dB TOSOT unit. After that, most quiet air conditioners are rated either 51dB or 52dB. An average portable air conditioner is 56dB, which is&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;more because each 3dB increase doubles the perceived noise volume.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is a Single-Hose or Dual-Hose AC Better?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/is-a-single-or-dual-hose-portable-ac-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 14:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/is-a-single-or-dual-hose-portable-ac-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many people are confused about which type of portable air conditioner to buy. If you are also questioning whether to buy a single-hose or dual-hose AC, here&amp;rsquo;s your answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dual-hose portable air conditioners are more efficient than single-hose as they don&amp;rsquo;t suck any outdoor air into the room due to negative pressure. A dual-hose unit is perfect for larger spaces because it can cool an area more quickly and efficiently than a single-hose AC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Best Air Conditioners for Small Rooms</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-air-conditioners-for-small-rooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 10:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-air-conditioners-for-small-rooms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Air conditioners for small rooms should not take up much space, effectively cool your room, and don’t consume much electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check the best air conditioners for small rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The best air conditioner for small rooms is a 5,000 BTU window air conditioner. Getting a larger air conditioner and cooling your entire living space (instead of just one small room) is even more cost-effective because small rooms can’t keep the cold air for long and heat up quickly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Ways to Improve Wood Stove Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-improve-wood-stove-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 22:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-improve-wood-stove-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is your wood-burning stove not producing enough heat? Or does it consume too much firewood?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;To improve your wood stove’s efficiency, use a firewood holder, use properly dried wood, and keep the chimney and the airways clean. Additionally, you can install a wood stove insert or a reflective wall heat shield.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-improve-wood-stove-efficiency-13-methods&#34;&gt;How to improve wood stove efficiency (13 Methods)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a full list of all the ways to improve your wood stove’s efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Long do Oil-Filled Radiators Last?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-long-do-oil-filled-radiators-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 16:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-long-do-oil-filled-radiators-last/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oil-filled radiators last a long time. In our wood workshop, we have a 30-year-old oil-filled radiator that’s still fully functional. In comparison, other space heater types age much faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s check what makes an oil-filled radiator last for so long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And also, I am going to tell you what you can do to increase your oil radiator’s lifespan &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;An oil-filled radiator lasts at least 20+ years. If it is not exposed to weather and large temperature changes, then it can easily work well beyond 30 years. The main reason is that oil-filled radiators don’t have any built-in moving parts that wear down.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Air Conditioners Wear Out? (High vs Low Maintenance)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-air-conditioners-wear-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 12:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-air-conditioners-wear-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Air conditioners wear out over time. However, you can do something about it. In this article, you’re going to learn how long air conditioners last, and how you can extend the lifespan of your air conditioner!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, air conditioners wear out. You can expect an air conditioner to last 20+ years if you maintain it once a year. If you skipped your maintenance, you can revive your air conditioner by changing air filters, cleaning the evaporator coil, and fully dusting the internals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Best Propane Heaters for High Altitude</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-propane-heaters-for-high-altitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 17:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-propane-heaters-for-high-altitude/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the best propane heaters for high altitude. The burn of propane heaters becomes less efficient with increasing altitude. However, some heaters are proven to work by the camping and outdoor community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check the best propane heaters for high altitudes. We’re going to check why altitude is a problem for &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; propane heaters. And we’re going to check what you can do about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Cheapest Ways to Cool a Garage</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/cheapest-ways-to-cool-a-garage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 15:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/cheapest-ways-to-cool-a-garage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have a garage, you know it can be hot and sweaty. Not only is it uncomfortable to be inside a hot garage during the summer, but a cool garage helps you stay cool-headed when you&amp;rsquo;re doing car repairs or other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The cheapest way to cool a garage is a floor or ceiling fan. Insulation additionally prevents the heat from entering your garage on hot summer days. Installing air conditioning is rather expensive but very effective for cooling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Remove Smell in a Portable AC</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-remove-smell-in-portable-ac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 12:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-remove-smell-in-portable-ac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to remove smell in a portable AC?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The only way to remove smell from a portable AC is to open it up and clean the components. You may have to identify where the smell is emanating from and what&amp;rsquo;s causing it, but it&amp;rsquo;s safer to clean and deodorize the entire appliance regularly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remove the smell from your portable AC, just follow the steps below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-remove-portable-ac-smell&#34;&gt;How to remove portable AC smell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying the cause of the smell is sometimes a try-and-error method. You must check each component and clean or change what is necessary until the smell is gone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use a Portable AC when it’s Smoky outside?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-portable-ac-when-smoky-outside/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 08:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-portable-ac-when-smoky-outside/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can only use &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; portable ACs when it’s smoky outside, whether that’s because of wildfires or due to an industrial area nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check which air conditioners are OK to be used and which aren’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You should not use a single-hose portable AC when it’s smoky outside. However, you can always use dual-hose portable ACs, window ACs and split ACs, as these don’t suck in outdoor air.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Heat a Cabin without Electricity (5 Methods)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-a-cabin-without-electricity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 10:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-a-cabin-without-electricity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To heat a cabin without electricity, your best options are wood or propane gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The best way to heat a cabin without electricity is a wood-burning stove or a propane heater. Both wood and propane gas provide lots of heat at a low cost. Heating with wood minimizes your dependency on anyone since it is available (for free) around your cabin.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-5-best-methods-to-heat-a-cabin-without-electricity&#34;&gt;The 5 Best Methods to Heat a Cabin without Electricity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at 5 different methods to heat an off-grid cabin without electricity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which Air Conditioner Type is Best for a Garage? (1,2,3,4 cars)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/which-air-conditione-type-is-best-for-garage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 09:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/which-air-conditione-type-is-best-for-garage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mini-split ACs are the best air conditioner type for garages. In this article, we’re checking three different air conditioner types: portable, window, and split ACs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a garage, you should not shortcut your air conditioning. Here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Mini-split ACs are the best type of air conditioner for garages. They provide enough cooling power, don’t consume any floor space, and don’t need any windows for installation. A good mini-split unit will last you for decades if you take care of it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Vent a Portable AC Without a Window?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-vent-portable-ac-without-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 16:44:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-vent-portable-ac-without-window/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using a window to vent your &lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/most-powerful-portable-air-conditioners/&#34;&gt;portable air conditioner&lt;/a&gt; is the simplest method, but not every room in your home has access to a window. Although it could be demanding and difficult, employing an alternative to vent your air conditioner is not impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick answer: You can vent a portable air conditioner without a window by using different alternatives such as; through the door, wall, drop ceiling, chimney, or even the dryer vent. It is possible that not every alternative may apply to you since they have different requirements, but you can always check which one would work well for you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Install a Wood Stove in a Mobile Home</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-install-a-wood-stove-in-a-mobile-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 15:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-install-a-wood-stove-in-a-mobile-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You want to install a wood stove in your mobile home? Here’s how you can do it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;To install a wood stove in a mobile home, get a mobile home-approved wood stove model. Then, drill a hole through the roof where you insert a double-layered pipe or a firebox. Then, connect the pipe to your wood stove and mount the stove’s feet to the floor.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optionally, add tiles to the walls surrounding your wood stove.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can You Use a Propane Heater in an RV?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-propane-heater-in-an-rv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 09:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-propane-heater-in-an-rv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A portable propane heater can be a source of fast, efficient heat during chilly nights and winter months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But can you use a portable propane heater in an RV? Is it safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can use a propane heater in an RV. However, the heater must be fully functional (ideally new) and its oxygen intake must be well-adjusted. Also, always ensure the propane heater stands firmly. If necessary, build an anti-tip-over construction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Best Portable Air Conditioners for Garages</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-portable-air-conditioners-for-garage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 10:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-portable-air-conditioners-for-garage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What are the best portable air conditioners for garages? Where should you set up the portable AC in your garage? Especially, when you don’t have a window, you’ll need some installation work. And how can you maximize the efficiency of your garage AC? This article will clarify all of these questions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The best portable air conditioner for garages is the Whynter ARC-14S. Because it’s a dual-hose AC, it’s very efficient when cooling hot garages. However, you will need a window fitting two hoses or you will need to drill two holes in your garage wall for installation. If that’s too much, get the recommended Black+Decker single-hose portable AC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix a Portable AC not turning on</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-portable-ac-not-turning-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 11:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-portable-ac-not-turning-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your portable AC won’t turn on? Here’s how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;To fix a portable AC not turning on, check fuses and circuit breakers. Ensure the wall outlet is powered. Check clogged air filters and the drain pan. Check for internal ice buildup and verify that compressor and ducts are sealed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry! For each of those causes, I’ll tell you exactly how to check it and which steps to take to fix it. Let’s go one by one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Most Powerful Portable Air Conditioners</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/most-powerful-portable-air-conditioners/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/most-powerful-portable-air-conditioners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most powerful portable air conditioners are 14,000 BTU. One Honeywell portable AC even has 15,000 BTU of cooling power. However, it’s almost always out of stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too bad, Honeywell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The most powerful portable air conditioner is a 15,000 BTU AC by Honeywell. However, this model is always out of stock. Instead, the 14,000 BTU dual-hose Whynter ARC-14S provides the most powerful and efficient cooling. If that is not enough for you, you should get a 25,000 BTU window air conditioner instead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cost-Effective Heating and Cooling Methods</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/cost-effective-heating-and-cooling-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 16:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/cost-effective-heating-and-cooling-methods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On HeaterTips, you get &lt;strong&gt;honest, cost-effective, and technically solid recommendations&lt;/strong&gt; on heating and cooling your home!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Daniel. Everything you read on this page is backed by my &lt;strong&gt;own experiments&lt;/strong&gt; which I perform in my &lt;strong&gt;home lab&lt;/strong&gt;, studies, and my own experience using heaters, air conditioners, and air purifiers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t care about product brands, marketing, design, and all of that stuff. I just recommend what works and what is reasonable for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you Run Two Space Heaters at once? (Experiment Confirmed)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-two-space-heaters-at-once/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 12:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-two-space-heaters-at-once/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can run two space heaters at once almost anywhere in the world except in the US. Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to find this out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;On regular US 120V wall outlets you can run two space heaters at once on reduced heating settings only (80% or less). On 220V-240V (eg. UK, Europe) power outlets you can run two space heaters on full power since more voltage means less amperage which means less tripping of circuit breakers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s the Difference between a Window vs Split AC?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/whats-the-difference-between-window-ac-and-split-ac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 11:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/whats-the-difference-between-window-ac-and-split-ac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Window ACs and Split ACs differ in their internal structure. But the difference is not only technical. It also affects the efficiency, cost, noise, and installation cost of the different AC types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Window ACs are window-mounted, low-cost, but noisy. Split ACs are wall-mounted, rather expensive, but more powerful and quiet. Both window and split ACs have a similar cooling efficiency. Technically they are equally capable of cooling large rooms.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Best Space Heaters for Hot Yoga</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-space-heaters-for-hot-yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 13:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-space-heaters-for-hot-yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can do Hot Yoga on infrared heaters, oil-filled radiators, or even propane gas heaters. For hot yoga, it’s critical that the heater&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;does not auto shut-off&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;heats to the desired temperature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The best space heaters for Hot Yoga are the Mr. Heater Big Buddy (propane heater) or the Dr. Infrared Heater. Both heat quickly, don’t turn off and provide enough power to get small rooms to 100°F.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Radiant Floor Heating Add Value to Your Home?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/does-radiant-floor-heating-add-value-to-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 08:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/does-radiant-floor-heating-add-value-to-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Radiant floor heating is a popular choice for people who want to improve their home&amp;rsquo;s comfort and energy efficiency. But does it also add value to your home?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes, radiant floor heating can add value to your home. But it is expensive — before adding floor heating, ensure your house is well-insulated, as insulation gives you a much better return on investment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiant floor heating adds value to your home in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Solar Panels Power a Heat Pump?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-solar-panels-power-heat-pump/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 16:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-solar-panels-power-heat-pump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Solar panels can power a heat pump. Here’s how many solar panels you need to cover a heat pump’s power consumption. Additionally, you’ll get to know the cost of installing the solar panels as well as the heat pump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you need 17 solar panels to run an average 3-ton heat pump. Depending on the unit size and efficiency of your heat pump, you will need anywhere between 5 to 32 solar panels. Check the table below to see how many solar panels you need to run your heat pump.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Space Heaters Emit Carbon Monoxide?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-space-heaters-emit-carbon-monoxide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 10:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-space-heaters-emit-carbon-monoxide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Electric space heaters don’t emit carbon monoxide. But gas- and fuel-burning heaters can emit carbon monoxide!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Electric space heaters never emit carbon monoxide. However, fuel or gas-burning heaters can produce carbon monoxide if broken or improperly adjusted. You can avoid indoor carbon monoxide buildup by using the right space heaters and regularly venting your room.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we&amp;rsquo;re shedding light on what type of space heaters can emit carbon monoxide, and how you can carbon monoxide-proof your home. Also, you’re going to learn about the most important gas-protection measures when running a fuel-burning space heater indoors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Much Power Does a Heat Pump use? (1-5 Tons)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-much-power-does-a-heat-pump-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 17:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-much-power-does-a-heat-pump-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Heat pumps use between 545W and 4,286W of power depending on unit size and energy efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, you’re going to learn how to calculate heat pump wattages and yearly running costs. But don’t worry! You won’t have to do a single calculation yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have calculated all the wattages and yearly running costs for the most common heat pump sizes (1-5 tons) and the most common energy efficiencies (SEER ratings between 14 and 22) for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Size Generator can run a Heat Pump?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/what-size-generator-can-run-a-heat-pump/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 18:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/what-size-generator-can-run-a-heat-pump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only home standby generators can power heat pumps larger than 2 tons. However, even smaller heat pumps require expertise in wiring and setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check the wattages, different heat pump sizes use, and which generators suit each heat pump size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Only a home standby generator can power a medium-sized heat pump. Small heat pumps of 1-2 tons can be powered off large portable generators. However, getting a portable generator just for powering a heat pump is cost-inefficient. Rather, consider getting a wood stove or a propane heater. These provide more BTUs of heat energy for less money.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run a Space Heater off a Solar Panel?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-space-heater-off-solar-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 16:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-space-heater-off-solar-panel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can run a space heater on solar panel energy. However, running a space heater on high heating settings continuously gets expensive quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can run a space heater off a solar panel. One solar panel produces enough energy to run one space heater on full power for 1.2h a day. To run a space heater continuously, you need 20 solar panels. Wood-burning stoves or propane gas heaters are more cost-effective for off-grid heating.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Ways to Heat a Room without Electricity</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-room-without-electricity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 17:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-room-without-electricity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you have to keep warm without electricity. Whether in an electricity outage or in an off-grid location, it&amp;rsquo;s always good to know the best possible ways to heat a room without electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through the most cost-effective &amp;amp; least energy-intensive ways to heat a room without electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading it thoroughly, you&amp;rsquo;ll know plenty of alternative heat sources. Some of them can heat entire houses, like wood, others are emergency heat methods that require next to no energy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Heat a Large Room (Methods &amp; Cost)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-a-large-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 14:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-a-large-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To heat a large room using wood can be as cheap as $300 a year. With space heaters, you’ll pay around $54 - $108 a month.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s never easy to find a heat source that is well-suited for large rooms. Either you have to pay a lot, or it’s hard to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, you can always turn up your central heater’s temperature settings. However, that increases your heating bill significantly. Central heating heats the entire home and, therefore, produces more heat than is needed for a single room.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Heat a Room Without a Heater</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-room-without-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 13:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-room-without-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not the best idea to use heaters, especially at this point when utility costs are so high. However, you obviously cannot let yourself freeze to death. I&amp;rsquo;ve got some pretty good alternatives for you that will heat your space without using a heater. How amazing would that be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick answer: You can heat a room without a heater using candles, running electronics, an electric blanket, a hair dryer, or simply wearing warm clothing. The cheapest method to heat a room is using a low-wattage infrared heater since it bundles heat radiation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Space Heaters Save Money?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-space-heaters-save-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 16:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-space-heaters-save-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do space heaters save you money? And if yes, how? Space heaters use a lot of electricity. Nevertheless, you can use them to increase your home’s heating efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we are going to cover how you can cut your heating bill using space heaters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Space heaters save you at least $162 yearly if you reduce your central heater’s temperature by more than 8°F (4.4°C) and supply heat using two space heaters. If you use just one space heater to supply heat, your heating bill is reduced by at least $324 a year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Terracotta Clay Pot Heater</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-build-a-terracotta-clay-pot-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 16:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-build-a-terracotta-clay-pot-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the ultimate guide on how to make a terracotta clay pot heater to reduce your heating expenses in the cold season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utility and electricity bills are at an all-time high currently and I have been looking for ways to save some money while still keeping my expenses low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check everything you need to know about terracotta clay pot heaters, how to build them, which materials are best and how to set them up safely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Portable Air Conditioners Run 24/7?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-portable-air-conditioners-run-continuously/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 15:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-portable-air-conditioners-run-continuously/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating to repeatedly turn your &lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/how-does-a-portable-air-conditioner-work/&#34;&gt;portable air conditioners&lt;/a&gt; on and off, and you might want to keep them on forever. The question now is whether it is even safe to run them 24/7. Here&amp;rsquo;s the answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Answer: Yes, portable air conditioners can run 24/7. While it may not have a negative impact on the AC itself, it will result in an increase of your electricity bill by around $151.20 a month. If you really need to run your portable AC that much, you should rather get a wall-mounted AC unit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Dyson Cooling Fans Worth It?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-cooling-fans-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 14:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-cooling-fans-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Dyson cooling fans worth it? Dyson is known for their high-quality, technologically advanced cooling fans, among other household items. But are they really worth that hefty price?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;No, Dyson cooling fans are not worth it and overpriced. For venting a room, a regular floor or pedestal fan will perform just as well. However, Dyson cooling fans can be worth it in some situations for their directional, strong airflow and their design.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Solar Panels Heat a House?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-solar-panels-heat-a-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 09:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-solar-panels-heat-a-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can solar panels heat a house? In this article, we&amp;rsquo;re going to check how much electric power solar panels produce and how you can use this power to heat your home. We’re going to consider the effects of different seasons of the year on your solar power generation and the power yields of different roof sizes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, solar panels can heat a house. To heat your home on solar panels only, you will need to install 19 solar panels to power electric heating, or 7 solar panels to power a heat pump with a coefficient of performance (CoP) of 3.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why does your Portable Air Conditioner Collect no Water?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/portable-air-conditioner-collects-no-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 14:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/portable-air-conditioner-collects-no-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why does your portable air conditioner collect no water? In this article, we’re checking 5 possible reasons and how to fix them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Your portable air conditioner collects no water because it is either broken or the water tank leaks. Low air humidity is also a potential cause. Another cause is that your portable AC is an evaporative cooler, which does not collect water.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s have a look at each of those reasons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Portable Air Conditioners Safe?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-portable-air-conditioners-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-portable-air-conditioners-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Portable air conditioners can be a great way to keep your home cool and comfortable during the hot summer months. But before you buy one, it&amp;rsquo;s important to ensure it is safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, portable air conditioners are safe. As long as you maintain them properly and run them on moderate settings, there are no health hazards. They are also safe for children and pets since there are no exposed hot parts and no sharp edges.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can You Use a Window Air Conditioner without a Window?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/use-window-air-conditioner-without-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 11:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/use-window-air-conditioner-without-window/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use a window air conditioner without a window? In this article, you will learn 3 methods to set up your window AC when you only have a room without regular windows at hand, through a regular or a sliding door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Window units are designed specifically to be mounted on a window. The warm air and water produced during the cooling process escape to the outdoors through the window. But if you don’t have a suitable window in that room, you can improvise another way to remove those by-products without a window.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix a Portable Air Conditioner not Cooling</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-portable-air-conditioner-not-cooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 08:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-fix-portable-air-conditioner-not-cooling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to fix a portable air conditioner not cooling? In this article, we’re checking the 6 most common causes, how to test your portable AC for them, and how to repair each of the causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Place your portable AC in a room that suits its size. Insulate the hose and window kit using aluminum wrap and HVAC tape. Clean clogged air filters and the evaporator coil. Then, drain the water tank. Finally, make sure your portable air conditioner is set to cooling mode.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run a Portable AC off a Generator?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/run-portable-air-conditioner-off-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 14:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/run-portable-air-conditioner-off-generator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run a portable AC off a generator? This article is all about the size of generator you need to power a portable air conditioner. And, of course, how to do it safely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You can run most portable air conditioners on 2500W AC generators. For portable air conditioners with over 14,000 BTU cooling capacity, you need over 3000W generators. Make sure the generator is located outside to prevent carbon monoxide exposure indoors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Cheapest Ways to Cool a Room &amp; House</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/cool-room-house-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 10:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/cool-room-house-cheap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about the cheapest ways to cool your room, your house, and yourself. In this article, we’re going to cover a ton of different home-cooling methods, packed with advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will find something suitable for your situation. Whether you need to cool your room &lt;strong&gt;without an AC, without electricity, or without windows&lt;/strong&gt;. Everything is in here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also included a few feel-cold methods that do not need any devices, which you can use anytime, anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Remove Mold in a Portable Air Conditioner</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/remove-mold-portable-air-conditioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 10:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/remove-mold-portable-air-conditioner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to remove mold in a portable air conditioner? AC units provide the perfect conditions for mold to grow-oxygen, moisture and matter. And since they push air around your house, it means a moldy air conditioner will be blowing microscopic mold spores into the air you breathe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you suspect there could be mold in your portable AC, either because of seeing or smelling it, this article will help you solve that problem once and for all. But here’s the summary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are DeLonghi Portable Air Conditioners Good?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/delonghi-portable-air-conditioner-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 08:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/delonghi-portable-air-conditioner-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are DeLonghi portable air conditioners good &amp;amp; worth it? DeLonghi is widely known as a reputable brand that produces great electronics. Let’s have a look at whether you should spend the money or not!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, DeLonghi portable ACs are good, but they are more expensive than most other brands. The main advantages are that they are quiet, have more advanced features and some do not give off greenhouse gas emissions. However, for most people, there are many lower-priced air conditioners that will do the same job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Portable Air Conditioners give off Carbon Monoxide?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/portable-air-conditioner-carbon-monoxide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 10:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/portable-air-conditioner-carbon-monoxide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do portable air conditioners give off carbon monoxide? There are two reasons why many homeowners ask this question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer &lt;strong&gt;: No, portable air conditioners do not give off carbon monoxide. Carbon monoxide is only created from fuel-burning devices such as furnaces, gas stoves, and generators. Portable ACs use electricity so there is no risk of them emitting carbon monoxide.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are a few uncommon situations whereby your portable AC could be involved in circulating carbon monoxide in your home. Read on to learn the real culprits you should be worrying about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portable Air Conditioner Running Cost (Ultimate Guide)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/portable-air-conditioner-running-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 13:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/portable-air-conditioner-running-cost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s everything you need to know about portable air conditioner running cost. No fluff, just the facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer, and in this article, I am telling you all about the average running cost of portable air conditioners in different locations, for different models. You’ll find a formula to calculate the exact running cost of the portable AC you want to buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you stick around to the end of the article, I am telling you exactly what to do to reduce your portable air conditioner’s electricity usage!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Portable Air Conditioners need to be Vented?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-portable-air-conditioners-need-to-be-vented/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 14:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-portable-air-conditioners-need-to-be-vented/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do all portable air conditioners need to be vented? If so, why do all air conditioners need a hose? And can you use a portable AC without a hose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, all portable air conditioners need to be vented. The heat extracted from the air has to leave your room, otherwise, it will mix up with the cold air again. Ventless ACs are a marketing scam and never work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do you have to put Water in a Portable Air Conditioner?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/put-water-in-portable-air-conditioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 08:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/put-water-in-portable-air-conditioner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you have to put water in a portable air conditioner? The answer to this question uncovers a huge marketing scam, so keep reading until the end. You’ll be shocked. But before that, here’s the quick answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You don’t have to put water in a portable air conditioner. Portable air conditioners extract heat from the air and vent it out the window. The cooling process condensates water which accumulates in the air conditioner. Rather, you have to drain water from your portable AC. Any air conditioner where you put in water or ice cubes is a junk product!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Portable Air Conditioners need Regassing?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-portable-air-conditioners-need-regassing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-portable-air-conditioners-need-regassing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do portable air conditioners need regassing? Do you need to put in any maintenance work? Your portable AC&amp;rsquo;s efficiency decreased any you suspect the refrigerant needs a refill?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Portable air conditioners never need regassing. Portable ACs are fully enclosed systems and refrigerant will never leak if the device is not broken. If it is broken, you should just replace it with a new one and not worry about maintenance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does a Portable Air Conditioner work?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-does-a-portable-air-conditioner-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 07:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-does-a-portable-air-conditioner-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How does a portable air conditioner work? Air conditioners work “magically” and nobody ever fully gets them. As an electrical engineer, I try to break up the answer to this question into digestible chunks everybody can understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Like a regular air conditioner, a portable air conditioner cools the air by evaporating a refrigerant that carries the absorbed heat from your room outdoors. Since a portable air conditioner has no outdoor parts which ensure that no heat is carried back into the room, it is not as efficient as a regular air conditioner.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to make a Portable Air Conditioner More Efficient?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-make-portable-air-conditioner-more-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 08:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-make-portable-air-conditioner-more-efficient/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to make a portable air conditioner more efficient? Portable air conditioners can turn into a money drain if you don’t use them properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is all about helping you to make sure that you are running your portable air conditioner at the highest efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this, you’ll know exactly what to do in order to increase the cooling power of your portable AC while maintaining low electricity usage and therefore lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to make a Portable Air Conditioner quiet?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-make-a-portable-air-conditioner-quiet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 10:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-make-a-portable-air-conditioner-quiet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to make a portable air conditioner quiet? What&amp;rsquo;s the best way to silence a noisy portable AC?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found lots of useless and ridiculous advice online, such as wrapping your portable AC in blankets. Not only do tips of this kind not work, but they are even dangerous.&lt;br&gt;
This article deals with the few tips that will really get you a silent portable air conditioner. Just follow along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You can only make a portable air conditioner quieter by placing it on an anti-vibration pad and lowering the power settings. Soundproofing an AC is likely to overheat it and decreases the cooling efficiency. If your portable air conditioner is old (10 years or more), I would suggest you replace it. Modern air conditioners are significantly quieter.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to keep a Portable Air Conditioner Hose from falling out</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/portable-air-conditioner-hose-falling-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 11:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/portable-air-conditioner-hose-falling-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your portable air conditioner hose keeps falling out? The connection of the exhaust hose and portable AC or between hose and window is not secure enough? How do you ensure your portable air conditioner hose stays in place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re having a look at a few simple things you can do to prevent your air conditioner hose from falling out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A portable AC hose can fall out at either one of its ends: Either directly at the portable AC connection, or it can slip out from the window.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use an Extension Cord with a Portable Air Conditioner?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-extension-cord-with-portable-air-conditioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 09:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-extension-cord-with-portable-air-conditioner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use an extension cord for a portable air conditioner? In this article, we’re going to explore the art of using extension cords with portable ACs and how to stay safe at all times!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extension cords are one of the weak points when using portable ACs. Generally, portable ACs are very safe. However, they need lots of power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when a weak extension cord has to handle too much power, it can melt or even catch fire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the Safest Space Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/what-is-the-safest-space-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 12:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/what-is-the-safest-space-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the safest space heater? Space heater fires are in the news regularly. And still, space heaters don’t decline in popularity. The opposite is the case: More and more people see the advantages of space heaters and choose to buy one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But with all the space heater accidents in the back of your mind, you wonder how much you can trust such a space heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will declare the safest space heater model available. This article will be updated whenever a better model becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which Space Heater Size do you need?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/which-space-heater-size-do-you-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 10:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/which-space-heater-size-do-you-need/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Which space heater size do you need? How many Watts do you need? Most guides online, when googling for this question, give you formulas to calculate the needed wattage based on the size of your room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that is an over-complication of the approach to solving the question and an oversimplification of the real world. A simple formula can’t consider all boundary conditions in your home: What’s the exact volume of your living space? How well insulated is your home? How moist is the air? What kind of furniture do you have? What’s the weather like outside? Are doors kept open or closed?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Wood Stove Fans worth it?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-wood-stove-fans-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 10:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-wood-stove-fans-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are wood stove fans worth it? And do they really work? In this article, we’re looking at wood stove fans, what they are, how they work, and whether you should get one. Also, we’re clearing up some common misconceptions. So let’s jump right in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Wood stove fans are worth it, but only for smaller rooms. They will help distribute the hot air a little but are more of a toy and nice to look at as a design item. If you seriously have to distribute heat in your home, you should use an electric floor fan. Floor fans are very powerful and are able to quickly move large amounts of air between and within rooms.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How long can you leave a Space Heater on?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-long-can-you-leave-space-heater-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 12:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-long-can-you-leave-space-heater-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How long can you leave a space heater on? Will space heaters eventually catch flames? Or will they break? In this article, we are going to explore these questions. After reading this, you’ll be confident and able to use your space heater responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;All quality space heaters theoretically are safe to run 24h a day. As long as you are in the same room, you can leave a space heater on. Modern space heaters have built-in safety features such as a temperature controlling thermostat, tip-over protection, and overheat protection, which reduce risk of fire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you put a Space Heater on Carpet?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-put-a-space-heater-on-carpet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-put-a-space-heater-on-carpet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you put a space heater on carpet? Or should you rather place them on the bare floor? And what if your floor is fully carpeted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many websites online suggest to never put a space heater on a carpet. A quick search already revealed quotes such as the following&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You should never sit a space heater on a carpet or area rug. The carpet will trap the heat, and the build-up of heat may cause a fire.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Heater not Blowing Hot Air (How to fix it)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-not-blowing-hot-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 10:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-not-blowing-hot-air/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your space heater is not blowing hot air and you don’t know how to fix it? In this article, we are going to go through potential causes. Don’t worry, it’s not going to be too technical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after reading this, you will know exactly how you can fix your issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;When a space heater blows cold air or no air at all, it is usually due to a hardware failure. Some part of the electronic circuitry is likely broken. If your space heater does not blow air at all, it is likely that either the fan is broken or it does not receive enough power. Usually, fixing a space heater yourself is not worth it and dangerous. Instead, just buy a new one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Dyson heaters noisy? (A critical review)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-heaters-noisy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 10:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-heaters-noisy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Dyson heaters noisy? With their popular air-multiplier technology, Dyson advertises their heaters to be strong. But how much noise does a Dyson Pure Hot + Cool generate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, Dyson heaters can get noisy. The Dyson Pure Hot + Cool models provide fan speed settings. The higher the setting, the louder it is. On the lowest setting, a Dyson heater fan is very quiet. However, the high fan speed setting is very loud.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Dyson Heaters safe? (A Critical Review)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-heaters-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 11:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-heaters-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Dyson heaters safe? Dyson heaters are among the best-looking heaters. Their design is widely recognizable. This does not only apply to Dyson space heaters, but also to Dyson vacuum cleaners and other products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how safe are Dyson heaters? Do they have any unique safety features that other space heaters do not provide? And how does Dyson compare to other heater brands safety-wise?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to explore the answers to these questions. As an electrical engineer, I am staying critical of any advertising claims made by Dyson. My goal is to provide you with a simple, yet realistic understanding of the real safety of Dyson space heaters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Pelonis Heaters energy efficient?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-pelonis-heaters-energy-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-pelonis-heaters-energy-efficient/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Pelonis heaters energy efficient? The answer to this question is very simple. Yes, Pelonis heaters are energy efficient. But let’s have a closer look at what that means and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, technically, Pelonis heaters are 100% energy efficient. The reason is that all the input power from your wall outlet is converted to heat. There is no difference in efficiency between different heater brands. It might only be the case that some heaters feel more efficient than others because they heat up quicker.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Pelonis heaters safe? (A critical review)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-pelonis-heaters-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 11:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-pelonis-heaters-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Pelonis heaters safe? Pelonis is a space heater brand that sells affordable heaters, such as ceramic tower heaters, oil-filled radiators, and electric heaters. Pelonis heaters come in all sizes and in various price points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some popular Pelonis heater models are significantly cheaper than their higher-end advertised counterparts from brands such as DeLonghi. Are these cheap Pelonis heaters safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we find out whether Pelonis heaters are as safe as other brands. Also we uncover the most common safety issues with Pelonis heaters. Yes, there are some. So, let’s have a look.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to assemble an Oil Heater (Picture manual)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-assemble-an-oil-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 15:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-assemble-an-oil-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to assemble an oil heater. Assembling an oil heater is actually very easy, once you understand how it’s done. Since there are only confusing resources online, I created this helpful picture guide with real-life pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just recently I received an oil-filled radiator myself. I did not even know that I have to assemble it myself. This presented itself as an opportunity for writing this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Assembling an oil heater is simple. First, attach the wheels to the brackets. Then use the bent metal connectors to attach the brackets (with wheels) to the bottom of the oil heater. Place the oil heater upright. Wait a minute for the oil to flow down. And then turn the oil heater on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Best Programmable Space Heaters</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-programmable-space-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 17:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-programmable-space-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re having a look at the 3 best programmable space heaters. I took a deep dive into programmable space heaters for you and found 3 different heaters that are a good bang for the buck. All 3 heaters differ a little bit, but I will explain everything to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s one thing all 3 best programmable space heaters have in common: They are oil-filled radiators. I chose to stick to oil-filled radiators because I am convinced that once you are looking for a programmable space heater, you want to be able to leave it running independently of you. You want to automate the heating times and the temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much does an Oil-filled Radiator weigh?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-much-does-an-oil-filled-radiator-weigh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 16:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-much-does-an-oil-filled-radiator-weigh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How much does an oil-filled radiator weigh? The weight of an oil heater becomes important when you are moving it frequently. Especially when you get one heater to heat multiple rooms, it is important, that the heater is easy to carry around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other side, when you have children or pets at home, having a heavy heater is an advantage. Heavy heaters stand their place and do not tip over as easily as lightweight space heaters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Oil Heaters need to be refilled?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-oil-heaters-need-to-be-refilled/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 09:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-oil-heaters-need-to-be-refilled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re just getting into oil-filled radiators, you might wonder if oil heaters need to be refilled? Does an electric oil radiator run out of oil? Luckily, this question is easy to answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;No, oil heaters do not need to be filled. An oil heater should never run out of oil. The metal heating body has no openings. Since it is a closed system, the oil cannot leak. At least as long as the heater is undamaged and in a good condition. However, yes a damaged heater can run out of oil. In this case, you should replace the heater. An oil heater that runs out of oil is not a reliable and safe source of heat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How long does a Wood Stove take to heat up?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-long-does-a-wood-stove-take-to-heat-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 14:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-long-does-a-wood-stove-take-to-heat-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How long does a wood stove take to heat up? To answer this question, I could measure just the heat-up time of my own wood stove for you and give you the numbers. However, that is not the best way to get accurate numbers. Your home is different than mine and therefore your numbers will vary. To find accurate numbers I have collected stove heat-up times from various people around the web and compiled them in this article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Heater keeps shutting off (5 reasons and how to fix it)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-keeps-shutting-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 10:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-keeps-shutting-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When a space heater keeps shutting off, you often don’t know what to do. However, troubleshooting the issue is not too hard. You can find out the reason for the repeated shutoffs even if you are an electronics layman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I am going to guide you through 5 different causes of your problem and I am going to present you a potential solution for every case. So, without wasting too much time, let’s get right into it and have a look.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are wood stove inserts worth it? (When does it pay off?)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-wood-stove-inserts-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 15:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-wood-stove-inserts-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wood stove inserts claim to increase the heating efficiency of your fireplace. But is it worth getting one? The initial cost of getting an insert confuses most people. Will the upfront costs ever be covered? In this article, we will look at the initial costs of a wood stove insert and the long-term savings. To do this, we will have to look at the efficiency of wood stove inserts. Also, we have to understand how much maintenance such an insert needs. I am going to do the research for you and let you know all my findings!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Dispose of a Space Heater</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-dispose-of-a-space-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 09:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-dispose-of-a-space-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to dispose of a space heater. That’s actually a good question and it pops up to lots of people when they want to get rid of their old space heater. Whether it’s broken, too old and unfashioned or you just want to free some space. In this article, we’re going to find out how to dispose of space heaters. For extra detail, I will divide this article into different subsections and explain how to dispose of each individual heater type.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Heat a Walk-in Closet (In 4 Simple Steps)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-a-walk-in-closet-in-4-simple-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 07:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-a-walk-in-closet-in-4-simple-steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s how to heat a walk-in closet. Does your walk-in closet get super cold as well? I totally understand how you feel. Oftentimes, it’s one of the first rooms you enter in the morning. With a walk-in closet that feels like a teleport to the north pole, you start your day uncomfortably every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this guide, we’re going to cover a few basic options to heat a walk-in closet. I will stick to simple solutions. You can implement most of them on your own, without the need for professionals. So, let’s start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do Convection Heaters Work?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-do-convection-heaters-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 07:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-do-convection-heaters-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do convection heaters work? In this article, we’ll take a look at that. After reading this short convection heater guide, you’ll understand how convection heaters work. In my explanations, I’ll stick to a very intuitive level. Let’s just avoid the detailed physics. We all had enough of it in school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the short answer: &lt;strong&gt;Convection heaters work using a heating coil that produces hot air. The hot air is then distributed by a fan or by a large metal surface. Convection heaters use the air as a medium to transport the heat. Either they heat up air and then blow it across the room to distribute it. Or they make use of the natural rising of warm air, which ensures that the heat distributes itself. Keep reading to find out more.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Many Candles do you need to Heat a Room?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-many-candles-do-you-need-to-heat-a-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 07:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-many-candles-do-you-need-to-heat-a-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How many candles do you need to heat up a room? When it’s freezing cold, you have to be prepared. So, that’s actually a good question. Whether you’re doing survival, you spend a few nights in your off-grid cabin, or whether your room heater just broke. Heating with candles is definitely a thing that comes to your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my radiator stopped working, the question about heating with candles popped into my head. When I started my research, I was SHOCKED. There are dozens, if not hundreds of tutorials online about building a candle heater at home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Heater vs Electric Blanket: 21 Pros and Cons</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-vs-electric-blanket-21-pros-and-cons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 10:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-vs-electric-blanket-21-pros-and-cons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Space heater vs electric blanket. Both are completely different products and yet they have something in common: They are meant to keep you warm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are not sure which one you should get, this article is for you. We’re going to compare space heaters and electric blankets and find out which one is the better choice for you. This is a very individual choice, so we’ll cover everything you need to know, to make the best decision. Heating with an electric blanket or with a space heater is very different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electricity Usage of Oil-Filled Heaters: The Ultimate Guide</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/electricity-usage-of-oil-filled-heaters-the-ultimate-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 20:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/electricity-usage-of-oil-filled-heaters-the-ultimate-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This guide is all about the electricity usage of oil heaters. You are probably about to get a new space heater and wondering whether getting an oil heater is the right choice for you. Oftentimes, you have several concerns when you’re about to get a brand new heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much electricity do oil heaters use?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it expensive to run an oil heater continuously?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are oil heaters more efficient than other types of space heaters?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can you reduce the electricity usage of your oil heater?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to tackle all these questions (and even more)! And don’t worry. You don’t need to be an electrician to be able to follow along. I’ve made this guide as easy and beginner-friendly as possible. All you have to do is to read through it and cherry-pick the information you need.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get Heat Upstairs: A Detailed Guide</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-get-heat-upstairs-a-detailed-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 12:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-get-heat-upstairs-a-detailed-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to get heat upstairs in an old house? This is often an issue when you rely on a wood stove. While one floor is perfectly heated, the upstairs floor remains ice-cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s the short version: To get heat upstairs, you have to improve ventilation and insulation in your home. If you feel like your home still doesn’t feel warm upstairs, you should add other heat sources. For example, you can use space heaters. They will make a significant difference. However, that’s just half of the story. Keep reading to learn more.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best Torpedo Heater: Powerful and Reliable</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/torpedo-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 18:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/torpedo-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to buying a torpedo heater, you should get a suitable model right away. Usually, when you try to get a cheap torpedo heater, you are disappointed by what you receive. Therefore, I recommend getting a known and popular product right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter what you use it for, whether it is for construction work, for keeping your garage warm, for a workshop… the right heater will support you at your work. A bad heater will only hinder you and produce unnecessary problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Propane Heater: My Top Pick</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/propane-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 18:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/propane-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Mr. Heater propane heater can produce heat equivalent to 3 average 1,500W space heaters and lasts up to 5 days on the lowest setting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either you pick cheap ones that will last for a few months until they break or you pick a good one right away that will last a lifetime. If you want to save money, you should be picking the one that lasts forever. Not only will it save you the stress to look for new propane heaters over and over, but you also feel much better, knowing you have a model that will reliably heat - even in emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best Oil-Filled Radiator: My favorite!</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/oil-filled-radiator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 18:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/oil-filled-radiator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been recommending one oil-filled radiator model over and over on this website. I am just convinced that this one is by far the best value-for-money deal you can currently get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now hold on: I want you to pick the right oil heater right away. My buying philosophy is to look for items where you get your money’s worth. I want you to minimize the long term cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carless buying of heaters could lead to bad choices and buying the wrong products that don’t last long or don’t fulfill your needs. So, you would need to look out for heaters over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Infrared Heater for your Home: My Top Pick</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/best-infrared-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 18:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/best-infrared-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What’s the best infrared heater? I tried, tested and researched several infrared heaters and came to a conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is to pick a model where you get the most out of your money. I don’t want you to waste time and energy on buying heaters that will last you only a few months or can’t deliver the heat you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s the short version: The best infrared heater in terms of quality, price, and reliability is by far the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Dr-Infrared-Heater-Portable-1500-Watt/dp/B002QZ11J6/ref=as_li_ss_tl?crid=1Z796YYBSCYXT&amp;amp;keywords=dr+infrared+heater&amp;amp;qid=1578427646&amp;amp;sprefix=dr+infrare,aps,278&amp;amp;sr=8-4&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=heatertips-20&amp;amp;linkId=e84d6163b83a30dbc5a70e5a5f4b38e0&amp;amp;language=en_US&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Infrared Heater Dr-968 (click to view it on amazon)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;. Among all infrared heaters, it is my favorite, because, in contrast to other models, it is able to keep the temperature of big rooms high, even when it’s the only heat source in your home in mid-winter. The Dr Infrared Heater is incredibly good to have for emergencies and whenever you need a reliable heat source. It comes with all the safety features you need and has a built-in thermostat (which is unusual for infrared heaters).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recommended Products</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 18:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am writing honest cost-effective heating and cooling articles for this website for many years now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With time, I noticed a few products, which I always come back to and that I always recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommended-products&#34;&gt;Recommended Products&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electric space heaters:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/best-infrared-heater&#34;&gt;Best Infrared Heater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/oil-filled-radiator/&#34;&gt;Best Oil-filled Radiator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gas-based space heaters:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/propane-heater/&#34;&gt;Best Propane Heater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/recommended-products/torpedo-heater/&#34;&gt;Best Torpedo Heater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Air Conditioners:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/most-powerful-portable-air-conditioners/&#34;&gt;Best Portable Air Conditioners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These are the best heating and cooling products you can get. No fancy marketing, no ads. Just what really works.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Heat a Garage Gym: The 21 Best Ways</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-a-garage-gym-the-21-best-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 17:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-a-garage-gym-the-21-best-ways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s freezing cold again and you want to workout. What’s the best way to heat your garage gym?&lt;br&gt;
Working out in an ice-cold garage is not the healthiest thing to do, aside from the lack of motivation you have. That’s why you need to set your garage gym workout up properly to be able to heat it in the cold seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In this article, you are going to learn 21 different ways to stay warm and heat your garage gym. From keeping yourself warm to proper insulation and buying the right heaters: You will learn everything you need to know.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infrared vs Oil Heater: 21 Pros and Cons</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/infrared-vs-oil-heater-21-pros-and-cons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 13:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/infrared-vs-oil-heater-21-pros-and-cons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are clear differences between an infrared vs oil heater. But they are actually very simple to understand. In this article, I’m going to show you 21 pros and cons of using an infrared vs oil heater, so you know which one suits you best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The difference between infrared heaters and oil heaters is that infrared heaters are designed for quick, directional heat and better efficiency, whereas oil heaters are meant to replace your home heating unit by heating whole rooms evenly and with more strength.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Cheapest Ways to Heat a Room &amp; House</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/the-21-cheapest-ways-to-heat-a-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 13:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/the-21-cheapest-ways-to-heat-a-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What are the cheapest ways to heat your room or even your entire house? In this article, we&amp;rsquo;re going to look at exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Daniel, an electrical engineer from Germany, and here&amp;rsquo;s a list of all the cheapest practical ways to heat your home!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the methods listed teach you cheap ways to heat single rooms. Also, you&amp;rsquo;ll find cheap ways to heat your entire house. Some of the heating-methods listed don&amp;rsquo;t even need central heating or electricity!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Space Heaters Under $50: A Complete Guide to the Cheapest Ones ﻿</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-space-heaters-under-50-a-complete-guide-to-the-cheapest-ones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 12:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-space-heaters-under-50-a-complete-guide-to-the-cheapest-ones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s cover the best space heaters under $50!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone who’s new to space heaters knows this feeling. You want to finally get a new heater and you want to get it NOW! But there’s one thing holding you back: Your budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is just for you. We’re going to cover absolutely everything you need to know about cheap space heaters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I own a cheap heater well below $50 and it’s running reliably for months now. I’ll answer your questions:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much does a Space Heater Cost to Run? (21 Heaters Tested)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-electricity-cost-a-look-at-the-costs-of-21-different-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 11:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-electricity-cost-a-look-at-the-costs-of-21-different-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How much does a space heater cost to run? Here&amp;rsquo;s everything you need to know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we&amp;rsquo;re comparing the electricity cost of 21 different space heaters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll help you decide whether you can afford to run a space heater. And also, I am giving you a simple formula to calculate the exact electricity cost of your space heater model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;A space heater costs $54 per month to run if you use it for 8 hours every day. I assumed an average 1500W space heater and the average US electricity rate of 15 cents per Kilowatt-hour for the calculation. If you run your space heater on lower settings or for shorter durations, the cost to run your space heater decreases accordingly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Keep Heat in a Room Without a Door: 21 Helpful Tips</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-keep-heat-in-a-room-without-a-door-21-helpful-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 11:03:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-keep-heat-in-a-room-without-a-door-21-helpful-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to keep heat in a room without a door? That’s one of the few questions humanity fails to answer. While we know everything about applied thermodynamics and heating options, we get a chill when we spend time in a room without a door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cold air comes in from the open door and you don’t know what to do about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you don’t need to worry! You will stop freezing today!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Heater makes Clicking Noise: 2 Common Reasons for the Popping</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-makes-clicking-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heater-makes-clicking-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your space heater makes a clicking noise and you’re not sure where it’s coming from and whether your heater is broken?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had this myself: I was comfortably sitting on my couch, with my infrared heater keeping my feet warm. It was really comfortable and I totally concentrated on the book. All of a sudden, there was a loud clicking noise. It was a quick clicking sound, just like the sound you often hear right after turning on an oven or an air conditioner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Space Heaters that don’t Dry the Air</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heaters-that-dont-dry-the-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 08:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heaters-that-dont-dry-the-air/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are 3 space heaters that don’t dry the air!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you heat your room with a space heater, the air gets dryer and dryer. Sometimes even so much that it makes you uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The level of humidity in your room can make a big difference for your wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Too dry air will make your skin feel dried out and your throat can get sore. Too humid air will make you feel sweaty at home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heating a Wedding Tent - The Ultimate Guide</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/heating-a-wedding-tent-the-ultimate-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 09:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/heating-a-wedding-tent-the-ultimate-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Heating a wedding tent is one of the things you should never forget while planning your wedding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having shivering guests is one of the worst things that can happen to you. Being cold keeps the mood down and your guests might even remember your event as an ice-disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once, I’ve had a party that was simply too cold. I just didn’t plan the weather in and thought, the party tent would keep the cold out. That was not the case:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Space Heaters with Long Cords (Ranked &amp; Reviewed)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/5-space-heaters-with-long-cords-ranked-reviewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 12:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/5-space-heaters-with-long-cords-ranked-reviewed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are there any space heaters with long cords? I just had to answer this question, when I noticed that my space heater cord isn’t long enough to place my heater anywhere I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To find the space heater with the longest cords, I’ve researched for hours, browsing through product descriptions and manuals to find the lengths of the cords of dozens of space heaters.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it was pretty difficult to get the values. It seems like companies try to hide the cord length on purpose. But why?&lt;br&gt;
What I found was surprising. Keep reading to find out!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Heaters that don&#39;t Blow Fuses: Our 5 Top Picks</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heaters-that-dont-blow-fuses-our-5-top-picks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 18:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heaters-that-dont-blow-fuses-our-5-top-picks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Space heaters that don’t blow fuses: Is that even possible? Of course, it is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to take a look at 5 space heaters that definitely don’t blow any fuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m an electrical engineer and carefully selected each of them and their potential to blow a fuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 5 space heaters listed below are perfectly safe because they either &lt;strong&gt;need less power than other space heaters or they have variable power settings and various safety features.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Best Oil Heaters You Can Leave on All Night</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/3-best-oil-heaters-you-can-leave-on-all-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 08:06:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/3-best-oil-heaters-you-can-leave-on-all-night/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oil heaters are exactly the type of heater you need to leave on all night and heat your basement safely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, nights are freezing cold and you absolutely need to stay warm at night in order to get a good night of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For heating a bedroom, oil-heaters are really practical: Compared to other space heaters, they are very safe. And they are energy efficient and won’t raise your electric bill too high.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Heat a Boat Cabin (Without Electricity)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-a-boat-cabin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 09:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-to-heat-a-boat-cabin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to heat a boat cabin and what’s the best heater to use in a boat cabin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That question first got me thinking when I was on a boat trip on the Rhine river in Germany in the springtime and all the passengers shivered throughout the tour: There was no heater on the boat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why is heating a boat cabin important? By heating a boat, you not only feel more comfortable, but you also benefit some technical aspects of the boat: Heat protects the water and sewage system and the engine compartment from freezing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Effective Ways to Heat a Garage without Insulation</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/5-ways-to-heat-a-garage-without-insulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 10:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/5-ways-to-heat-a-garage-without-insulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How can you heat a garage without insulation? What’s the best way to do it? Is it possible to heat effectively? And if yes, how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, garages can get uncomfortably cold in the wintertime. Especially when your garage is without insulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Entering a cold garage is and having no option to heat it effectively is like jumping into cold water - it’s just uncomfortable and everyone hates it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially if you have a garage woodworking shop (or similar), it adds a lot of enjoyment if you can heat your space whenever you like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Safety Tips for using a Space Heater in a Bathroom ﻿</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/5-safety-tips-for-using-a-space-heater-in-a-bathroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 09:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/5-safety-tips-for-using-a-space-heater-in-a-bathroom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use a space heater in a bathroom? If yes, what do you have to consider for safety? And which kind of space heater is best for bathrooms? In this article, we’re going to cover all of these questions and a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-you-use-a-space-heater-in-a-bathroom&#34;&gt;Can you use a space heater in a bathroom?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can use a space heater in a bathroom as long as you do it responsibly. Even though there’s water vapor in the air, most space heaters are still able to run just fine. You can minimize the risk of an accident by sticking to the space-heater-bathroom safety tips below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Space Heaters you can leave unattended (Reliable &amp; Safe)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heaters-you-can-leave-unattended/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 10:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heaters-you-can-leave-unattended/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are there any space heaters you can leave unattended? And if yes, how can you find the safest ones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry, I’ve done the work for you and found the safest space heaters you can get! These space heaters are the best choices for long heating periods and for leaving them unattended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are suited, for example, if you’re cooking something in the kitchen but you want to pre-heat your living room for a cozy movie night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Space Heaters allowed in Dorms?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-space-heaters-allowed-in-dorms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 07:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-space-heaters-allowed-in-dorms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it allowed to use space heaters in college dorms? Currently, I’m sitting in my dorm, with cold feet. My radiator (for some reason) decided not to heat this evening. Even though I can layer clothes and socks to keep warm, using a space heater would help so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are space heaters even allowed in dorms?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not sure whether your college allows space heaters in dorms, you’re in the right place. &lt;strong&gt;In this article, we’re going to cover everything you need to know about space heater rules in college dorms.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Space Heaters Safe for Cats?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-space-heaters-safe-for-cats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 16:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-space-heaters-safe-for-cats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Space heaters and cats - is that a safe combination? You know exactly how cats behave: They think they are the queens of your house, like to tip over stuff and do whatever they want. Partly that’s because cats are genetically programmed this way. They like to own your place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, should you get a space heater if you have a cat at home? And if yes, which kinds of space heaters are safe for cats? And which safety aspects are important? In this article, we’re going to cover all of these questions so you can stop worrying!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run a Space Heater off a Car Battery?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-a-space-heater-off-a-car-battery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 10:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-a-space-heater-off-a-car-battery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To run a space heater off a car battery makes sense in two cases: When you camp in a freezing cold car, or during an energy outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to cover everything you need to know about whether you can power a space heater off a car battery when there’s no other energy source around!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an emergency survival situation, you’ll try everything you can to stay warm. So, is it a practical solution to connect a space heater to your car battery? I’m an electrical engineer, and I’ll show you how it would work!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you Plug a Space Heater into a Timer?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-plug-a-space-heater-into-a-timer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 20:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-plug-a-space-heater-into-a-timer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you plug a space heater into a timer? This is a question many people ask because you could save so much energy by automatically switching off a space heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dial outlet timers are simple to employ - just plug them into an outlet, then plug your device into them and set the timer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cecilia Harsch - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hunker.com/13425604/how-to-set-the-timer-on-intermatic-malibu-landscape-lighting&#34;&gt;Hunker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could, for example, heat your bedroom while you sleep and automatically switch off the space heater at 1 am in order to save some money on your electric bill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you get a Tan from a Space Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-get-a-tan-from-a-space-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 10:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-get-a-tan-from-a-space-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you get a tan from a space heater? I mean, that would be incredibly practical and would save you so much money on tanning products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I love the sun but don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to get a good tan and keep it year-round, so I am a huge fan of tanning products.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim Kardashian&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re like the Kardashians and prefer to get your tan at home rather than outdoors, here’s the right place. In this article, we’ll find out whether you can use a space heater to tan your skin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will a Space Heater Dehumidify a Room?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/will-a-space-heater-dehumidify-a-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 08:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/will-a-space-heater-dehumidify-a-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Will a space heater dehumidify a room? Can it dry the air? If your room is damp and you want to know whether you can get rid of the moisture by using a space heater, this is the right place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll cover everything you need to know to understand exactly how space heaters affect the humidity in your room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this, you’ll know how to dehumidify your room, and, if you want, how to humidify your room with a space heater as well (you can actually do both if you know how).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run a Space Heater off a Generator?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-a-space-heater-off-a-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 08:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-a-space-heater-off-a-generator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You want to run a space heater off a generator? Here’s everything you need to know about powering space heaters with generators and what you need to consider to stay safe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we’ll cover whether it makes sense to use generators to power space heaters and I’ll show you some handy alternatives (that might work even better for your purposes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first, let’s take a look at the generators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Question: Can you run a space heater off a generator?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Space Heaters are Safe for Birds?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/what-space-heaters-are-safe-for-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 13:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/what-space-heaters-are-safe-for-birds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What space heaters are safe for birds? This article contains everything you need to know to choose the right space heater for your bird as well as safety tips to make sure your bird stays happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this, you’ll know exactly which kind of space heater you should get for your bird and I’ve even included an easy-to-follow guide that shows you exactly what to do with a new heater to bird-safe it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infrared vs. Radiant Heaters: Are they the same?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/infrared-vs-radiant-heaters-are-they-the-same/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 11:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/infrared-vs-radiant-heaters-are-they-the-same/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are infrared heaters and radiant heaters the same or is there a difference? If there’s a difference: Which one is better? This is actually a topic that confuses lots of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I am an electrical engineer I was sitting in front of my screen thinking: “Is there even a difference between infrared and radiant heat”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to uncover the truth that baffles even engineers. After reading this you’ll have a solid knowledge of what radiant and infrared heaters are and why they are called like this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/cookie-privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 17:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/cookie-privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the Cookie Policy for heatertips, accessible from heatertips.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Are Cookies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is common practice with almost all professional websites this site uses cookies, which are tiny files that are downloaded to your computer, to improve your experience. This page describes what information they gather, how we use it and why we sometimes need to store these cookies. We will also share how you can prevent these cookies from being stored however this may downgrade or ‘break’ certain elements of the sites functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legal Details</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/legal-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 17:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/legal-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Information in accordance with Section 5 TMG&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Hirsch&lt;br&gt;
Kiefernweg 17&lt;br&gt;
36110 Schlitz&lt;br&gt;
Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact-information&#34;&gt;Contact Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E-Mail: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daniel@heatertips.com&#34;&gt;daniel@heatertips.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Internet address: &lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com&#34;&gt;heatertips.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;accountability-for-content&#34;&gt;Accountability for content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contents of our pages have been created with the utmost care. However, we cannot guarantee the contents’ accuracy, completeness or topicality. According to statutory provisions, we are furthermore responsible for our own content on these web pages. In this matter, please note that we are not obliged to monitor the transmitted or saved information of third parties, or investigate circumstances pointing to illegal activity. Our obligations to remove or block the use of information under generally applicable laws remain unaffected by this as per §§ 8 to 10 of the Telemedia Act (TMG).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 11:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Effective date: November 18, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;heatertips(“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.heatertips.com&#34;&gt;www.heatertips.com&lt;/a&gt; website (the “Service”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data. Our Privacy Policy for heatertips is managed through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freeprivacypolicy.com/free-privacy-policy-generator.php&#34;&gt;Free Privacy Policy Website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, accessible from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.heatertips.com&#34;&gt;www.heatertips.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
