<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Air-Conditioning on HeaterTips</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/category/air-conditioning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Air-Conditioning on HeaterTips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 08:09:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/category/air-conditioning/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dyson F2 Error Code: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fix-dyson-f2-error-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 08:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fix-dyson-f2-error-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The F2 error code on Dyson fans is simple to fix once you know what causes it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, Dyson doesn’t seem to know what causes the error. I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the reason for your Dyson fan showing the F2 error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptom:&lt;/strong&gt; Dyson fan senses a power drop, displays F2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cause:&lt;/strong&gt; Friction in the fan motor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; Disassemble and clean the fan, ensure the fan motor is snapped into position, tighten any screws&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The F2 error is comparably rare because it is related to internal friction inside the device. This usually happens when a Dyson fan is not carefully assembled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When to Replace Your Air Conditioner: 3 Rules Of Thumb</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/when-to-replace-air-conditioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 08:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/when-to-replace-air-conditioner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is it time to replace my air conditioner?&amp;rdquo; This is a question that plagues many homeowners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air conditioners, unlike some other household items, don&amp;rsquo;t just stop working overnight. Instead, they degrade slowly, leaving you in a grey area about when exactly to invest in a new unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help the decision-making, rules like &amp;lsquo;replace it after 10 years&amp;rsquo; exist. But are they genuine?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found that most rules on the internet are constructed by the HVAC industry to sell you a new air conditioner way too early.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Vornado Fans Worth It? (Vortex Power or Marketing Hoax?)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/are-vornado-fans-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 09:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/are-vornado-fans-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Vornado fans worth it? In this article, we’re going to check how well Vornado fans &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; perform and whether they are worth the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am Daniel! I am an electrical engineer and I investigate electric devices &lt;em&gt;in-depth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t care about the Vornado brand and I am not affiliated with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, everything you read in this review is 100% independent information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, Vornado fans are worth it. They blow a focused stream of air, optimized for cooling people. Their build quality is superior to most other fans. A Vornado fan can easily last you 10-20 years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Tower Fans better than Pedestal Fans? (Answer: NO)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/are-tower-fans-better-than-pedestal-fans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 10:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/are-tower-fans-better-than-pedestal-fans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are tower fans better than pedestal fans? Just recently, I noticed tower fans are trending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what are the differences between tower fans and pedestal fans? Are they better in any way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what makes them so popular?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to take a dive into understanding tower fans and their purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, what’s the gap a tower fan fills that makes people want to buy them?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Fan not Cooling (5 Fixes)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dyson-fan-not-cooling-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 09:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dyson-fan-not-cooling-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Dyson fan not cooling (anymore) can be very frustrating. After all, Dyson fans are not cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to have a quick look at the 5 most common issues with a Dyson fan not cooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;A Dyson fan is usually not cooling because of blocked airways (air filter, air inlet holes). Also, check the set target temperature, and ensure your Dyson cooling fan does not run in backward airflow mode.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Swamp Cooler: My Top Pick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-swamp-cooler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 15:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-swamp-cooler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve seen me talk a lot about the Hessaire MC37M. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s on the list of top swamp coolers for garages or in our swamp cooler vs air conditioner comparison, the MC37M stands out. But why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The best swamp cooler is the Hessaire MC37M. It is robust, has more than enough power to cool even large spaces, and lasts a lifetime. For smaller rooms, you can get the MC18M model.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Swamp Coolers need open windows?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/do-swamp-coolers-need-open-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 09:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/do-swamp-coolers-need-open-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered if you need to leave your windows open for your swamp cooler to work effectively? The answer is no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;No, swamp coolers do not need open windows to operate effectively. For optimal performance and energy efficiency, it&amp;rsquo;s better to keep windows closed and control the indoor humidity through regular venting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, your cooler performs best with your windows closed and occasional venting. This contrasts with several misconceptions about swamp coolers: that the increased humidity must be constantly vented out, that longer running times lead to higher humidity, and that open windows help airflow. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll bust these myths and give you a clear guide to using your swamp cooler more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does putting ice in a Swamp Cooler make sense?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/does-ice-in-a-swamp-cooler-make-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 14:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/does-ice-in-a-swamp-cooler-make-sense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Does putting ice in a swamp cooler make sense? Hardly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It definitely skyrockets your swamp cooler running costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Putting ice in a swamp cooler doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense. The addition of ice doesn&amp;rsquo;t significantly enhance cooling, it increases energy consumption and cost, and ice melts rapidly in the cooler&amp;rsquo;s environment. Moreover, the design of many swamp coolers prevents the inclusion of ice in the tank.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-a-swamp-cooler-work-does-it-need-ice&#34;&gt;How does a swamp cooler work? Does it need ice?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A swamp cooler cools down air by evaporating water. Water evaporation sucks heat energy away from the air.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run a Swamp Cooler without water?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-a-swamp-cooler-without-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 08:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-a-swamp-cooler-without-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you need to refill a swamp cooler or can you run it without water? In this article, we’re checking how a swamp cooler uses water to cool and what happens once it runs dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to popular belief you can run a swamp cooler without water! And in extreme situations, you can even refill a swamp cooler without access to water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s find out how!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can run a swamp cooler without water. Once the water runs out, it becomes a simple fan. So, you still have a (reduced) cooling effect. In an emergency, where you don’t have access to water, you can collect morning dew by placing the water pads outdoors overnight. The humidity is enough to cool you in the afternoon heat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Cooler vs Air Conditioner (Cost comparison)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swamp-cooler-vs-air-conditioner-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swamp-cooler-vs-air-conditioner-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Swamp cooler vs air conditioner. What’s the better choice for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I am comparing swamp coolers and air conditioners&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus here is to provide you with an objective comparison. For every comparison, I am providing numbers and indisputable facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading through all the sections, you will know whether a swamp cooler or an air conditioner suits you better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Swamp coolers are way cheaper to run and do not require any installation. Air conditioners, however, work anywhere and anytime. Swamp coolers work best in dry and hot climates.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix Swamp Cooler Smell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-swamp-cooler-smell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 18:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-swamp-cooler-smell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to fix swamp cooler smell. Swamp coolers are the ultimate breeding ground for bacteria and bad odors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the dust that comes in from the outside collects on the air filters and the wet water pads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few days in the summer heat, the smell is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swamp coolers stink naturally. Especially, when they’re used a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let’s have a look at how you can get rid of the smell by cleaning your swamp cooler.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where do Swamp Coolers work? (US States List)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/where-do-swamp-coolers-work-us-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 10:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/where-do-swamp-coolers-work-us-states/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether a swamp cooler works depends on the climate in your area. In this article, we’re having a quick glance at all US states and whether swamp coolers work there or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Swamp coolers work in&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;every US state during the afternoon, because that is the driest time of the day. Using a swamp cooler all day and throughout the year only makes sense in Arizona, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, New Mexico, Utah, and Wyoming.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can a Swamp Cooler run all day?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-a-swamp-cooler-run-all-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 15:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-a-swamp-cooler-run-all-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run a swamp cooler all day? How humid will your living space be? And is there a risk of the electronics blowing up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can run a swamp cooler all day. Swamp coolers do not add humidity to your room indefinitely, because they run at room temperature (and don’t boil the water like a kettle). Also, they run on very little electric power, so they don’t overheat. To maximize running time, lubricate the fan every year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can a Swamp Cooler catch on fire?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-a-swamp-cooler-catch-on-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 08:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-a-swamp-cooler-catch-on-fire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can a swamp cooler catch on fire? What happens when they run out of water?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;A swamp cooler will not catch fire, even when the water runs out. Swamp coolers run on low wattages, which makes overheating highly unlikely. Swap coolers are the safest cooling devices (together with fans).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-swamp-coolers-overheat-when-they-run-out-of-water&#34;&gt;Do swamp coolers overheat when they run out of water?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A swamp cooler is a fan that blows air through wet sponge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Best Swamp Coolers for Bedrooms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-swamp-coolers-for-bedrooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 13:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-swamp-coolers-for-bedrooms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; few swamp coolers that are actually good. In this article, we’re looking at the 3 best swamp coolers to use in a bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The best bedroom swamp coolers are the Hessaire MC37M and MC18M models. Their water tanks last for a full night if you run them on half-power. Alternatively, you can connect them to a tap for continuous refills.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After checking my 3 different recommendations, we will also have a look at whether it makes sense to run a swamp cooler in your bedroom and see if there are better alternatives for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Best Swamp Coolers for Garages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-swamp-coolers-for-garages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 11:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-swamp-coolers-for-garages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Garages get very hot in the summer. Let’s have a look at the best swamp coolers specifically for garages!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I looked for garage swamp coolers online, I was actually a bit surprised by the lack of information about garage swamp coolers. I mean, when you look for garage swamp coolers, you want a sturdy, durable, and maintainable device, that will last you for many summers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You usually don’t care about looks. You don’t want plastic screws. You want a swamp cooler that can take a hit, and which you can easily move around the garage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaporative Cooler not turning on (7 Fixes)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/evaporative-cooler-not-turning-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 12:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/evaporative-cooler-not-turning-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your evaporative cooler is not turning on? In this article, you’re getting a complete list of things you should inspect before you declare your evaporative cooler dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re going to check the most common issues and their fixes. And along the way, you’re going to learn a bunch about the inner workings of your cooler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;An evaporative cooler won’t turn on if it does not receive electric power. This could be due to a broken wall outlet, power cord, or blown fuse. But broken parts such as blown electronics, water damage, or an empty water tank can also stop your evaporative cooler from turning on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Cooler not Blowing Cold Air (8 Fixes)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swamp-cooler-not-blowing-cold-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 11:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swamp-cooler-not-blowing-cold-air/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your swamp cooler is not blowing cold air? In this article, I guide you through fixing your swamp cooler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do that, we’re going to check the different possible reasons why your swamp cooler is not blowing cold air. For each cause, I list a way to test for this cause and one or more methods to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;A swamp cooler is not blowing cold air when the fan does not blow air or when the water pads are not soaked. Possible causes include a broken fan, clogged air filters, a broken water pump, or clogged water lines. Usually, cleaning the clogged parts, replacing air filters, and checking the connection points of the water lines solves the issue.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Cooler making Noise (7 Fixes)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swamp-cooler-making-noise-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 12:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swamp-cooler-making-noise-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your swamp cooler is making noise? In this article, we’re going to cover the most common noise types, including humming, screeching, buzzing, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each noise, you’re going to learn where it comes from and how you can fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Swamp coolers often make humming, gurgling and crackling noises. These are expected. You can reduce these normal noises with anti-vibration pads. Screeching, buzzing, scratching and banging noises are signs of unlubricated parts, loose parts, or faulty electronics. You can fix these noises with silicone lubricant, by tightening the parts in place, or by replacing the noisy parts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Window AC making Noise (9 Fixes)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/window-ac-making-noise-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 10:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/window-ac-making-noise-fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your window AC is making noise? In this article, we’ll cover all the different noise types in window ACs. For each noise, we check whether it is dangerous, the cause for the noise, and, of course, how to fix it (if necessary).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Window AC noises are usually&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not dangerous.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;But scratching, whistling or banging noises indicate larger failures in your window AC which you have to address. The most common cause for window AC noises is broken parts in the compressor or fan, such as broken bearings or broken brackets which allow the fan or compressor to jump around in your window AC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Fan not Rotating (7 Fixes)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dyson-fan-not-rotating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 18:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dyson-fan-not-rotating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating to find out that your Dyson fan is no longer rotating. Obviously, how would you circulate the air in your room without this feature?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Dyson fan may have stopped oscillating for several reasons. And usually, the issue is relatively easy to fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I will share with you the most common reasons why your Dyson fan isn&amp;rsquo;t oscillating, along with troubleshooting and fixing instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Dyson heaters usually don’t rotate if there’s still tape on your Dyson fan&amp;rsquo;s base body split section. Additionally, if the fan doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit right in its base and dust accumulates in the oscillation system (oscillation motor), the system won&amp;rsquo;t work and thus won&amp;rsquo;t oscillate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to insulate a Window AC (for Efficiency)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-insulate-a-window-ac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 10:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-insulate-a-window-ac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How can you insulate a window air conditioner? Usually, the window kit that comes with a window AC does not fit perfectly and leaves room for heat to enter your room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let’s have a look at some improvements you can make to improve your window AC’s insulation (and, therefore, its &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/how-to-make-a-window-ac-more-efficient/&#34;&gt;cost-efficiency&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You can add insulation around a window AC by gluing styrofoam panels around the sides. To close all air gaps, use spray foam or foam tape. If available, close your outdoor shutters to reduce the amount of heat entering your room.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to make a Window AC more efficient (9 Methods)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-make-a-window-ac-more-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 21:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-make-a-window-ac-more-efficient/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Window ACs are power-hungry! Even though they are one of the most-efficient AC types, their running cost adds up over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain 3 essential things you should do to make your window AC more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer: &lt;strong&gt;You can make your window AC more efficient by insulating windows and gaps below your door. Also, clean the evaporator coil and air filter. To avoid efficiency-decreasing dirt accumulation, clean your window AC’s internals yearly. Additionally, use high-quality extension cords (instead of cheap ones) and run your AC on a moderate cooling setting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix a Window Air Conditioner not Cooling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-window-air-conditioner-not-cooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 13:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-window-air-conditioner-not-cooling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your window air conditioner is not cooling? In this article, I am listing all of the possible reasons!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll tell you &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; how to test each cause and how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list is sorted by issue frequency. So, the most common reasons are listed first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;To fix a window air conditioner not cooling, ensure that all airways are free. Clean the evaporator coil. Ensure that the power supply is OK and that there is no issue with the power cord. Also, properly insulate the window setup of your window AC. If nothing helps, get a new window AC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run two Portable ACs at once?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-two-portable-air-conditioners-at-once/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 17:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-you-run-two-portable-air-conditioners-at-once/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Running two portable air conditioners simultaneously on the same circuit is not a good practice, as it will increase energy consumption or may trip your circuit breaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still, if you want to run two portable ACs simultaneously, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you whether you can do it or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you an alternative to portable ACs that will consume less energy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer: &lt;strong&gt;You can run two portable air conditioners at the same time on the same circuit if they do not draw current more than the ampere rating of the circuit (15A - 20A). A 15A circuit and 110V - 120V outlet voltage (US) will not support two portable air conditioners. On the other hand, you can easily run two portable air conditioners when the outlet voltage is 220V - 230V (Europe and UK) and the circuit ampere rating is 15A - 20A.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Quietest Portable Air Conditioners (47dB - 52dB)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/quietest-portable-air-conditioners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 14:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/quietest-portable-air-conditioners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the 5 quietest portable air conditioners between 47dB and 52dB. You’ll find all cooling capacities between 8,000 BTU and 14,000 BTU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each quiet portable air conditioner, I’ll also list the room size each model is good for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The quietest portable air conditioner is a 47dB TOSOT unit. After that, most quiet air conditioners are rated either 51dB or 52dB. An average portable air conditioner is 56dB, which is&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;more because each 3dB increase doubles the perceived noise volume.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is a Single-Hose or Dual-Hose AC Better?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/is-a-single-or-dual-hose-portable-ac-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 14:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/is-a-single-or-dual-hose-portable-ac-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many people are confused about which type of portable air conditioner to buy. If you are also questioning whether to buy a single-hose or dual-hose AC, here&amp;rsquo;s your answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dual-hose portable air conditioners are more efficient than single-hose as they don&amp;rsquo;t suck any outdoor air into the room due to negative pressure. A dual-hose unit is perfect for larger spaces because it can cool an area more quickly and efficiently than a single-hose AC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Best Air Conditioners for Small Rooms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-air-conditioners-for-small-rooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 10:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-air-conditioners-for-small-rooms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Air conditioners for small rooms should not take up much space, effectively cool your room, and don’t consume much electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check the best air conditioners for small rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The best air conditioner for small rooms is a 5,000 BTU window air conditioner. Getting a larger air conditioner and cooling your entire living space (instead of just one small room) is even more cost-effective because small rooms can’t keep the cold air for long and heat up quickly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Air Conditioners Wear Out? (High vs Low Maintenance)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/do-air-conditioners-wear-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 12:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/do-air-conditioners-wear-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Air conditioners wear out over time. However, you can do something about it. In this article, you’re going to learn how long air conditioners last, and how you can extend the lifespan of your air conditioner!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, air conditioners wear out. You can expect an air conditioner to last 20+ years if you maintain it once a year. If you skipped your maintenance, you can revive your air conditioner by changing air filters, cleaning the evaporator coil, and fully dusting the internals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Cheapest Ways to Cool a Garage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cheapest-ways-to-cool-a-garage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 15:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cheapest-ways-to-cool-a-garage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have a garage, you know it can be hot and sweaty. Not only is it uncomfortable to be inside a hot garage during the summer, but a cool garage helps you stay cool-headed when you&amp;rsquo;re doing car repairs or other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The cheapest way to cool a garage is a floor or ceiling fan. Insulation additionally prevents the heat from entering your garage on hot summer days. Installing air conditioning is rather expensive but very effective for cooling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Remove Smell in a Portable AC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-remove-smell-in-portable-ac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 12:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-remove-smell-in-portable-ac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to remove smell in a portable AC?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The only way to remove smell from a portable AC is to open it up and clean the components. You may have to identify where the smell is emanating from and what&amp;rsquo;s causing it, but it&amp;rsquo;s safer to clean and deodorize the entire appliance regularly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remove the smell from your portable AC, just follow the steps below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-remove-portable-ac-smell&#34;&gt;How to remove portable AC smell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying the cause of the smell is sometimes a try-and-error method. You must check each component and clean or change what is necessary until the smell is gone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use a Portable AC when it’s Smoky outside?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-you-use-portable-ac-when-smoky-outside/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 08:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-you-use-portable-ac-when-smoky-outside/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can only use &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; portable ACs when it’s smoky outside, whether that’s because of wildfires or due to an industrial area nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check which air conditioners are OK to be used and which aren’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You should not use a single-hose portable AC when it’s smoky outside. However, you can always use dual-hose portable ACs, window ACs and split ACs, as these don’t suck in outdoor air.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which Air Conditioner Type is Best for a Garage? (1,2,3,4 cars)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/which-air-conditione-type-is-best-for-garage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 09:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/which-air-conditione-type-is-best-for-garage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mini-split ACs are the best air conditioner type for garages. In this article, we’re checking three different air conditioner types: portable, window, and split ACs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a garage, you should not shortcut your air conditioning. Here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Mini-split ACs are the best type of air conditioner for garages. They provide enough cooling power, don’t consume any floor space, and don’t need any windows for installation. A good mini-split unit will last you for decades if you take care of it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Vent a Portable AC Without a Window?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-vent-portable-ac-without-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 16:44:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-vent-portable-ac-without-window/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using a window to vent your &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/most-powerful-portable-air-conditioners/&#34;&gt;portable air conditioner&lt;/a&gt; is the simplest method, but not every room in your home has access to a window. Although it could be demanding and difficult, employing an alternative to vent your air conditioner is not impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick answer: You can vent a portable air conditioner without a window by using different alternatives such as; through the door, wall, drop ceiling, chimney, or even the dryer vent. It is possible that not every alternative may apply to you since they have different requirements, but you can always check which one would work well for you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Best Portable Air Conditioners for Garages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-portable-air-conditioners-for-garage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 10:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-portable-air-conditioners-for-garage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What are the best portable air conditioners for garages? Where should you set up the portable AC in your garage? Especially, when you don’t have a window, you’ll need some installation work. And how can you maximize the efficiency of your garage AC? This article will clarify all of these questions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The best portable air conditioner for garages is the Whynter ARC-14S. Because it’s a dual-hose AC, it’s very efficient when cooling hot garages. However, you will need a window fitting two hoses or you will need to drill two holes in your garage wall for installation. If that’s too much, get the recommended Black+Decker single-hose portable AC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix a Portable AC not turning on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-portable-ac-not-turning-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 11:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-portable-ac-not-turning-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your portable AC won’t turn on? Here’s how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;To fix a portable AC not turning on, check fuses and circuit breakers. Ensure the wall outlet is powered. Check clogged air filters and the drain pan. Check for internal ice buildup and verify that compressor and ducts are sealed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry! For each of those causes, I’ll tell you exactly how to check it and which steps to take to fix it. Let’s go one by one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Most Powerful Portable Air Conditioners</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/most-powerful-portable-air-conditioners/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/most-powerful-portable-air-conditioners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most powerful portable air conditioners are 14,000 BTU. One Honeywell portable AC even has 15,000 BTU of cooling power. However, it’s almost always out of stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too bad, Honeywell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;The most powerful portable air conditioner is a 15,000 BTU AC by Honeywell. However, this model is always out of stock. Instead, the 14,000 BTU dual-hose Whynter ARC-14S provides the most powerful and efficient cooling. If that is not enough for you, you should get a 25,000 BTU window air conditioner instead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s the Difference between a Window vs Split AC?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/whats-the-difference-between-window-ac-and-split-ac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 11:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/whats-the-difference-between-window-ac-and-split-ac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Window ACs and Split ACs differ in their internal structure. But the difference is not only technical. It also affects the efficiency, cost, noise, and installation cost of the different AC types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Window ACs are window-mounted, low-cost, but noisy. Split ACs are wall-mounted, rather expensive, but more powerful and quiet. Both window and split ACs have a similar cooling efficiency. Technically they are equally capable of cooling large rooms.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Portable Air Conditioners Run 24/7?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-portable-air-conditioners-run-continuously/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 15:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-portable-air-conditioners-run-continuously/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating to repeatedly turn your &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/how-does-a-portable-air-conditioner-work/&#34;&gt;portable air conditioners&lt;/a&gt; on and off, and you might want to keep them on forever. The question now is whether it is even safe to run them 24/7. Here&amp;rsquo;s the answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Answer: Yes, portable air conditioners can run 24/7. While it may not have a negative impact on the AC itself, it will result in an increase of your electricity bill by around $151.20 a month. If you really need to run your portable AC that much, you should rather get a wall-mounted AC unit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Dyson Cooling Fans Worth It?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/are-dyson-cooling-fans-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 14:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/are-dyson-cooling-fans-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Dyson cooling fans worth it? Dyson is known for their high-quality, technologically advanced cooling fans, among other household items. But are they really worth that hefty price?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;No, Dyson cooling fans are not worth it and overpriced. For venting a room, a regular floor or pedestal fan will perform just as well. However, Dyson cooling fans can be worth it in some situations for their directional, strong airflow and their design.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why does your Portable Air Conditioner Collect no Water?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portable-air-conditioner-collects-no-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 14:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portable-air-conditioner-collects-no-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why does your portable air conditioner collect no water? In this article, we’re checking 5 possible reasons and how to fix them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Your portable air conditioner collects no water because it is either broken or the water tank leaks. Low air humidity is also a potential cause. Another cause is that your portable AC is an evaporative cooler, which does not collect water.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s have a look at each of those reasons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Portable Air Conditioners Safe?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/are-portable-air-conditioners-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/are-portable-air-conditioners-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Portable air conditioners can be a great way to keep your home cool and comfortable during the hot summer months. But before you buy one, it&amp;rsquo;s important to ensure it is safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, portable air conditioners are safe. As long as you maintain them properly and run them on moderate settings, there are no health hazards. They are also safe for children and pets since there are no exposed hot parts and no sharp edges.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can You Use a Window Air Conditioner without a Window?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/use-window-air-conditioner-without-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 11:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/use-window-air-conditioner-without-window/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use a window air conditioner without a window? In this article, you will learn 3 methods to set up your window AC when you only have a room without regular windows at hand, through a regular or a sliding door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Window units are designed specifically to be mounted on a window. The warm air and water produced during the cooling process escape to the outdoors through the window. But if you don’t have a suitable window in that room, you can improvise another way to remove those by-products without a window.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix a Portable Air Conditioner not Cooling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-portable-air-conditioner-not-cooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 08:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-fix-portable-air-conditioner-not-cooling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to fix a portable air conditioner not cooling? In this article, we’re checking the 6 most common causes, how to test your portable AC for them, and how to repair each of the causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Place your portable AC in a room that suits its size. Insulate the hose and window kit using aluminum wrap and HVAC tape. Clean clogged air filters and the evaporator coil. Then, drain the water tank. Finally, make sure your portable air conditioner is set to cooling mode.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run a Portable AC off a Generator?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/run-portable-air-conditioner-off-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 14:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/run-portable-air-conditioner-off-generator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run a portable AC off a generator? This article is all about the size of generator you need to power a portable air conditioner. And, of course, how to do it safely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You can run most portable air conditioners on 2500W AC generators. For portable air conditioners with over 14,000 BTU cooling capacity, you need over 3000W generators. Make sure the generator is located outside to prevent carbon monoxide exposure indoors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Cheapest Ways to Cool a Room &amp; House</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cool-room-house-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 10:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cool-room-house-cheap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about the cheapest ways to cool your room, your house, and yourself. In this article, we’re going to cover a ton of different home-cooling methods, packed with advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will find something suitable for your situation. Whether you need to cool your room &lt;strong&gt;without an AC, without electricity, or without windows&lt;/strong&gt;. Everything is in here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also included a few feel-cold methods that do not need any devices, which you can use anytime, anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Remove Mold in a Portable Air Conditioner</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/remove-mold-portable-air-conditioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 10:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/remove-mold-portable-air-conditioner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to remove mold in a portable air conditioner? AC units provide the perfect conditions for mold to grow-oxygen, moisture and matter. And since they push air around your house, it means a moldy air conditioner will be blowing microscopic mold spores into the air you breathe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you suspect there could be mold in your portable AC, either because of seeing or smelling it, this article will help you solve that problem once and for all. But here’s the summary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are DeLonghi Portable Air Conditioners Good?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/delonghi-portable-air-conditioner-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 08:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/delonghi-portable-air-conditioner-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are DeLonghi portable air conditioners good &amp;amp; worth it? DeLonghi is widely known as a reputable brand that produces great electronics. Let’s have a look at whether you should spend the money or not!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, DeLonghi portable ACs are good, but they are more expensive than most other brands. The main advantages are that they are quiet, have more advanced features and some do not give off greenhouse gas emissions. However, for most people, there are many lower-priced air conditioners that will do the same job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Portable Air Conditioners give off Carbon Monoxide?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portable-air-conditioner-carbon-monoxide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 10:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portable-air-conditioner-carbon-monoxide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do portable air conditioners give off carbon monoxide? There are two reasons why many homeowners ask this question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer &lt;strong&gt;: No, portable air conditioners do not give off carbon monoxide. Carbon monoxide is only created from fuel-burning devices such as furnaces, gas stoves, and generators. Portable ACs use electricity so there is no risk of them emitting carbon monoxide.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are a few uncommon situations whereby your portable AC could be involved in circulating carbon monoxide in your home. Read on to learn the real culprits you should be worrying about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portable Air Conditioner Running Cost (Ultimate Guide)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portable-air-conditioner-running-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 13:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portable-air-conditioner-running-cost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s everything you need to know about portable air conditioner running cost. No fluff, just the facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Daniel, I am an electrical engineer, and in this article, I am telling you all about the average running cost of portable air conditioners in different locations, for different models. You’ll find a formula to calculate the exact running cost of the portable AC you want to buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you stick around to the end of the article, I am telling you exactly what to do to reduce your portable air conditioner’s electricity usage!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Portable Air Conditioners need to be Vented?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/do-portable-air-conditioners-need-to-be-vented/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 14:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/do-portable-air-conditioners-need-to-be-vented/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do all portable air conditioners need to be vented? If so, why do all air conditioners need a hose? And can you use a portable AC without a hose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, all portable air conditioners need to be vented. The heat extracted from the air has to leave your room, otherwise, it will mix up with the cold air again. Ventless ACs are a marketing scam and never work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do you have to put Water in a Portable Air Conditioner?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/put-water-in-portable-air-conditioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 08:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/put-water-in-portable-air-conditioner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you have to put water in a portable air conditioner? The answer to this question uncovers a huge marketing scam, so keep reading until the end. You’ll be shocked. But before that, here’s the quick answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You don’t have to put water in a portable air conditioner. Portable air conditioners extract heat from the air and vent it out the window. The cooling process condensates water which accumulates in the air conditioner. Rather, you have to drain water from your portable AC. Any air conditioner where you put in water or ice cubes is a junk product!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Portable Air Conditioners need Regassing?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/do-portable-air-conditioners-need-regassing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/do-portable-air-conditioners-need-regassing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do portable air conditioners need regassing? Do you need to put in any maintenance work? Your portable AC&amp;rsquo;s efficiency decreased any you suspect the refrigerant needs a refill?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Portable air conditioners never need regassing. Portable ACs are fully enclosed systems and refrigerant will never leak if the device is not broken. If it is broken, you should just replace it with a new one and not worry about maintenance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does a Portable Air Conditioner work?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-does-a-portable-air-conditioner-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 07:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-does-a-portable-air-conditioner-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How does a portable air conditioner work? Air conditioners work “magically” and nobody ever fully gets them. As an electrical engineer, I try to break up the answer to this question into digestible chunks everybody can understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Like a regular air conditioner, a portable air conditioner cools the air by evaporating a refrigerant that carries the absorbed heat from your room outdoors. Since a portable air conditioner has no outdoor parts which ensure that no heat is carried back into the room, it is not as efficient as a regular air conditioner.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to make a Portable Air Conditioner More Efficient?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-make-portable-air-conditioner-more-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 08:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-make-portable-air-conditioner-more-efficient/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to make a portable air conditioner more efficient? Portable air conditioners can turn into a money drain if you don’t use them properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is all about helping you to make sure that you are running your portable air conditioner at the highest efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this, you’ll know exactly what to do in order to increase the cooling power of your portable AC while maintaining low electricity usage and therefore lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to make a Portable Air Conditioner quiet?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-make-a-portable-air-conditioner-quiet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 10:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-make-a-portable-air-conditioner-quiet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to make a portable air conditioner quiet? What&amp;rsquo;s the best way to silence a noisy portable AC?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found lots of useless and ridiculous advice online, such as wrapping your portable AC in blankets. Not only do tips of this kind not work, but they are even dangerous.&lt;br&gt;
This article deals with the few tips that will really get you a silent portable air conditioner. Just follow along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You can only make a portable air conditioner quieter by placing it on an anti-vibration pad and lowering the power settings. Soundproofing an AC is likely to overheat it and decreases the cooling efficiency. If your portable air conditioner is old (10 years or more), I would suggest you replace it. Modern air conditioners are significantly quieter.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to keep a Portable Air Conditioner Hose from falling out</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portable-air-conditioner-hose-falling-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 11:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portable-air-conditioner-hose-falling-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your portable air conditioner hose keeps falling out? The connection of the exhaust hose and portable AC or between hose and window is not secure enough? How do you ensure your portable air conditioner hose stays in place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re having a look at a few simple things you can do to prevent your air conditioner hose from falling out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A portable AC hose can fall out at either one of its ends: Either directly at the portable AC connection, or it can slip out from the window.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use an Extension Cord with a Portable Air Conditioner?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/can-you-use-extension-cord-with-portable-air-conditioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 09:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/can-you-use-extension-cord-with-portable-air-conditioner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use an extension cord for a portable air conditioner? In this article, we’re going to explore the art of using extension cords with portable ACs and how to stay safe at all times!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extension cords are one of the weak points when using portable ACs. Generally, portable ACs are very safe. However, they need lots of power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when a weak extension cord has to handle too much power, it can melt or even catch fire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
