<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Safety on HeaterTips</title>
    <link>https://heatertips.com/category/safety/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Safety on HeaterTips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.146.7</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:55:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://heatertips.com/category/safety/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>4 Best Child-Safe Heaters</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/best-child-safe-heaters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/best-child-safe-heaters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some space heaters are made specifically for families with children. However, most of these “child-safe space heaters” are actually regular space heaters that are designed to &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; child-safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But inherently, there’s nothing that makes them safer than space heaters for adults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really dislike the marketing scheme here. Just designing a dangerous device to &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; safe doesn’t make it safe. Especially not for children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll have a look at space heaters that are very safe for children, regardless of whether they are designed to look like baby / child products, or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Space Heaters explode?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-space-heaters-explode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 12:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-space-heaters-explode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can space heaters explode? Space heaters can catch a fire if you use them incorrectly. But will they explode?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s important because an explosion could stun you and limit your ability to take action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am Daniel, an electrical engineer, and in this article, we’re going to check whether space heaters can explode and the fascinating engineering behind explosion-proof space heaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, space heaters don’t explode. In fact, it’s impossible for a space heater to explode. Let’s have a look.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Space Heaters Burn Oxygen?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-space-heaters-burn-oxygen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 08:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-space-heaters-burn-oxygen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do space heaters burn oxygen? The cold season is approaching and there are plenty of space heater myths and misconceptions that make you stop and hesitate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If space heaters really burn oxygen, maybe you should find another way to heat. Should you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s stop the speculation and get right to the core of the matter. Here’s the answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electric space heaters never burn oxygen, since the source of the heat is not a chemical reaction. Only fuel-burning heaters such as propane heaters or kerosene heaters do burn oxygen. However, due to tiny oxygen inflow streams from outdoors through gaps and creeks, and the built-in oxygen depletion sensor many fuel-burning heaters are absolutely safe to use indoors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Air Purifiers Safe for Pets? (Dogs, Cats, Birds, etc.)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-air-purifiers-safe-for-pets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 08:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-air-purifiers-safe-for-pets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are air purifiers safe for pets? 4 months ago, my girlfriend got a puppy. Naturally, I have to take care of her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as an HVAC blogger, I have all kinds of devices at home, including an air purifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how did things turn out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did the dog survive the air purifier? (&amp;hellip; joking)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I am going to guide you through using air purifiers with pets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this, you’ll know exactly:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use an Extension Cord with an Air Purifier?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-an-extension-cord-with-an-air-purifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 09:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-an-extension-cord-with-an-air-purifier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use an extension cord for an air purifier? In this article, we’re going to explore the art of using extension cords with air purifiers and how to stay safe at all times!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extension cords can pose a risk when not used appropriately. While air purifiers generally consume much less power than similar devices (such as portable air conditioners), safety precautions are still essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most extension cords can handle the little power an air purifier draws. But a very bad quality extension cord that can&amp;rsquo;t handle the required power can pose a risk of melting or even catching fire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run a Swamp Cooler without water?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-a-swamp-cooler-without-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 08:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-a-swamp-cooler-without-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you need to refill a swamp cooler or can you run it without water? In this article, we’re checking how a swamp cooler uses water to cool and what happens once it runs dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to popular belief you can run a swamp cooler without water! And in extreme situations, you can even refill a swamp cooler without access to water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s find out how!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can run a swamp cooler without water. Once the water runs out, it becomes a simple fan. So, you still have a (reduced) cooling effect. In an emergency, where you don’t have access to water, you can collect morning dew by placing the water pads outdoors overnight. The humidity is enough to cool you in the afternoon heat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the safest Propane Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/whats-the-safest-propane-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 10:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/whats-the-safest-propane-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the safest propane heater? When it comes to propane heater safety, &lt;em&gt;everybody&lt;/em&gt; is claiming different things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I am going to uncover propane heater safety myths and tell you only the facts that &lt;em&gt;everybody&lt;/em&gt; agrees on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an experiment, I bought a propane heater, and actually tried to burn things. And I measured propane heater temperatures using a laser thermometer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the measurements, you can tell what is and what isn’t a safe propane heater.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Mr. Heaters safe in a tent? (Fact checked)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-mr-heaters-safe-in-a-tent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 09:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-mr-heaters-safe-in-a-tent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Mr. Heaters safe to use in a tent? Many use Mr. Heater Buddys (and other models) as their primary outdoor heat source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are great in cabins, RVs, and in workshops. But can you use a Mr. Heater in your tent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will check whether Mr. Heaters can ignite or melt tent walls and whether they emit carbon monoxide. And of course, we will check whether it’s possible to run a Mr. Heater for a full night in a tent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use a Gas Stove as a Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-gas-stove-as-a-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 11:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-gas-stove-as-a-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use a gas stove as a heater? Especially in emergencies, when there is no electricity and even central heating turns off, you need a backup heat source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a gas stove at home, then using it could be an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; you need to know about emergency heating using your gas stove. And you’re going to learn about better (and more cost-efficient) alternatives to gas stoves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you put a Space Heater on a table?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-put-a-space-heater-on-a-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 09:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-put-a-space-heater-on-a-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you put a space heater on a table? When I googled this phrase initially, I found answers diverging all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People answered “yes” and “no” everywhere without actually proving their point somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to place my three space heaters (oil-filled radiator, infrared heater, and propane heater) on top of a living room table and see if anything happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I am going to prove that you can place your space heater on tables as well using simple physics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Ventless Heaters cause Carbon Monoxide Poisoning?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-ventless-heaters-cause-carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 11:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-ventless-heaters-cause-carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you get CO poisoning from a ventless heater?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can &lt;em&gt;theoretically&lt;/em&gt; get carbon monoxide poisoning from a ventless heater. However, it is very unlikely as long as you vent your room every few hours. Ventless space heaters are among the most common source of carbon monoxide poisoning in homes. Modern ventless heaters are designed not to produce CO when functioning properly, but many factors, including poor ventilation and dirt, can make the heater less than safe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Propane Heaters safe indoors?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-propane-heaters-safe-indoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 10:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-propane-heaters-safe-indoors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are propane heaters safe for indoor use? In this article, we’re going to answer this question by checking the temperature a propane heater produces. Then we can conclude, whether propane heaters cause a fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we will follow up with a look at the combustion of propane gas and whether it creates any toxic waste materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After checking all of these “scary” aspects of propane heaters, you’re going to learn how to use a propane heater safely. And I am going to recommend you my favorite indoor-safe propane heater!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use a Surge Protector with a Space Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-surge-protector-with-a-space-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 15:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-surge-protector-with-a-space-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Surge protectors are the best safety devices to handle voltage spikes and power surges and keep your devices safe. But can you use a surge protector with your space heater?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we can&amp;rsquo;t answer this with a yes or no, because there are certain things you need to consider before using a surge protector with a space heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you if you should use a surge protector with your heater. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m going to do some calculations that will make it easy for you to choose the suitable surge protector for your space heater.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Infrared Heaters safe indoors?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-infrared-heaters-safe-indoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 11:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-infrared-heaters-safe-indoors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are infrared heaters safe to use indoors? Can they be a fire hazard? In this article, I am going to tell you exactly how hot infrared heaters get, which materials they can ignite and whether they can start a fire on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I will tell you how to safely run an infrared heater. And we will check whether you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need an infrared heater (because there is a safer space heater type).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How long can you run a Dyson Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-long-can-you-run-a-dyson-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 10:29:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-long-can-you-run-a-dyson-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How long can a Dyson heater run without interruption? Is it safe to run a Dyson heater overnight?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to inspect &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; we need to find out how long a Dyson heater can truly safely operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re going to check&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the design of a Dyson heater and where the heat accumulates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how hot Dyson heaters get&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how much power Dyson heaters draw and whether that can overload circuits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whether Dyson heaters can melt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the end, we’re going to conclude with what you can do to prepare your Dyson for long heating sessions!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run an Infrared Heater overnight?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-an-infrared-heater-overnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 08:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-an-infrared-heater-overnight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run an infrared heater all night? In this article, we’re going to measure the temperature of my infrared heater’s heating elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we can check whether this temperature is night-safe (i.e. will it burn or melt anything?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I am going to recommend you a night-safe infrared heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can run a quality infrared heater overnight given it is made of fireproof material and has built-in overheat protection. The radius of up to 2 feet in front of a space heater has to be free of any objects, as within this radius high temperatures up to 750°F can occur. Place your infrared heater at a safe distance from your bed without any objects blocking the heat radiation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Candles cause Carbon Monoxide Poisoning?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-candles-cause-carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 20:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-candles-cause-carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, candles can cause carbon monoxide poisoning, but it’s highly unlikely. Candles produce very little carbon monoxide. That’s not enough to cause poisoning unless you light many candles in a small, unventilated space, which would increase carbon monoxide emissions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that doesn’t mean lighting candles is 100% safe. Since carbon monoxide is undetectable by all five senses, it can be difficult to establish when the CO from candles is nearing dangerous levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use an Oil-filled Radiator in an RV?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-an-oil-filled-radiator-in-an-rv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 10:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-an-oil-filled-radiator-in-an-rv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use an oil-filled radiator in an RV? Sure! But you have to make sure you use a proper power source!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can use an oil-filled radiator in an RV. You can run any oil-filled radiator off shore power, off a generator, or off the batteries using an inverter. However, electric heating is not always the most cost-effective form of heating when you are off-grid.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check all you need to know about oil-filled radiators. And in the end, we’ll see whether there are better heating options for your RV!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use an Oil-filled Radiator in a Bathroom?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-an-oil-filled-radiator-in-a-bathroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 16:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-an-oil-filled-radiator-in-a-bathroom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use an oil-filled radiator in a bathroom? Or will it take damage from the humidity, or even be a safety threat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check whether and how to use oil-filled radiators in bathrooms, along with the necessary safety precautions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can use an oil-filled radiator in a bathroom. The large metal heating body is completely safe, even when water is splashed on it. Only the front panel of an oil-filled radiator contains sensitive electronics. So, avoid exposing it to water. An electric shock from an oil-filled radiator by accident is almost impossible unless you really try. Also, oil-filled radiators need no ventilation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you burn Coal in a Wood Stove?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-burn-coal-in-a-wood-stove/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 13:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-burn-coal-in-a-wood-stove/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coal has been used to heat homes and workplaces for centuries, but is it possible to burn coal in a wood stove?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;It is not recommended to burn coal in a wood stove. While it is possible, it is not efficient and can cause damage to your stove. A coal stove needs a grate at the bottom in order to allow air from below the fire to burn efficiently. Without this grate, wood stoves won&amp;rsquo;t be able to burn coal properly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can You Run a Wood Stove Pipe through a Window?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-wood-stove-pipe-through-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 11:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-wood-stove-pipe-through-window/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you run a wood stove pipe through a window?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wood stove pipe connects the chimney to the stove, and it&amp;rsquo;s meant to exhaust fumes out of your home. But what if your house or RV doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a chimney?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can run a wood stove pipe through a window by using a pre-made window plate kit or making one yourself using double-walled metal pipes and a metal sheet to cover the window space. Ensure the pipe is angled upwards and lifted above the roof to increase efficiency.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run two Portable ACs at once?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-two-portable-air-conditioners-at-once/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 17:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-two-portable-air-conditioners-at-once/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Running two portable air conditioners simultaneously on the same circuit is not a good practice, as it will increase energy consumption or may trip your circuit breaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still, if you want to run two portable ACs simultaneously, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you whether you can do it or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you an alternative to portable ACs that will consume less energy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer: &lt;strong&gt;You can run two portable air conditioners at the same time on the same circuit if they do not draw current more than the ampere rating of the circuit (15A - 20A). A 15A circuit and 110V - 120V outlet voltage (US) will not support two portable air conditioners. On the other hand, you can easily run two portable air conditioners when the outlet voltage is 220V - 230V (Europe and UK) and the circuit ampere rating is 15A - 20A.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use a Space Heater for a Sauna?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-space-heater-for-a-sauna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 14:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-space-heater-for-a-sauna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use a space heater as a heat source for your sauna? Yes! In this article, I am going to tell you exactly what you have to do and what you should consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can use space heaters to heat a sauna. However, you either have to use two electric space heaters without built-in thermostats simultaneously or one propane gas heater for heating. Adding insulation to your sauna helps increase to raise the possible maximum temperature.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use a Portable AC when it’s Smoky outside?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-portable-ac-when-smoky-outside/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 08:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-portable-ac-when-smoky-outside/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can only use &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; portable ACs when it’s smoky outside, whether that’s because of wildfires or due to an industrial area nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to check which air conditioners are OK to be used and which aren’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;You should not use a single-hose portable AC when it’s smoky outside. However, you can always use dual-hose portable ACs, window ACs and split ACs, as these don’t suck in outdoor air.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can You Use a Propane Heater in an RV?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-propane-heater-in-an-rv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 09:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-a-propane-heater-in-an-rv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A portable propane heater can be a source of fast, efficient heat during chilly nights and winter months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But can you use a portable propane heater in an RV? Is it safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can use a propane heater in an RV. However, the heater must be fully functional (ideally new) and its oxygen intake must be well-adjusted. Also, always ensure the propane heater stands firmly. If necessary, build an anti-tip-over construction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you Run Two Space Heaters at once? (Experiment Confirmed)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-two-space-heaters-at-once/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 12:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-two-space-heaters-at-once/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can run two space heaters at once almost anywhere in the world except in the US. Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to find this out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;On regular US 120V wall outlets you can run two space heaters at once on reduced heating settings only (80% or less). On 220V-240V (eg. UK, Europe) power outlets you can run two space heaters on full power since more voltage means less amperage which means less tripping of circuit breakers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Space Heaters Emit Carbon Monoxide?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/do-space-heaters-emit-carbon-monoxide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 10:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/do-space-heaters-emit-carbon-monoxide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Electric space heaters don’t emit carbon monoxide. But gas- and fuel-burning heaters can emit carbon monoxide!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;Electric space heaters never emit carbon monoxide. However, fuel or gas-burning heaters can produce carbon monoxide if broken or improperly adjusted. You can avoid indoor carbon monoxide buildup by using the right space heaters and regularly venting your room.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we&amp;rsquo;re shedding light on what type of space heaters can emit carbon monoxide, and how you can carbon monoxide-proof your home. Also, you’re going to learn about the most important gas-protection measures when running a fuel-burning space heater indoors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Portable Air Conditioners Run 24/7?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-portable-air-conditioners-run-continuously/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 15:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-portable-air-conditioners-run-continuously/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating to repeatedly turn your &lt;a href=&#34;https://heatertips.com/how-does-a-portable-air-conditioner-work/&#34;&gt;portable air conditioners&lt;/a&gt; on and off, and you might want to keep them on forever. The question now is whether it is even safe to run them 24/7. Here&amp;rsquo;s the answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Answer: Yes, portable air conditioners can run 24/7. While it may not have a negative impact on the AC itself, it will result in an increase of your electricity bill by around $151.20 a month. If you really need to run your portable AC that much, you should rather get a wall-mounted AC unit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Portable Air Conditioners Safe?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-portable-air-conditioners-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-portable-air-conditioners-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Portable air conditioners can be a great way to keep your home cool and comfortable during the hot summer months. But before you buy one, it&amp;rsquo;s important to ensure it is safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, portable air conditioners are safe. As long as you maintain them properly and run them on moderate settings, there are no health hazards. They are also safe for children and pets since there are no exposed hot parts and no sharp edges.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Portable Air Conditioners give off Carbon Monoxide?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/portable-air-conditioner-carbon-monoxide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 10:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/portable-air-conditioner-carbon-monoxide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do portable air conditioners give off carbon monoxide? There are two reasons why many homeowners ask this question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer &lt;strong&gt;: No, portable air conditioners do not give off carbon monoxide. Carbon monoxide is only created from fuel-burning devices such as furnaces, gas stoves, and generators. Portable ACs use electricity so there is no risk of them emitting carbon monoxide.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are a few uncommon situations whereby your portable AC could be involved in circulating carbon monoxide in your home. Read on to learn the real culprits you should be worrying about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you use an Extension Cord with a Portable Air Conditioner?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-extension-cord-with-portable-air-conditioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 09:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-use-extension-cord-with-portable-air-conditioner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use an extension cord for a portable air conditioner? In this article, we’re going to explore the art of using extension cords with portable ACs and how to stay safe at all times!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extension cords are one of the weak points when using portable ACs. Generally, portable ACs are very safe. However, they need lots of power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when a weak extension cord has to handle too much power, it can melt or even catch fire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the Safest Space Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/what-is-the-safest-space-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 12:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/what-is-the-safest-space-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the safest space heater? Space heater fires are in the news regularly. And still, space heaters don’t decline in popularity. The opposite is the case: More and more people see the advantages of space heaters and choose to buy one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But with all the space heater accidents in the back of your mind, you wonder how much you can trust such a space heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will declare the safest space heater model available. This article will be updated whenever a better model becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How long can you leave a Space Heater on?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/how-long-can-you-leave-space-heater-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 12:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/how-long-can-you-leave-space-heater-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How long can you leave a space heater on? Will space heaters eventually catch flames? Or will they break? In this article, we are going to explore these questions. After reading this, you’ll be confident and able to use your space heater responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick answer: &lt;strong&gt;All quality space heaters theoretically are safe to run 24h a day. As long as you are in the same room, you can leave a space heater on. Modern space heaters have built-in safety features such as a temperature controlling thermostat, tip-over protection, and overheat protection, which reduce risk of fire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you put a Space Heater on Carpet?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-put-a-space-heater-on-carpet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-put-a-space-heater-on-carpet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you put a space heater on carpet? Or should you rather place them on the bare floor? And what if your floor is fully carpeted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many websites online suggest to never put a space heater on a carpet. A quick search already revealed quotes such as the following&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You should never sit a space heater on a carpet or area rug. The carpet will trap the heat, and the build-up of heat may cause a fire.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Dyson Heaters safe? (A Critical Review)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-heaters-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 11:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-dyson-heaters-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Dyson heaters safe? Dyson heaters are among the best-looking heaters. Their design is widely recognizable. This does not only apply to Dyson space heaters, but also to Dyson vacuum cleaners and other products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how safe are Dyson heaters? Do they have any unique safety features that other space heaters do not provide? And how does Dyson compare to other heater brands safety-wise?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to explore the answers to these questions. As an electrical engineer, I am staying critical of any advertising claims made by Dyson. My goal is to provide you with a simple, yet realistic understanding of the real safety of Dyson space heaters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Pelonis heaters safe? (A critical review)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-pelonis-heaters-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 11:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-pelonis-heaters-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Pelonis heaters safe? Pelonis is a space heater brand that sells affordable heaters, such as ceramic tower heaters, oil-filled radiators, and electric heaters. Pelonis heaters come in all sizes and in various price points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some popular Pelonis heater models are significantly cheaper than their higher-end advertised counterparts from brands such as DeLonghi. Are these cheap Pelonis heaters safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we find out whether Pelonis heaters are as safe as other brands. Also we uncover the most common safety issues with Pelonis heaters. Yes, there are some. So, let’s have a look.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Safety Tips for using a Space Heater in a Bathroom ﻿</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/5-safety-tips-for-using-a-space-heater-in-a-bathroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 09:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/5-safety-tips-for-using-a-space-heater-in-a-bathroom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you use a space heater in a bathroom? If yes, what do you have to consider for safety? And which kind of space heater is best for bathrooms? In this article, we’re going to cover all of these questions and a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-you-use-a-space-heater-in-a-bathroom&#34;&gt;Can you use a space heater in a bathroom?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can use a space heater in a bathroom as long as you do it responsibly. Even though there’s water vapor in the air, most space heaters are still able to run just fine. You can minimize the risk of an accident by sticking to the space-heater-bathroom safety tips below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Space Heaters you can leave unattended (Reliable &amp; Safe)</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/space-heaters-you-can-leave-unattended/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 10:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/space-heaters-you-can-leave-unattended/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are there any space heaters you can leave unattended? And if yes, how can you find the safest ones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry, I’ve done the work for you and found the safest space heaters you can get! These space heaters are the best choices for long heating periods and for leaving them unattended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are suited, for example, if you’re cooking something in the kitchen but you want to pre-heat your living room for a cozy movie night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Space Heaters Safe for Cats?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/are-space-heaters-safe-for-cats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 16:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/are-space-heaters-safe-for-cats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Space heaters and cats - is that a safe combination? You know exactly how cats behave: They think they are the queens of your house, like to tip over stuff and do whatever they want. Partly that’s because cats are genetically programmed this way. They like to own your place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, should you get a space heater if you have a cat at home? And if yes, which kinds of space heaters are safe for cats? And which safety aspects are important? In this article, we’re going to cover all of these questions so you can stop worrying!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you run a Space Heater off a Car Battery?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-a-space-heater-off-a-car-battery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 10:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-run-a-space-heater-off-a-car-battery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To run a space heater off a car battery makes sense in two cases: When you camp in a freezing cold car, or during an energy outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to cover everything you need to know about whether you can power a space heater off a car battery when there’s no other energy source around!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an emergency survival situation, you’ll try everything you can to stay warm. So, is it a practical solution to connect a space heater to your car battery? I’m an electrical engineer, and I’ll show you how it would work!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you Plug a Space Heater into a Timer?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-you-plug-a-space-heater-into-a-timer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 20:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-you-plug-a-space-heater-into-a-timer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you plug a space heater into a timer? This is a question many people ask because you could save so much energy by automatically switching off a space heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dial outlet timers are simple to employ - just plug them into an outlet, then plug your device into them and set the timer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cecilia Harsch - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hunker.com/13425604/how-to-set-the-timer-on-intermatic-malibu-landscape-lighting&#34;&gt;Hunker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could, for example, heat your bedroom while you sleep and automatically switch off the space heater at 1 am in order to save some money on your electric bill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Space Heaters are Safe for Birds?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/what-space-heaters-are-safe-for-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 13:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/what-space-heaters-are-safe-for-birds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What space heaters are safe for birds? This article contains everything you need to know to choose the right space heater for your bird as well as safety tips to make sure your bird stays happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this, you’ll know exactly which kind of space heater you should get for your bird and I’ve even included an easy-to-follow guide that shows you exactly what to do with a new heater to bird-safe it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can I use an Extension Cord with a Space Heater?</title>
      <link>https://heatertips.com/can-i-use-an-extension-cord-with-a-space-heater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 08:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://heatertips.com/can-i-use-an-extension-cord-with-a-space-heater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🆕 Updated April 17, 2025&lt;/strong&gt; - All recommended extension cords and power strips are up-to-date and safe for use with space heaters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’re going to cover exactly whether you can use an extension cord with your space heater and what you have to be cautious of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Question: Can I use an extension cord with a space heater?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer: &lt;strong&gt;Usually, you should not use an extension cord with your space heater. Most extension cords can not handle the high currents space heaters draw. Especially small, low-quality extension cords can easily catch fire. However, if you absolutely need an extension cord, then you should get a heavy-duty cord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
